American 11 Heavy,
we're at Bravo 32,
ready for push.
American 11 Heavy,
thank you,
Monitor Ground 0.9,
November's current.
We've got November today.
Class 4,
United 175,
ready for push,
Charlie 19,
We have November.
United 175,
Monitor Ground 0.9,
He'll call you,
Oscar's current.
0.9,
we'll get Oscar,
United 175.
United 175,
Boston ground,
Gate 19,
Pushback approved.
Pushback approved,
United 175.
American 11 heavy,
contact departure,
that traffic's now in your 10 o'clock and 2 miles,
3400 feet.
Yes,
sir,
you're going to contact American. 11 heavy.
Climax Delivery,
this is United 93,
we're clocking 1527 for Delta.
United 93,
delays off the airport,
less than 15 minutes,
monitor this frequency for changes,
let me know when you're ready for the push.
Monitor this frequency,
call you for push,
United
93. Good morning,
American 11,
with you,
passing through 190 for 230.
American 11,
Boston,
NASA Center,
roger,
Climb maintain level 280.
United 175,
heavy hold,
show the runway for left,
Monitor down 128.8.
128.8,
hold,
show the for left.
We're warning ground,
American
7-7 is off.
Okay.
Dixie, 26, with information taxi.
American 7-7,
Dallas-Texas Runway, 30.
Taxi 30,
American 7-7.
American 11,
Turn 20 degrees, right.
Right,
American 11.
United 175 Heavy Runway Niner cleared for takeoff traffic holding a position on 4. right
cleared for takeoff Runway Niner. United 175 Heavy
American 11. Climbing Table, Level
350,
American 11,
Boston.
Earth 7,
Mike Lima,
How do you hear?
as you, loud and clear.
American 11,
Boston.
American 1-1,
the American on the frequency,
How do you hear me?
This is
Adam. This is Boston.
I turned American 20 left, and I was in a climb.
He will not respond to me now.
It looks like he's turning right.
Yeah,
I turned him 20, right.
Oh,
okay.
And he's only going to,
I think,
29.
Okay.
Sure,
that's fine.
But I'm not talking to him.
He's Nardo.
Roger.
All right.
Thanks.
7. Mike Lima, descendant,
Pulse discretion maintain for level 240.
PD,
level 240 will begin down on 311,
Mike Lima.
American 11,
Boston.
if you hear Boston Center,
ident.
Boston,
Cotter
683, flight level 210,
climb to 230.
Cotter 683,
Boston Center,
roger,
Climb maintain for level 310.
American 11,
If you hear Boston Center,
identify or acknowledge.
American
11,
If you hear Boston Center,
recontact Boston Center on 127.82.
That's American 11,
127.82.
United 175 heavy turn right heading 270.
Turn right heading 270, United 175.
Cape John Killer, 59 line,
question.
I'm listening in the back.
The cockpit's not answering.
Somebody's stabbed in business class.
And
I think there's mace that we can't breathe.
I don't know.
I think we're getting high-deck.
Which flight are you on?
Flight 12.
What seat are you in?
Are you there?
We just left Boston,
we're up in the air.
We're supposed to go to L.A. and the cockpit's not answering their phone.
Okay,
but what seat are you sitting in?
What's the number of your seat?
Okay,
I'm in my jump seat right now.
Okay.
At 3R.
Okay,
you're the flight attendant?
I'm sorry,
did you say you're the flight attendant?
Hello?
Yes,
hello?
What is your name?
Hi,
I'm going to have to speak up.
I can't hear you.
Sure,
what is your name?
Okay,
my name is Betty Ong.
I'm number three on flight 11.
Okay.
The cockpit is not answering the phone.
And there's somebody stabbed in business class.
And we can't breathe in business class.
Somebody's got mace or something.
Can you describe the person that you said someone is what in business class?
I'm sitting in the back.
Somebody's coming back from business.
If you can hold on for one second,
they're coming back.
Okay,
we've got staff.
Purser is staffed.
Nobody knows who's staffed who,
and we can't even get up to business class right now because nobody can breathe.
Number one is staffed right now.
And our number five,
our first class passengers,
our first class flight attendant and our purser's been staffed.
Can't get the cockpit,
the door won't open.
Yeah,
I'm taking down all the information, and we're also,
you know,
of course,
recording this.
This is operations.
What flight number are we talking about?
Flight 12.
Okay.
We're on flight 11 right now.
This is Flight 11.
Flight 11.
I'm sorry,
Nitties.
Boston to Los Angeles.
Yes.
This has been stabbed.
NR.5 has been stabbed.
Cockpit.
Can anybody get up to the cockpit?
We can't even get into the cockpit.
We don't know who's up there.
If they were shrewd,
they would keep the door closed.
And would they not maintain a sterile cockpit?
I think the guys are up there.
They might have gone their way up there or something.
Nobody can call the cockpit.
We can't even get inside.
Still there?
Yes,
we're still here.
Okay,
I'm staying on the line as well.
Okay.
Hi,
who is calling reservations?
Is this one of the flight attendants or who?
Who are you,
hon?
Her name is Betty Ong.
Betty Ong?
I'm number three.
I'm number three on this flight.
You're the number three on the flight?
Yes.
And this is flight 11, from where to where?
Have you guys called anyone else?
Somebody's calling medical and we can't get a cell.
American 77,
turn left, heading 270 and connect partial.
Southern Hennig,
departure, American 77,
thanks for getting.
American 11,
Boston.
United 175,
coming to Boston Center 127.
27.82.
2782,
United 1-35.
American 11,
American
1-1, How do you hear the center?
Athens,
this is Rockdale.
A couple things,
point out. North and west of Rockdale,
Amsterdam,
this is 986.
Right on,
Bruce.
Hey,
also,
are you trying to get through the company on the American or anything?
We're trying everything here.
Is he really getting no transplant and screwed up or what?
It appears that way.
No kidding,
hi.
Is that American 11 trying to call?
We have some claims,
just stay quiet and you'll be okay.
We're returning to the airport.
And who's trying to call me here?
American 11,
Are you trying to call?
Nobody move.
Everything will be okay.
If you try to make any move,
you'll endanger yourself and the airplane.
Just stay quiet.
Yeah,
we got him on primary.
838?
Have you guys heard anything from American?
No.
Okay,
we think there might be somebody in the cockpit right now taking it over.
Okay.
Yeah,
we just broadcast over here.
we're already doing it.
Okay,
head on.
Nobody move.
Everything will be okay.
If you try to make any move,
you'll danger yourself and the airplane.
Just stay quiet.
American, 77,
contact Washington Center, 120.65.
Good flight.
American 77,
I'm on the way.
Is there any chance you can get direct Flint this morning?
Not right now.
Go ahead 38.
Yeah,
American 11,
we suspect there's someone in the cockpit that's taken over.
We have just put him in direct water town, Jamestown.
Last we knew he was on present heading cleared to flight level 290.
No one is talking to him.
Eric has been called.
We've broadcasted on guard.
We've tried through company.
Okay,
thanks.
And 290 is not verified.
Okay,
thanks.
You're welcome.
United 93 Runway 4L Follow ups
Follow ups United
93 to 4L. Because he was just heading that way,
Yes, yeah, we've taken the American back because he appears to have turned. Yep,
thanks. Flagship 5616,
boss Help,
sir, your what?
230,
Flagship 5616
Override.
Go ahead.
Yeah,
I need you to look West of Albany,
American 11,
and put him on your scope.
He is,
uh,
nor, though, has been since he talked to Boston High.
We assume he's at flight level 290.
Uh,
we're not sure.
We think there's someone in the cockpit with him.
Um,
we broadcasted over guard.
We've gone airing.
We have gone company.
Uh,
nobody is talking to him.
We don't know where he's going.
We don't know what altitude he's at.
Okay.
Cleveland.
Hi,
Cleveland,
New York,
Boston.
I got a little situation with American 1-1 and American 11.
He is a 767 departed Boston going to LAX.
We don't know where the aircraft is going.
He supposedly going to LAX was going westbound.
We lost his frequency,
then we lost his transponder,
and now the aircraft is just west of Albany, heading due south.
Oh,
my goodness.
Do we have the data block on it?
Yeah,
it's a primary target presently, and it's just heading southwestbound.
Okay,
I understand.
I'll go to it right now.
I'll advise the area.
The last officer that observed was flight level 290.
29.
Heading southwestbound.
He's like towards
Hancock.
Right around there.
He's southwest of Albany by 1.5 miles.
Do you have no idea where he's going?
No idea,
sir.
You can tag him on the TSC.
I'll have you pick him up.
Primary only?
Primary only.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hampton,
Cameron,
39.
Boston here.
Do me a favor.
See if you have an American 11 on your frequency.
If you have them,
put them on me here at both ends.
Okay,
I'll try them.
Thank you.
Well,
Boston Center claims that they lost radio communication with the aircraft and the transponder.
And there's also,
they're tracking the primary target at this point.
It was last known at flight level 290.
And it appears to have turned south-southwestbound.
Also, there was some mention of some sort of a threat being made.
Being made?
A threat to the cockpit, or some threat in the cockpit.
And
Boston's uncertain exactly what was said.
I guess they're going to try to pull the tapes as quick as they can.
Hey,
Tom,
where can I reach you back?
What number at?
Okay,
all right.
Okay.
I'll call you back.
Bye.
Where are you from?
Youngstown.
What are you doing here?
Who are you here with?
My son and my husband.
Cape Drake on Cape,
on team Unit
41.
This is King Traecon.
Yeah,
hi,
are you able to talk to Otis on this line?
Um,
I'm not sure,
but if I need to get in touch with him,
I can.
I think they're on the 7 line.
I have a situation with the
American 11.
What?
I have a situation with the American 11.
You want to talk to Otis Tower?
I want to talk to Otis Traecon.
I need to scramble some fighters.
Alright,
well, hold on a second,
let me get you the soup.
Hey,
Cape,
Dan Buenacore from Boston Center.
Yes.
Are you having a situation with American 11,
a possible hijack?
American 11?
Yes,
sir.
Departing from Boston,
going to LAX.
Right now, he's south of Albany.
He'd like to scramble some fighters to go tail him.
Oh,
okay.
All proctored here.
Okay,
and just put a few arms,
just depart,
and we'll put a flight plan in for him,
and we'll aim him towards Hampton direct.
Okay, I'll talk to these guys over here and see what we can do.
Okay.
And right now, he's on the ground at Albany?
No,
no,
no.
He's right now airborne. About 40 to the south of Albany,
primary only.
Ah,
okay.
I'll talk to them right now.
And who's this here?
Dan Buena from Boston to the TMU.
Dan to the TMU,
okay.
All right.
All right,
TJ.
Bye.
Nobody move,
please.
We're going back to the airport.
Don't try to make any stupid moves.
SOC,
Ray Holland.
Ray Holland,
Nancy Wyatt,
Boston Flight Service.
Yes.
Okay,
we've got the flight attendants on the line here.
You do have them on the line?
On the plane,
yeah.
Can you conference them in with us?
I have no idea...
I have no idea how to do that,
if you can help me out.
He's getting some information here.
I'm going to read his notes for you.
It looks like he's Middle Eastern,
speaks no English.
He was in 10B,
10, Baker,
9D and G,
speaks no English.
The plane's in a rapid descent.
Is the cockpit still?
Yes.
Okay,
the flight attendants are concerned, they don't know what's going on in the cockpit.
Are you in contact with them?
No,
we're not.
That's true.
We're trying to get in contact with the cockpit.
Okay.
We don't really want to tell her that.
Okay,
got it.
there,
um,
we're not sure.
Um,
okay,
looks like there is severe bleeding that,
uh,
he's keeping her on the line.
Um,
there's severe bleeding.
There's a slashed throat.
Michael,
is that severe?
Is that a slashed throat?
A flight attendant?
No.
Hi Tony,
good morning Boston Center.
I got a situation here with American 11,
American 11.
Boston departure to
LAX.
We believe it's a possible hijack situation.
Okay,
tell me more.
he departed Boston.
We lost radio communications with him.
Then we lost his transponder.
And they believe that they heard in the background something,
a threat.
What,
a threat, you said?
A threat.
And right now, the aircraft is just west of Albany, going southbound.
Okay,
nobody's talking to him,
right?
Nobody's talking to him at this time,
correct?
That's correct.
Okay.
Anything
I can do to help you right now?
Uh,
no.
I mean,
uh,
just in the right,
we have no idea where this aircraft is going.
Maybe ahead of,
head up to New York Center?
Okay.
Uh,
well,
probably just precaution might be good.
If we,
uh,
call up Cleveland in New York. And at least let them know, in case this guy starts heading there,
whether they'll have a headshot on it.
Right.
Kennedy,
Kingston, 93.
Kennedy.
I got a heads up for you here.
I got an american 11.
He's right over Kingston right now.
We think he's at flight level 290.
There appears to be some possible problem with him.
He departed Boston, going to
Los Angeles.
But somewhere along the way here, he took a left turn.
And he's not talking to anyone.
Hasn't talked to anybody in about 75.
Eastbound right now,
so you're gonna pass just like over Carmel, and again,
we don't have a verified altitude. We think you deflatable 290.
We're trying to verify the code on them.
No, you just play an x-ray.
There's no code on the guys plan X-ray and we approve that.
Oh,
he's a primary. Right now,
we're kicking out of a 290.
Oh, supposedly it's out these better now, like he's gonna go between,
maybe right over Dewey's intersection,
so I'm just giving you a heads up.
We're not talking to him.
No one's talking to him about the last 20 minutes.
Go to your boundary,
okay?
Okay.
Over to you.
Cape Trach on 2 minute
41.
Cape trach on,
sir.
You said Panta 4-6?
4-5 or 4-6,
or and 4-6,
yeah.
Okay,
got it.
All right.
UCF 583,
Boston.
583,
go ahead.
How's the visibility?
It's unlimited.
It's clear and no clouds.
It's great.
I want you to look out your right side.
Maybe you're at 3 o'clock and about 10 miles.
We got an American 767 we lost contact with, and
I want to know if you can tell me if he's over. Roughly 29,000 feet there.
We're showing him at 29.
We can't verify that.
Okay,
we're not showing anybody on the
TCAS. Just a second,
we're looking over there and see if we can spot him.
Right,
he'd be about right around your turn right now.
He's probably about your
3 o'clock right now.
We can't spot him yet.
How many miles off to the 3 o'clock position?
He's about 7 miles right now.
And he's heading southbound.
United 175,
Boston.
175,
Go ahead, sir.
Roger,
can you have traffic,
look at your 12 to 1 o'clock at about 10 miles southbound.
See if you can see an American 767 out there, please.
We're looking,
negative contact,
United 175.
UCF 583,
Can you see us?
583,
we still don't have him yet, sir,
we're looking.
Roger,
this is weapon,
Sergeant Powell.
Hi, Boston Center TMU,
we have a problem here.
We have a hijacked aircraft headed towards
New York and we need you guys to,
we need someone to scramble, some F-16s or something up there to help us out.
Is this real world or exercise?
No,
this is not an exercise,
I'm going to test it.
Okay,
hey,
hold on one second,
okay?
Yep.
Sir.
Yes,
sir.
Yeah,
I've got an MCC coming in right now to talk to you so you can handle all that.
Thank you.
Alright.
Hi,
this is Major Deskins.
Joe Cooper,
Boston Center.
We have a hijacked aircraft headed towards the New York metro area.
I'm wondering if you could send someone up there,
some F-16s or something,
and help us out,
maybe out of Otis.
Do you have a Mode 3 on it?
No,
it's just a primary target only.
We lost the mode
C on it.
So you'd have to get up in the air and we'd have to vector you towards the aircraft.
Okay,
so you'd want to control the intercepts because...
We have to,
yeah.
You have to.
We have to pick him up in primary radar.
Okay,
so you have a general location as to where he is?
We're still tracking him right now.
You're tracking him?
Can you give me a lat and long of where you think he is just for RSA?
Yeah,
hold on a second.
What?
What was that?
Is that real world?
Cool!
For real?
Perfect!
Boston?
Yep.
Uh,
bluh bluh, bluh, bluh bluh.
Open line.
Boston,
M.L. Tech.
Uh,
yeah,
Hunter.
Calling in reference to the Hijack aircraft.
Yes.
We're checking to get some information from you if we could.
Okay,
what do you need?
We need CallSign type aircraft.
It's American 11.
Okay,
we're checking to get some information from you if we could.
what do you need?
We need CallSign type aircraft.
It's American 11.
From you, if we could.
Okay,
what do you need?
We need call sign type aircraft.
It's American 11.
American 11.
Type aircraft to the 767.
And number of souls on board,
do you know that?
I don't know,
hold on.
Hey, Danny,
we got souls on board and all that information?
No,
we don't have any of that information.
You don't have any of that?
Okay.
Position's about 40 miles north of Kennedy.
40 miles north of Kennedy?
Right.
Do you have a mote 3?
No,
we don't.
He's a primary target only.
Primary target only?
Yep.
Okay,
and you don't know where he's coming from or destination?
No idea.
He took off out of Boston,
originally heading for
Los Angeles.
Boston to Los Angeles?
That was his original destination,
yeah.
And where are they going now,
do you know?
No idea.
He's heading towards Kennedy.
It looks like his speed is decreasing.
I'm not exactly sure where.
Nobody really knows.
Are you the controlling agency?
Or is New York?
Boston Center.
Right now we are.
He's heading right for New York Center.
And is there any military assistance requested?
Yes,
we're actually trying to get the F-15s to...
you do want F-15s out?
Yeah,
F-15s out of Otis.
But you don't have any modes or codes on him?
No,
right now, it's just...
we don't have any modes.
Is he inbound to JFK?
We don't know.
You don't know where he is at all?
He's being hijacked.
The pilot's having a hard time talking to the...
I mean,
we don't know.
We don't know where he's going.
He's heading towards Kennedy.
He's...
Like I said,
he's like 35 miles north of Kennedy, now at 367 knots.
Okay.
No idea where he's going.
If you could, please give us a call and let us know,
you know,
any information,
that would be great.
Okay.
Right now, I guess we're trying to work on,
I guess there's been some threats in the cockpit.
There's been what?
I'm sorry.
We'll call you right back as soon as we know more.
Thank you.
Okay.
Okay,
United 175,
do you have him much at 12 o'clock now,
in 5,
10 miles?
Affirmative,
we have him.
He looks about 20,
yeah,
about 29,
28,000.
Okay,
thank you.
Command Center,
this is Tony.
Hi,
Tony,
Command Center here,
I mean,
Boston Center here.
Can I get New York to recon?
You bet.
Nothing with the...
Yes,
with American 11.
Say it again?
Reference American 11.
Have you had any contact with him yet?
No,
no contact.
It is confirmed hijacked, though.
Hey,
Tracon,
hi.
Boston Center.
Good morning.
American 11.
767 possible hijacked.
American 11,
7-5 and...
7-6.
Where's he landing?
Right...
Right now, we don't have any idea. But he was to the northwest of Albany and now he's down by Sparta, losing speed very rapidly.
We believe he's primary only, and we believe he's on the descent, that's why he's slowing down.
I'm just trying to,
and he's around the Sparta area now, you say?
Yeah, he's around the Sparta area right now.
Yeah,
it's a primary target right now.
I'm looking pretty hard for any kind of primary target.
We still should be able to see it,
and I don't see...
I do have something on the TSD,
if that gives you an idea of which way he's heading.
Yeah,
I'm just looking at the real raw radar here,
and
I just don't see...
I'll let the area notice start looking for it.
We just don't have any idea what happened.
Last time we had a fellow 290,
but his speed has diminished quite a bit.
So we believe he might be at descent.
Okay.
Alrighty.
I'll pass along to the sector.
Alright,
just be careful.
Understand.
Check.
Boston?
Yes.
You said you confirmed the hijack.
How'd you...
Well,
what has happened,
the pilot has kept the mic keyed while...
The persons in the cockpit,
the flight deck.
Okay,
and what are you hearing?
The threat,
you know,
I don't really know what they're hearing,
but the suit came down and confirmed that there's a hijack.
Hey,
if you literally need help,
please give us a call so we can help you out as best we can.
Does New York know about this kind of hit and run?
New York knows.
Cleveland knows.
Maybe Washington will be next.
We're going to scramble for fighters to tail them.
Okay.
Coming out of Otis?
Yes.
Okay.
I'll take care of the coordination with the Washington
Center. I will advise them on what's going on.
Thank you.
Harry Belafonte,
it's a pleasure to see you.
Good morning.
I mean,
to say that this has been a project that's been long in the making is a bit of an understatement.
You started working on this back in 1954.
Tell me how it came about.
Well,
America was just the threshold of a new period in its evolution.
Brown versus the Board of Education had just come through the Supreme Court.
There was an awakening to the whole issue.
United 175,
Play Direct spotter.
Contact New York Center,
127.17, 127.17,
United 175 Center,
United 175,
Heavy 3-1, United 175,
correction,
United 175,
New York Center,
Roger
Houston 583, New York 583. Go ahead, give me a favor.
There's an aircraft that they had had, threatening things off the left. Did they ask you to look for an aircraft that's an American flight?
He's about 8 to 9 o'clock right now and about 10 miles from me, just heading southbound.
The last reported altitude on him was 29, and nobody's not sure what he might be at.
Yeah,
we talked about him on the last frequency.
We spotted him when he was at our 3 o'clock position,
and he did appear to us to be at 29,000 feet.
We're not picking him up on the T-Cavs.
I'll look again and see if we can spot him once more.
No,
it looks like they shut off the transponder.
That's why the question about it.
All right,
current coordinates are,
let's see,
4115 North.
07346.
07346 West.
And approximate heading is 190.
190.
387 knots.
Last known altitude is flight level 290,
but we cannot confirm that.
290.
Do you have time to give me any other amplifying information on it?
Yeah.
Do you want the type and stuff?
What do you mean?
What do you want?
Yeah,
like passengers on board,
where it came from.
767,
200 series,
No idea how many people are on board right now.
They came from Boston,
they're supposed to be going to LA,
and they're headed south.
They're going the wrong way,
obviously.
Okay.
Okay,
thank you very much.
So where are they coming,
who are you going to send,
do you know yet?
That determination hasn't been made yet.
Let me,
if you could hold on just a moment,
I'm going to get,
We've got some coordination going on right now.
I think that they said they were going to put Otis on Battle station.
That's who I would anticipate the air prep to be.
Okay.
Based on going to JFK.
They would be our closest asset.
Okay.
Let me give you my commercial number in case we get disconnected here.
603.
879.
6666.
Oh,
that's a scary number.
6666.
And your number again,
sir?
Joe.
Joe Cooper.
Cooper.
Yeah,
he can talk to anyone here.
He already knows what's going on.
Oh,
okay.
Alright,
so I'll stand, hold and give me the call signs at least so we can get them in priority and get them going.
Okay,
stand by.
Looking for assets under the surface of that long...
There's a real flag there.
You got it?
We know.
Yeah,
once he comes into our radar, we will.
We'll be taking it.
Give me the slides,
quick.
4-1-1-5 North.
...3,
4,
6,
5.
Don't look in the header, all your procedures and air spaces and everything.
Make sure you know what's going on.
Real world hijacked
40 miles north of Kennedy.
Do you have time to give me any other information on it?
Yeah,
like...
.Battle. Station.
.Where? It came from.
Point of notice on Battle Station.
Tower's in.
Take approaches on it.
Guy killer.
This is huntress placing Panta 4546 on battle stations.
I repeat,
battle stations.
Time 1241.
Authenticate.
Hotel Romeo.
All parties acknowledge with initials.
Command post.
Giant
Killer. Tower.
JL.
Approach.
Tango Julia,
and you say again, the call time?
Panta,
Papa,
Alpha,
November,
Tango Alpha,
4546.
Tango Julia.
Julia Papa,
all parties are cleared to drop.
New York,
United 175 heavy.
United 175,
go ahead.
We figured we'd wait to go to your center.
We heard a suspicious transmission on our departure out of Boston.
Someone keyed the mic and said,
everyone, stay in your seats.
Oh,
okay.
I'll pass that along over here.
Hey,
Kingston on 93 line.
Go ahead.
Hey,
United 175 just came on my frequency,
And he said that they heard a suspicious transmission when they were leaving Boston.
Oh,
yeah?
Everybody stay in their seat.
That's what they heard is a suspicious transmission.
Now,
that U.S. Air 583 thought the American who spotted him was at 29.
United 93,
Wind 330 at 7,
runway 4L, clear for takeoff.
Clear for takeoff
4L, United 93.
I've never seen so much real world stuff happen during the night.
Lat long burst showing the mass,
the light showing the mass,
the last...
Lat long,
41,
right,
what was that?
290,
we're going to LL,
and all the other things are going to LL.
Okay,
find this guy.
Yeah,
41, and we're putting it in.
1443.
1443,
look for it,
right there.
Okay,
mode 3,
1443,
last known.
No,
this is real world.
Okay,
we're in the high track.
I got a Z point.
Sir,
last known position that we got out of this guy was right there at the Z point.
He's heading 190 at 29,000 feet.
He's heading down.
So,
we're looking for somebody.
You know what,
just start hitting up tracks all around that area.
Is that Z point?
Okay,
just north of,
uh...
SD,
MCC,
Scramble, Otis.
Copy,
same mission.
MCC,
I don't know where I'm scrambling these guys to.
I need a direction,
a destination.
Okay,
I'm going to give you a Z point.
It's just north of
New York City.
I got this lat long 4115-7436,
or 7346.
Head them in that direction.
Copy that.
American Airlines Emergency line,
please state your emergency.
Hey,
this is Niti at American Airlines calling.
I am monitoring a call in which flight 11,
the flight attendant is advising our reps that the pilot,
everyone's been stabbed.
Flight 11?
Yep.
They can't get into the cockpit, is what I'm hearing.
Okay,
who is this I'm talking to?
Excuse me,
this is Nydia American Airlines at the Raleigh Reservation Center.
I'm the operations specialist on duty.
I'm sorry,
what was your name again?
Nydia.
And what's your last name?
Gonzalez,
G-O-N-Z-A-L-E-Z.
Raleigh Reservations.
Okay.
I have a flight attendant on the line with one of our agents.
And she's calling how?
Through reservations.
I can go in on the line and ask a lot of kind of questions.
Okay.
I'm assuming they've declared an emergency.
Let me get ATC on here.
Stand by.
Got any contact with anybody?
No.
Okay,
I'm still on with security.
Betty?
Yes.
You're doing a great job.
Just stay calm,
okay?
We are,
absolutely.
Okay,
we're contacting the flight crew now.
We're also contacting ATC.
Okay.
Anything else from this flight attendant?
So far, what I've got,
the number five flight attendant's been stabbed,
but she seems to be breathing.
The number one seems to be stabbed pretty badly,
and she's lying down on the floor.
They don't know whether she's conscious or not.
The other flight attendants are in the back.
Seems like the passengers and the coach might not be aware of what's going on right now.
These two passengers were from first class.
Okay,
hold on.
Hey,
Betty,
do you know any information as far as the gentlemen?
They're in the cockpit with the pilots.
Were they from first class?
They were sitting in 2A and B.
Okay.
They are in the cockpit with the pilots.
Who's helping them?
Is there a doctor on board?
Is there a doctor on board that he doesn't see you guys?
You don't have any doctors on board,
okay.
So you've gotten all the first class passengers out of first class?
Have they taken everyone out of first class?
Yeah,
she's just saying that they have.
They're in coach.
What's going on,
honey?
Okay,
the aircraft is erratic again.
Very erratic.
She did say that all the first class passengers have been moved back to coach.
So first class,
the cabin is empty.
What's going on on your end,
Craig?
We contacted Air Traffic control.
They are going to handle this as a confirmed hijacking.
So they're moving all the traffic out of this aircraft's way.
He turned his transponder off,
so we don't have a definitive altitude for him.
We're just going by.
They seem to think that they have him on a primary radar.
They seem to think that he is descending.
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay,
Lydia?
Yes,
dear,
I'm here.
Okay.
I have the dispatcher currently taking the current fuel on board.
Uh-huh.
And we're going to run some profiles.
Okay.
To see exactly what his endurance is.
She doesn't have an idea who the other passenger might be in first.
Apparently they might have spread something,
so it's,
um,
they're having a hard time breathing or getting in that area.
What's going on,
Betty?
Betty,
talk to me.
are you there?
Betty?
Do you think you lost her?
Okay,
so we'll stay open.
I think we might have lost her.
Okay.
Center,
U.S. Air 583.
U.S. Air 583,
go ahead.
Yeah,
I just picked up an ELC on 21-5.
It was brief,
but it went off.
Okay,
they said. It's confirmed,
believe it or not,
is a thing we're not sure yet.
So we're still trying.
They're going on another aircraft right now,
and they're trying to see what altitude he's at.
Kingston on the 93 line.
Take a point on yet?
Not yet.
Kings on 93 line,
This is East Texas.
Go ahead,
sir.
Can you turn that Delta 2433 a little bit to the right?
They got the Eagle flight in there,
the guy at 31,
that they wanted to look at this American, to see what altitude he was at.
Can you put him on like a 290 and stop the Delta 1489 underneath him?
Yeah,
well,
we just put Delta 2433 on you,
so we'll try him again.
If we have him,
we'll turn him to a 290,
all right?
I'm not talking to the Delta.
Hold on.
Okay.
All right.
Delta 2433,
New York.
Go ahead.
Turn right heading of 2-9-0,
Delta 2433,
vectors for traffic.
Delta 2433 at 2-9-0,
We'll pick up that ELC, too,
but it's very sunny.
Roger,
if you make it a nice, tight turn,
it would help.
Traffic 11 o'clock at about 10 miles northbound,
just turning eastbound at 31.
We'll make it,
Ty.
Yeah,
we're here.
Thanks.
Canada 3-0-7,
about 2-8-0,
please.
Close up.
How is that?
Touch.
Touch that.
This is Huntress with an active air defense scramble for
Panta
4546. Time 1246.
Authenticate Delta X-ray.
Scramble immediately Panta 4546.
Heading 280.
Flight level 290.
Contact Huntress on frequency
228 decimal niner.
Backup
364.2. All parties acknowledge those initials.
Campos.
Blake Bielow.
Tower.
J.R.
Allentown.
Approach.
Tango Juliet.
Giant Killer.
Charlie Brunel.
All parties are clear to drop.
Juliet Poppiger.
Hello,
I'm Rob Bonnet and this is Sport Today on BBC World, coming up on this programme.
The Champions League is back.
Roma start at home to last season's runners-up,
Real Madrid,
at the Olympic Stadium.
Liverpool make their first appearance in Europe's premier competition for 16 years.
Can they improve on their current poor form in the English Premiership?
Hi,
sir.
OK,
what we're doing,
we're trying to locate this guy.
We can't find him via IFF.
What we're going to do,
we're going to hit up every track within a
25-mile radius of the Z-point that we put on the scope.
29,000, heading 190.
We're just going to do,
we're going to try to find this guy.
They can't find him.
There's been supposedly threats in the cockpit.
So we're just,
we're doing the thing.
True.
And probably right now,
with what's going on in the cockpit,
it's probably really crazy.
So that probably needs to,
that will simmer down and we'll probably get some better information.
I have scrambled otis already.
For your direction, or send them in that general direction.
We're sending right to that Z point, and then we can. We can maneuver them as beam,
right?
We'll work with them, make sure weapons work for them now.
American 11.
Right now, he's primary only.
Do you have no Mode 3 or anything?
Um...
Not showing anything,
no.
Do you have a lat long now?
Hold on,
I can get a lat long.
Hold on one second.
Okay,
I'm showing 4039 North.
4039 North.
And 7403 West.
7403 West.
Boston Flight Service has another one of the flight attendants on the phone, too.
Boston Flight Service.
Amy?
She lost it.
Okay.
Yeah,
okay,
we lost the other one,
so I really need to get on the phone with her.
Okay,
something's wrong.
Amy Sweeney is on the phone.
Amy Sweeney?
Yeah,
she's a number nine.
Okay.
And he's having trouble talking to her right now.
All right,
these are the two that are injured.
Amy?
One in five.
She started screaming and saying, something's wrong, and now he's having trouble.
No.
Okay.
And he thinks he might be disconnected.
Okay,
we just lost connection.
Lost the connection.
Yeah.
Something's wrong with the airplane?
In other words,
she said, Something's wrong.
They're not in the cockpit.
Okay,
they're in the back of the plane.
They're in the back of the airplane?
Yeah,
they're in the back of the airplane.
They're not...
Oh,
the hijackers are in the cockpit.
Oh, no.
Okay,
they're in the cockpit.
Hey,
Craig?
They're saying they're in the cockpit.
Listen,
look to see where the next place of Kennedy is, just in case you're going to...
Battalion 1.
We just had a plane crash into Alpha 4 of the World Trade Center,
transmit a second alarm and start relocating companies into the area.
Send for Battalion 1.
Battalion 1 is also sending the whole crew on this box to that area,
K.
Come to
us,
Hey Beth,
what is that?
Somebody hit the World Trade Center?
It's the trade Center.
There's a fire on the upper floors.
It's just an explosion.
Engine 6 to Manhattan State.
Engine 6.
The World Trade said that tower number 1 is on fire.
The whole outside of the building was just a huge explosion.
10-4,
all companies stand by as it's time.
Engine is second row on that box immediately.
10-4.
Engine 1 out of
Manhattan. Engine 1 out.
Engine 1 out,
World Trade Center, 1060.
Send every available ambulance,
everything you got to World Trade Center now.
1060 has been transmitted for the World Trade Center.
1060 for the World Trade Center.
Robert Hughes lived the American dream.
He was wealthy beyond belief,
dated beautiful movie stars,
and made record-breaking flights.
But the man, who could have it all for years, just wanted to be left alone.
Because of that,
much of his life has remained a mystery until now.
Author Richard Hack uncovers America's first billionaire in his new book,
simply called
Hughes. Richard Hack,
Good morning.
Good to see you.
Thank you very much.
I'm fine,
thank you.
You say this is a different perspective on Howard Hughes, because the other books have been written based on stories told by people who knew him.
You think this is his point of view.
How could that be?
Say that again,
please.
I said, we...
.target. About 20 west of Kennedy, and we had a report of an ElT in the area.
This will,
uh,
get some...
We've lost the track,
too.
Hey,
Boston,
this is New York.
What type aircraft was the American?
167.
This is the ACI watch.
Say again if you lost track of the aircraft.
Over.
Boston has lost track.
On our frequency, we have confirmed that it was a hijack.
On the tapes.
Yeah,
New York confirms. We've lost the track as well, and we got a report of an ELT in the area that the track was in.
Kennedy Tower reports...
Kennedy Tower reports that there was a fire at the World Trade Center.
And that's the area where we lost the airplane.
I think it just happened.
Isn't that the twin Towers,
Rachel?
Let's see.
We've got to get to a radio.
This is New York Center.
We're watching the airplane.
He's 15 west of Kennedy now.
We had one or two confirmations that he was still at 29.
One at 29.
One at 31 couldn't see him.
I also had a conversation with American Airlines,
and they've told us that they believe that one of their stewardesses was stabbed. And that there are people in the cockpit that have control of the aircraft.
And that's all the information they have right now.
Is there any way, Ma'am, that we can get updates as far as the lat-longs of that aircraft?
Actually, I'm showing this track and coast right now.
Track and coast,
what does that mean?
Is it northbound?
It means we've,
as far as...
What I'm showing here, they've lost track. I'm gonna see if I can find out and I'll give you a call back. Three trucks have been hacked, civilian reports from Up here. A plane just crashed into the World Trade Center. For your information. Trucks
available United 93 right turn heading of UH, 310, right heading 310, United 93.
Yeah,
and how do you determine the value?
Is it a matter of...
I'm sorry,
I'm going to interrupt you right now.
We have what appears to be a very serious...
Is that the World Trade Tower?
Yeah.
This is...
They think so.
This is one of the towers of the World Trade Center in Manhattan,
which is clearly heavily involved in a smoke situation,
and one would assume there is fire.
Mark,
I heard that there was a fire in the building.
I heard from somebody who spoke to someone in the building.
They just called me and they said they were told to evacuate and that they were told that a plane had hit the building.
Now,
again,
I spoke to one of my Wall Street sources, who said they had just heard from somebody at a Wall Street firm that has some offices in the building. That they were told to evacuate and that a plane had hit the World Trade Center.
So,
Tony,
I want to know how to...
We have a number of floors on fire.
It looked like the plane was aiming towards the building.
Transmit a third alarm.
We'll have the staging area at
Vesey and West Street.
Have the third alarm assignment go into that area.
Second alarm assignment,
report to the building,
okay?
All right,
send forth.
Second alarm assignment,
report to the World Trade Center.
report to One World Trade Center.
I am shaking.
I'm being like, the most stupid of all the people.
I just heard a loud boom.
You did?
Was it a plane?
That's what I was thinking,
it was a terrorist attack.
Bob said he heard it sounded like a rocket.
I heard a plane,
it seemed like a plane went over.
Yeah?
And then I had the boom and I looked up and there was the...
Thing exploding from the outside,
exploding to the outside.
The whole,
it looked like a...
Your mom said there was a plane driving over,
flying over.
I heard the noise of the plane.
Oh,
she heard the noise of a plane, and then a boom.
And then I,
just like a,
It was like a bomb that dropped and all the building from the inside went out like there was an explosion from the inside going out.
Oh my god.
I hope there was nobody at work.
There's no one there.
That's what I'm thinking before nine.
It's the World Trade Center.
Oh,
I see fire engines,
they're coming.
Yeah,
big one.
Squad 182,
What have you got?
If the first battalion transitor that looked like it was intentional, involved in four more units going into the box,
it could be a terrorist attack.
Attention,
all units be advised.
this just in,
you are looking at obviously a very disturbing live shot there.
That is the World Trade Center, and we have unconfirmed reports this morning that a plane has crashed into one of the towers of the World Trade Center.
This is a special report from News Channel 4.
Good morning everybody.
I am Jane Hanson in the News Channel 4 studio this morning to bring you some news.
We are looking at a picture now of the World Trade Center. And we have an eyewitness on the telephone who tells us that he has seen an airplane crash into the World Trade Center.
His name is Tony Arrigo.
He is on East 12th Street.
Tony,
can you please tell us what you witnessed?
Yes,
I can tell you what happened.
I was taking the garbage out of the building when we heard this roaring engines coming.
We looked up and there was a plane.
Next thing, you know,
we heard boom.
We ran up to the corner and hit right into the World Trade Center.
22.
Can you tell us what kind of an airplane is it?
It had to be a 737.
It had to hit the World Trade Center.
It was a big,
big plane.
Okay.
And what do you see at this point?
Oh,
smoke and screaming and,
I mean,
screaming engines and all the fire engines and police departments all traveling down that way.
Oh my God almighty,
the black smoke all over the place.
I heard nobody.
It's got to be somebody killed in there.
Cool people.
I went to work.
Tommy,
we don't hear any confirmation from any officials of this happening.
Just repeat again.
You were walking.
You were just going outside.
I was bringing the guy to count to the freight engine.
We heard this roaring engine.
We looked up and there was the plane.
Next thing we know,
in a matter of seconds,
we heard a boom.
We went to the corner and there it was, right in the middle of the World Trade Center.
Where are you?
You standing right now in the building right now, okay, what do you see? At this point? People are staring up there, looking at it. Oh my god, the smoke is coming out, black bull smoke. Okay, you can see we are. We are physically looking at one of our sky cams right now, we can see building
smoke from the top of the World Trade Center. Tony, are there other people that are around you? At this point? Is everybody in pretty much a state of shock? Oh, of course, they are people, for the people in the building are going out.
Look at the building that's on fire.
Oh,
God,
there's a lot of people in there.
Oh,
my God.
There's still some of the brain coming down.
It's safe to stay inside the hotel.
Thank you.
Again,
now we're putting our camera in.
We are pushing our camera into the top of the World Trade Center,
and we can see that there appears to be some fairly significant damage to the top of the world.
Oh,
yes,
it's got to be these 15 floors that were hit with the plane.
Uh, Tony, um, you know, I'm keeping asking you to describe this for me, because as I was talking...
What really happened was I was taking the garbage out of the building to go into the freight entrance and dump it.
When we hurried, when I hurried, there was a big water going up,
stuff going on.
Oh,
my God,
the fire.
The plane soon arrived over a metal,
metal fire.
And then the next thing I hear in a few seconds was boom.
So we ran up to the corner and there was...
What are you doing?
You can see from this perspective that I would say about the top
15 or 20 percent of this building is affected in one way or another.
I am.
I'm trying to see if there's people up there.
I don't see people.
It's just an incredible amount of smoke.
I'm just standing right there, looking at the World Trade Towers.
I just saw, like a 747 flying through the trade towers.
Engine 1 on the manatee.
Engine 1 on go.
Roll every available ambulance.
I wish
you Gods to this position.
There's paper everywhere.
I'll tell you what woke me up.
They bombed the World Trade Center.
I'm looking at it,
Meeke Young's videotaping it.
Terrible.
I heard grandpa,
I saw it.
It could have been a plane,
but I think it was a bomb.
A missile.
This could be World
War... It just happened minutes ago.
Anybody know what that smoke is in Lower Manhattan?
I'm sorry,
say again?
A lot of smoke in Lower Manhattan.
A lot of smoke in Lower Manhattan?
Out of the top of the World Trade Center building,
a major fire.
Yeah.
We want to tell you what we know as we know it.
We just got a report in that there's been some sort of explosion at the World Trade Center in
New York City.
One report said,
and we can't confirm any of this,
that a plane may have hit.
One of the two towers of the World Trade CENTER.
But AGAIN,
you're seeing the live pictures HERE.
We have no further details than THAT.
We don't know
anything about
what they have concluded happened there
this MORNING.
But we're going to find OUT.
And, of COURSE...
Make sure that everybody knows on the air.
These are,
of course,
the two twin trade center buildings that are down at the foot of Manhattan,
that they really are the beacons of New York.
It was there that there was the explosion a couple of years ago, brought about by terrorists.
That's all gone through the courts.
But this,
we don't know anything about,
we don't know about anything that has happened here, other than the fact that there's obviously been a major incident there.
And we're going to go to a special report now from ABC News.
Yeah,
hi.
I'm on the 106th floor of the
World Trade Center.
We just had an explosion.
The 106th floor?
Yes.
106,
okay.
We have smoke and it's pretty bad.
We can't get down.
Down the stairs.
All right.
People up here do not leave.
Okay,
there's a fire or explosion or something in the building.
All right,
I want you to stay where you are.
we're there.
We're coming up to get you.
Alright,
we're on the way.
Just sit tight.
Alright,
just sit tight.
We're on the way.
Alright,
please hurry.
Did you see what happened?
What happened?
Well,
I was in the pass train and there was a huge explosion sound.
Everyone came out.
One
one would feel safe in saying, there's a fire in there somewhere, and well, it's big, I mean, it has a lot of the building involved. We can only hope Mark, given the time that many people were not yet at work. Something we're buying like,
nobody knows what that was,
but it was something big.
I got him now.
And which was the one that just saw the major fire?
This is Delta 1489.
We can see the lower Manhattan.
It looks like the World Trade Center is on fire,
but it's hard to tell from here.
On a 1489 Roger.
Hello.
Yes,
Sean.
You're on the air right now.
What can go ahead?
What can you tell us?
I just witnessed a plane that appeared to be cruising slightly
lower than normal altitude over New York City and it appears to have crashed into.
I don't know which tower it is,
but
it hit directly in the middle of one of the World Trade Center towers.
Sean,
what kind of plane?
Was it a small plane?
A jet?
It was a jet.
It looked like a two-engine jet,
maybe a 737.
You're talking about a large passenger commercial jet?
A large passenger commercial jet.
No way.
Holy mofo,
what is that, though?
Mom,
it's like...
Like, maybe it was just an explosion or something?
Yeah,
yeah.
Did you hear what I said about it, maybe not being a bomb?
Cause, like,
it's up high,
Mom.
It's unbelievable,
it woke us up.
Oh my god.
What happened?
It is spreading.
There's only one fire truck right now.
Division 1,
I'm in hot,
guys.
Division 1 here.
We're responding,
have another rescue spot out.
10-4,
Rescue spot out to box 8087,
guys.
Rescue is responding,
United 175,
recycle your transponder and squawk code to 1470.
New York.
United 175,
Do you read New York?
Delta 1489,
go ahead.
Okay,
just wanted to make sure you read New York.
United,
United 175,
Do you read New York?
We don't have any confirmation from any officials of this happening.
Just repeat again,
you were walking,
you were just going outside.
We had a guy,
a cow,
did a plane engine.
We had this roaring engine.
Good
God. We're- we're- we're freaking videotaping it.
Yeah.
I don't- I have no clue what it is.
There's just black smoke.
And what looks like paper,
but...
Unbelievable.
Division 1,
10-4,
that's confirmed.
We have fire on several floors,
the upper floors of the World Trade Center.
10-4,
Division 1.
What's up,
Ryan?
What was it?
I don't know.
Something just went shooting through there,
though.
Like a missile or a bomb or something.
No idea what it was.
That is fucked up.
There's shit everywhere.
I mean,
I heard a missile,
dude.
I heard, like...
Like that.
I'm not exactly sure what it is right now.
I'm going to go watch the news.
I'm going to put this on a tripod and go watch the news.
What the fuck?
It's a big one!
You see it?
I heard it.
And I think it's a big one.
It's a fucking airliner.
Yeah.
Alright,
the report continues to be that a plane...
Yeah.
.Hit. The World Trade Center.
That is what I was told,
Mark,
again,
by somebody...
Well,
from here, it now looks like the North Building.
Oh my fucking god.
Yeah,
I don't know, dude.
Holy shit,
look at that.
It is, man.
It's over soon?
How?
To the mob?
No.
Play it!
Can't we play it?
Yeah,
I told you.
Just tell them to play it.
You just told them to watch the news,
dude.
It's all over.
It's on the news.
Dude,
the news is so crazy.
There's a plane crashed into the tower of the World Trade Center.
Oh my...
Okay,
now I have it on the tripod.
Oh my God.
They believe it was an airplane.
I'm going to go watch the news now.
Come on,
movie.
Will knock on the door.
When HRH responds,
the man will open the door using the hand with the Kleenex.
I mean...
Right,
as opposed to the dirty hand.
I mean,
hello,
Howard,
you know.
The man was a bit compulsive,
let's face it,
but on the other hand,
he was absolutely the most amazing man that America has ever created,
ever.
Okay,
I have got to interrupt you right now.
Sorry.
Richard Hack,
Thank you very much.
We appreciate it.
The book is called Hughes.
We want to go live right now and show you a picture of the World Trade Center.
Where I understand,
do we have it?
No,
we do not.
We have a breaking story,
though.
We're going to come back with that in just a moment.
First,
this is today on NBC.
Smashing the twin
Towers.
So,
if we can find it,
we'll intercept it.
Did you just say something hit the World Trade Center or something reports?
No,
keep on going with it.
I'm talking with ID,
and we had a phone call that came down to us saying that they had a possible hijack out of Boston.
Okay.
And I just flipped around,
and we were just,
we always wanted good news.
And a 737 hit the World Trade Center.
And
I was just curious at the same time,
if that was the aircraft.
Last, I knew they had a primary on it and the track was not squawking 7500, but it was under duress.
Send them to New York City. still,
continue to go.
Sir,
hold on.
Okay.
Who's plugged in up there?
Plug in.
I'll have you hold up there a minute.
This is what I got so far.
Okay.
Okay,
this is what we need.
now we do.
Yes.
This is what I got.
Possible news is 737 just hit the World Trade Center.
This is real world.
And we're trying to confirm this.
Okay,
continue taking the fighters down to the New York City area,
JFK area,
as best as you can.
Make sure that the FAA clears your route all the way through.
Just do what we got to do,
okay?
Just press with us.
It looks like somebody...
Looks like this guy could have hit the World Trade Center.
Really,
you heard someone talking to you,
said, It's a plane?
Twin towers have their own ZiP code.
There are so many people who work there and there are so many offices there.
They recently sold,
in fact,
by the Port Authority of New York to an investment group,
Mark.
I.
We do have some breaking news that we want to bring you around.
We're going to go to a picture,
a live picture from New York City.
Apparently,
a plane has crashed into the World Trade Center in New York,
852.
We have limited information at this point.
We don't know about injuries in the building or people on the ground,
but obviously this has potential for being a major disaster here.
Look at that.
Coggins,
TMU.
Good morning,
Sergeant Powell, calling from Huntress.
Yes.
I just wanted to make sure that your guys know that we're not going to control it.
Your guys are going to have him on the radio.
Well,
we don't have him on the radio,
but he's keying the mic on whatever frequency he has.
We don't know if he's taking any switches.
Do you know if you guys are going to scramble at all?
Yeah,
we...
I scrambled at
4-6. Okay,
and we're out of Atlantic City?
No,
Otis.
They did scramble out of Otis?
Yes.
Okay.
They should be airborne any second now.
Should be airborne any second.
Did you get any height finding on him?
No,
we're looking right now for everything.
We don't see anything.
Do you have the target itself?
We have the approximate location where it was.
We don't know a Mode 3 or anything.
Yeah,
we didn't have a Mode 3 either.
I didn't know if you had a primary on him or not.
We lost radar on him.
That was about five minutes ago.
He was eight miles east of JFK.
So I assume he's probably about 20 miles southeast of JFK now, or south,
almost too south.
Oh,
southeast?
Yeah,
he's probably almost south now.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Okay,
and if you do get a hit on him or you track him up,
please let us know and call us back.
Alrighty.
Okay,
thank you.
Thanks,
bye.
Good morning,
I'm Chris Jansing here with Greg Jarrett. And there is a major incident in Lower Manhattan in the World Trade Center, which is in the Wall Street area of New York City.
You are looking at live pictures.
Apparently, a plane has crashed into one of the upper floors of the World Trade Center.
Talk to me.
You went over this building right here.
I was looking up because I was mad at this guy right here.
I said,
damn,
when they gonna open that?
And then all of a sudden, I saw red and white stuff go over the building.
But the fire department was sitting here all...
Yeah,
I saw it.
And I was wondering what they doing.
And I said,
what is the fire department just sitting there for?
That's what I'm thinking.
Is it a conspiracy?
Boom.
I saw the person go over there.
I watched it.
I seen it go around.
I heard the boom.
I saw them.
I said,
look at this,
he moved.
That's what I thought.
See,
I thought, as soon as it happened,
I said,
was it terrorists?
Because the fire department has been waiting there.
Like, they've been waiting for him to come in.
Unless it's been planned to come in.
I saw it.
It was a red light.
It was so low to this building right here,
I couldn't believe it.
That's exactly what I saw.
I thought it was a jet.
It was a big enough.
Yeah.
We are,
we have,
I understand,
an eyewitness on the phone right now.
Sir.
What's your name?
Hey,
my name is Stuart.
Stuart,
where are you right now?
I'm working at a restaurant in Soho.
Alright,
so tell us what you saw,
if you would.
I literally,
I was waiting at a table and I literally saw a,
it seemed to be like a small plane.
I just heard a couple noises.
It looked like it like bounced off the building. And then I heard I just saw a huge
like ball of fire on top. And then the smoke seemed to simmer down and it just stung. You know, a lot of smoke was coming out and
that's pretty much the extent of what I saw a private aircraft.
I'm not sure if it was a.
it just seemed like a smaller plane.
I don't think it was anything commercial.
Could you tell us whether or not it was a prop or a jet?
I honestly don't know.
It happened too quickly.
New York Amos,
Hunter's ID.
Yes,
ma'am.
Are you aware of the possible hijack of American 1-1?
No,
I'm not.
True Boston Center,
ma'am,
we just got information. There's a real world. hijack,
American 1-1.
He is headed,
he was 40 miles north of JFK,
headed towards JFK.
We're trying to find out any information.
That we possibly can. Apparently the pilot was having a rough time because there have been threats in the cockpit. He was, uh, started out of Boston for Los Angeles, now headed for JFK. We do have military assistance that is after him.
2F15 I wanted to give you a heads up to let you know American 1-1.
Okay,
and we're trying to locate any information as far as the location where he is currently on Mode 3.
Do you have any information whatsoever?
Um,
I do not.
Hold on one second.
I believe if we can get in touch with him,
we have a witness who saw what happened at the World Trade Center.
M.
David Levin,
are you with us?
I am right here at the foot of the World Trade Center, on the north side.
Smoke is billowing out of the,
oh,
I would say it's about 15...
Stories down from the top of the number two,
I believe it is,
World Trade Center.
Flames are coming out also.
This apparently was a commuter plane that smashed into it with such force that the windows of the Pick. A Bagel,
in which I was just about to buy a bagel,
smashed with a big bang.
Everybody was very frightened.
And it sounded like a fabulous explosion.
And indeed,
there is great devastation up there.
Ups 6053,
do me a favor.
Look at 2 o'clock and about 2 miles.
See if you see some traffic out there southbound at about 33,000 feet.
Yeah,
we got above it.
Can you tell if that's an American?
Yes,
we think it is.
We really can't see it.
Now he's going behind us.
Okay,
and you say it looks like an American jet.
Can you tell what type of aircraft that would be?
It looks like a 7-3,
but
I can't concur on the American now.
I'm almost positive it's a 7-3,
but I don't know if it's American.
Okay,
you're positive it's a 7-3?
Well,
we're pretty sure it's a 7-3,
but we're not positive. It's an American.
Ups 6053,
thank you.
I'm sorry,
we couldn't help you.
No,
that helped out quite a bit.
We're missing an American jet.
Okay.
Oh my god,
Lily's going to daycare there.
Hold on,
there's a call waiting.
Hello?
Hi.
Oh my god.
Do you see this?
Oh,
so they've got it on TV.
Oh my God,
I have it on...
It's 8.52 here in New York.
I'm Bryant Gumbel.
We understand that there has been a plane crash on the southern tip of Manhattan.
You're looking at the
World Trade Center.
We understand that. A plane...
Has crashed into the World Trade Center.
We don't know anything more than that.
We don't know if it was a commercial aircraft.
We don't know if it was a private aircraft.
We have no idea how many were on board or what is what the extent of the injuries are right now.
Kingston on 93 Line, East Texas.
Kingston.
Do me a favor,
see if United 175 went back onto your frequency.
United 175?
Yes.
He's not here, East Texas.
Do you see that United 175 anywhere?
And do me a favor,
you see that target there,
the 3321 code at 33.5 climbing?
Don't know who he is,
but you got the U.S. Air 583.
If you need to descend him down,
you can.
Nobody,
we have a hijack.
We have some problems over here right now.
Oh, you do?
Yes.
Okay,
that may be real traffic, nobody knows. I can't get a hold of the United 175 at all right now.
I don't know where he went to.
All right, Okay,
I'll see if I have one.
All right,
okay.
United 175, New York.
Oh man,
I can see the paper flying. Let me see,
let me see. I got it,
I'm trying to record this thing.
Oh man,
I can even see the fire.
Does anybody know what that was?
A plane hit it.
A plane did?
It was like a two engine jet flying real low and went through it.
A two engine jet?
I heard a jet.
Yeah,
that was it.
I mean, it was coming fast, too.
It was coming from that direction.
And this one.
And it was super sonic.
Hey Robert,
will you get me another battery?
I got it because this package is while I'm here.
Okay.
Hey Shane?
Will you get me another battery and a tape?
Yeah.
Call the guy we knew.
Yeah,
the guy that bought my video.
My battery, dude?
It's in my little blue tote bag.
This is an ABC News special report.
Now, by the entire ABC network,
Good Morning America was in progress in the east coast and the Midwest,
but we're joined by the entire network. Just to show you some pictures at the foot of New York City.
This is at the World Trade Center.
Obviously a major fire there,
and there has been some sort of...
We don't fully know the details.
There is one report, as of yet unconfirmed, that a plane has hit the World Trade Center,
and you can see that there is smoke there coming out of at least two sides of the building.
And as you said,
there are two towers,
the tallest structures in Manhattan,
on the island of Manhattan.
We're trying to get people on the telephone to see what more we can learn.
We have no idea if it was a plane.
Was it in any sense deliberate?
Was it an accident?
I'm at the World Trade Center.
What happened?
The whole place just filled up with smoke.
I popped our ears and couldn't hear anything down there.
Now, I was told a 737 jet hit the building all the way up.
The flames are still coming out of the trade center on the top.
Say it again?
A 737.
I was told the 737 jet hit the building,
but we're down on the B1 level.
We walked down there.
The whole place filled up with smoke,
and everybody's ears popped.
It was,
like,
unbelievable.
It was like the whole place was clogged up, like a thunderstorm, full of smoke.
I know.
We was in the basement in this.
He was the breast of the plane.
I don't see no parts of no part of the plane.
And we're getting reports of a plane crash in the World Trade Center in New York.
You can see the pictures there.
It's one of New York's tallest buildings.
That's all the information we know at the moment,
but as you can see,
it is a considerable collision,
and there is a large fire.
That's all the information we have at the moment,
but we'll be back with more details in just a short while at the top of the hour.
Well,
we have one final story for you.
The New York Giants,
last season's Super Bowl runners-up,
have been...
BeATNIK
Okay.
We're going to Cleveland.
You should see there's so much stuff falling off the building.
Oh my god.
You heard the plane get, like,
I didn't see it happen, but I heard the whole thing.
I heard the engine and
boobies started crying.
You can see it all burning up.
You can see our,
the twin towers from our house.
I'm going to go.
I know how to do this.
Yay!
The actual reported position if he didn't crash into the World Trade Center was 20 miles south of Jigokai.
So I want you to take him down into this area.
Hold as needed.
Whatever altitude they need to go for center to make that work is fine with me.
That's the area I want him to go and hold.
Right in that little gap there.
All right,
this is what we're doing.
We're taking him down into this area to hold for now.
Whatever Altitude Center needs for them to do, that is fine.
Is the weapons team should pass that.
The fighters should be talking to center.
They're going to pass that through the fighters, exactly what we want them to do.
Now.
Okay,
now.
Foxy?
Yeah.
No,
no.
Because if he's still airborne,
he's going to have to pick anyone.
If he can,
hand the fighters over directly to FAA.
They're still under FAA control.
We're never going to take them.
Just take them all,
just work with them,
coordinate with them as best that you can with that.
Take them to the area and let them handle that airspace.
Considering that, a possible 737 jet may have crashed into World Trade Center Tower No.
1.
This just happened,
folks.
You're looking live at our cameras, at the billowing black smoke from multiple floors.
Me too.
I thought it was as well.
This is built,
Oh, you're right.
You mentioned earlier that, of course, as we all know, years ago there was that terrorist attack.
It took place down on the ground and in the underground levels and the garage levels.
But again, that's not to imply that we have any reason, at this point, to believe that this is...
Is this terrorism or not?
We simply don't know.
It was coming fast, too.
Yeah,
it sounded like it was like running.
I heard it.
It was going to explosion first and then it hit or something.
I heard it hissing.
Yeah,
I heard, like, a really straight,
like,
boom.
Holy...
I was trying to see if it was straight.
Are the Dragons still over there?
Oh my God,
everything's on fire.
Yeah.
Should I go over there and take pictures?
Thanks!
She's paper everywhere.
Yo.
I was like,
I looked out my window and saw people with guns.
Cell phones won't even work.
Go over one more block down this way.
U.S. Air 583,
go ahead.
Yeah,
I got reports on over the radio of a commuter plane hitting a World Trade Center.
Is that a
Nordau? Don't know,
but just stand by.
Delta 2433,
turn left to a heading of 170 now.
I have traffic,
I'm not really sure if it's good,
at a 32.
Might be descending,
might be climbing.
I'm showing them at 31 right now.
Heading 170,
Delta 2433.
Turn immediately,
20.
United 175,
Do you read New York?
Delta 2433,
Can you climb to flight level 330?
The traffic looks like it's descended back down to 31 now.
We can go up.
Okay,
climb and maintain flight level 330,
Delta 2433.
Climbing at 33,
Well,
Tom Kaminski may have a better view for us,
David.
He's in Chopper 880.
What are you seeing now,
Tom?
I think we can sort of confirm that, at least to some degree.
We are now looking at flames shooting out of the north side of No.
1 World Trade Center,
But there are at least some windows blown out and smoke billowing out of the opposite side.
We have not been able to get to the south side of the building yet.
We're sort of staying right here.
We have a very good vantage point,
so we're staying here for the time being.
However,
there is smoke billowing out of both sides,
really, of all four sides,
it would appear.
Don,
where are you and what do you know?
I am about four or five blocks just north of the World Trade Center.
And at about 10,
I would say 10 minutes ago,
15 minutes ago,
there was a loud sound that
I can only describe.
Is it sounded like a missile,
not an airplane.
Then there was a loud explosion and immediately lots of screaming out on the streets.
And I don't want to cause any speculation,
but that's the only way I could describe the sound.
And it was definitely...
Not the sound of a prop plane or anything like that.
Police Operator 1133,
What's the emergency?
I'm on the 100th floor of the World Trade Center with 30 people,
northeast corner.
Okay,
let me get you at
100th floor?
100th floor,
northeast,
30 people in the corner.
The smoke is very bad.
Okay,
I'll get you a fire department.
Hold on a second,
okay?
We're here immediately.
Okay,
hold on a second.
I'm on the 100th floor of the World Trade Center.
You said northeast,
right?
Northeast.
You got a lot of smoke?
A lot of smoke.
We can't see anything.
All on the floor,
there's heat.
We're just...
Fire?
We got people on 100th floor,
north East.
How you doing?
It's the fire department.
Hi.
It's hard to talk.
Yeah.
There's a lot of smoke.
Right.
The kids,
they're all overreacting.
Please come right now.
What floor are you on?
100th,
north East.
Alright.
Okay,
so what's your phone number there?
Sir,
I'm on a cell phone.
Alright,
no problem.
We'll get to you.
Please,
immediately.
They're on the way.
Bye.
Hello.
Who are you talking to?
Should we go home?
Uh,
maybe.
955.
Go ahead.
Okay,
north of Pops town, about 20 miles, code 3321.
New York City A3 Heavy 162417 south.
That's a hijacked aircraft,
it's an American Boeing 757.
And he's going south now?
We have no idea what he's doing.
Okay.
Okay?
Alright.
Thank you.
This is pandemonium.
But as you can also see there,
Mark,
relative to any sort of plane crash,
it is a clear and looks like a pretty decent day there.
We'll check in with Tom just a second,
but Tom doesn't look like there's any obstruction at all in the air over there in New York.
Good morning,
New York.
United 93,
New York Center.
Good morning.
It's only six in the morning, though.
So,
I mean,
it's supposed to be in news.
Kill this,
I love you,
I don't know if I'm going to be okay,
I love you so much.
Guy,
you know how close we were just to being killed?
I mean,
part of that fuselage just could have come this way.
Delta 2315,
Delta 2315 turn left immediately to a heading of 200.
Left turn immediately to 00,
Delta 2315.
Roger.
Traffic,
1 o'clock,
10 miles,
turning into your face,
descending out of 31.
It's a hijacked aircraft.
We don't know what is...
doing.
U.S. Air 542 turn left heading 200.
200 Yes, 542.
50 Mike Juliet maintain flight level 210.
Delta 2315. The traffic is now at your well. If you're heading on the 200 heading, he's about your two o'clock and about seven. Uh, looks like 30.6 descending.
We haven't been sight, sir.
Delta 2315,
roger.
Yeah,
he's inside.
Okay,
you can maneuver as necessary to avoid that aircraft,
sir.
I do not know what he's doing.
Delta 2315,
any evasive action you need to take is approved.
Come on,
we can go right now!
On the wires...
What's concerning me is the fact that this appears to be still spreading.
Yeah,
on the wires,
Mark,
We should point out that witnesses are saying it was a twin-engine plane that flew right into the Northern Tower there of the World Trade Center.
The water is on the 78th floor.
We're going to need the PD for security around the entire World Trade Center.
We have scopes coming from the World Trade Center right now, from the upper floors.
10-4.
American, 77,
Indy.
Indianapolis,
Good morning,
our Canada 579,
would you 350 for 390?
Our Canada 579,
Indy Center,
roger.
American, 77,
Indy.
American 77,
American,
Indy.
I just wanted to let you know I love you and I'm stuck in this building in New York.
There's lots of smoke and we just wanted you to know that I love you always.
Are they saying,
you know,
I should get off the phone because David might be trying to call me because I left a message.
I'll call you back.
Hi Darren,
it's Tammy Michaels.
I'm in the Hilton Millennium Hotel,
New York.
Across the street from me,
and I have my video camera running,
the World Trade Center was just hit by a plane.
The debris was hitting our window.
We are completely,
we are exactly across...
What can you tell us about what you saw?
I can tell you that I was watching TV and there was this sonic boom and the TV went out. And I thought, maybe that the Concorde was back in service, because I've heard about those sonic booms. And I got up to my window,
I live in Battery Park City, right next to the Twin Towers,
and I looked up and the side of the World Trade Center exploded.
When I looked up and at that point, debris started falling, I couldn't believe what I was watching.
Delta 231.5. Can you tell me what kind of aircraft that is and whose companies?
Rock.
Delta 2315,
Can you tell me what kind of aircraft it is and whose company?
He's going behind us,
sir.
I'm going to try to get a good look at him.
Delta 2315.
Yes,
sir.
542,
you see him there at 12 o'clock and 5 eastbound,
28 and 8.
Affirmative.
We got an RA on him.
We're leveling.
Okay,
you can. DSR 542,
we're heading a 2-9-0 now,
radar Vectors for your climb.
2-9-0,
Yes, sir,
542.
Delta 2315,
he's behind you now,
you can turn right to heading a 2-8-0 and join the airway.
Yes, sir,
and I didn't get a good...
Good look at him,
but it was a darker paint scheme.
Okay,
yes,
sir.
542,
Can you tell who he is?
Is that the guy that was right ahead of us?
Yes,
it is.
Looks like a Delta,
find the bank.
Okay,
looks like a Delta 75.
Thanks,
sir.
Delta 45,
maintain flight level 270 and contact New York.
1-3-4-3-2.
Test,
test,
test.
WCBS 880,
because we are right on top of this for you, with reporters on the way to the scene.
Tom
Tom Kaminski is overhead, giving us the bird's eye view, and, in fact, was the first to tell us about it and see it.
Tom's been hovering around.
Let's go to him right now. Up in Shopper 880.
Tom.
Of course,
the worst thing could well be,
and this is totally conjecture,
that on a clear day,
someone doesn't miss seeing that.
Obviously,
this could be a s****** mission.
Oh,
boy,
yeah,
that hadn't occurred to me.
Well,
that's what I meant.
You just don't want to conjecture.
That's true.
I saw the debris,
I saw the explosion,
the debris,
the fiery debris was coming right down in front of our window.
I was afraid part of it was going to come into our actual hotel room.
Do you see any of the debris currently on the ground area?
Absolutely.
I mean,
it's continuing to kind of flutter down, like leaflets.
And at first there was just tons of debris and it continues to fall out.
And it looks like these uppermost floors are definitely on fire.
Thank you.
Oh,
you can't stay here.
I'm sorry,
you gotta go.
Go!
You gotta clear!
Let's go!
Now,
you say you were out there grabbing a smoke when it happened?
Right.
What did the other people do when they heard the noise?
Well,
there was no noise.
I'm up on the 14th floor.
Oh,
you were on the 14th floor,
I see.
Yeah,
so I'm not street level.
I was up on the 14th floor,
and I was just,
like,
looking out.
You know,
looking out,
you know,
just watching the scenery and when I saw the plane.
Yeah,
she knew,
she knew.
God,
you should,
I have a video tape of it.
You should just see this thing.
Wow.
Mary,
can you tell us what you saw?
Mary?
Mary,
are you there?
I am here.
Mary,
can you please tell us what you saw and where you are?
I'm at 14th Street and 5th Avenue and we saw a plane flying low overhead, which caught all of our attention.
We looked up.
It was making a beeline for the World Trade Center.
Trade Center.
It was very low,
extremely low,
not a big plane like an airliner,
but not a tiny propeller plane either,
a small jet plane.
There are people trapped up there.
This is just the most incredible thing in the world,
and it's right in front of me at this moment.
We have flames shooting out the window,
Stanley.
Flames are coming out the window.
We've been told to stay in our hotel,
and I'm watching this right in front of me.
I wanted to call and tell you.
I'm at the Millennium Hotel.
My phone number is 212-693-2001.
Okay.
I don't,
Hey, mom,
it's Brad.
I just wanted to call and let you know,
I'm sure that you heard,
that a plane crashed into World Trade Center 1.
We're fine.
We're in World Trade Center 2.
I'm obviously alive and well over here.
But obviously a pretty scary experience.
I saw a guy fall out of probably the 91st story all the way down.
So you're welcome to give a call here.
I think we'll be here all day.
But give me a call back later.
Love you.
We had heard earlier from one of the witnesses,
M.
David Levin,
told us that the ground floor windows had been shaking,
Kelly.
Everybody we've been speaking with seems to have a vantage point of one side of the World Trade Center.
Hey,
I should make a,
I don't mean to interrupt the fun,
but this is a breaking news story,
a serious news story.
A plane has crashed,
hold it,
into the World Trade Center.
You're kidding!
The World Trade Center is on fire,
which is the...
What is going on?
Really?
Let me look out my window.
It's the tallest...
Right there.
It wasn't like one of those private planes?
Oh,
dude.
Do you see it?
Dude,
it's just hot.
Oh,
my God.
I've got to go out on my roof.
This is incredible.
The whole thing is on fire.
Yeah.
All right.
I mean,
not a little fire.
No,
it's huge.
Oh,
Yeah.
What if a plane hits a building?
I've got to run.
How did it take so long to happen?
I'll call you back.
Right,
bye.
I know.
To left.
Sloping to the left diagonally.
Smoke is pouring.
Out of that face. And now we have quite a bit of smoke and flame pouring out of the eastern side of Tower number one. And that also about ten.
This is fucking unbelievable.
Keep holding.
There's no way.
Somebody did that.
That was a plane.
There's no...
It was a plane.
Yeah.
But...
I got friends that work in that building,
Ryan.
Oh my god.
I'm sure there's a lot of people who do that.
No,
it was a big two-engine jet.
When you say a sonic boom,
did you actually feel anything?
Were things shaking in your apartment?
Uh,
you know,
yeah,
you could feel it.
It was just a gigantic sonic boom.
The TV nearly,
it went off for a second and then it went back on.
And the windows,
you know,
you felt the vibrations on the windows.
American,
77 American,
any radio check?
How do you read?
American 77,
American Radio check,
How do you read?
This is,
uh,
this is Henderson,
American, 77,
I don't know what happened to him,
I'm trying to reach him.
Looks like he took a turn to the south,
and now I'm,
uh,
I don't know what altitude he's at or what he's doing,
heading towards Falmouth at 35.
Okay,
I'll try to get a hold of him,
thanks.
American 10-23,
Contact Indy Center on 123.77,
Good day.
23-77,
American 10-23,
Good day.
USR 17-51 to center,
maintain flight level 350.
USR 17-51,
descend to 350.
North 489,
Quebec Sierra,
Clear Direct, Spartansburg.
Clear Direct Spartansburg,
489,
Quebec, Sierra.
American 77,
Indy Radio,
check,
How do you read?
Indy,
we're calling Flexjet 423.
Flexjet 423,
negative.
American, 77,
Indy Center,
How do you read?
American 77,
Indy Radio,
check,
How do you read?
U.S. Air 1751,
contact Indy Center on 134.22,
Good day.
1751,
3422.
Number 489,
Quebec, Sierra,
Contact Indy Center on 134.22,
Good day.
34229,
Quebec Sierra,
Good day.
U.S. Air 12,
correction,
U.S. Air 217,
Clear Direct, Holston Mountain.
Direct Holston Mountain,
U.S. Air 217.
Ah,
fucking plane or something hit the World Trade Center.
I'm sorry,
do you know?
Something happened at the World Trade Center,
it's not good.
Mike and I are here,
yeah,
we're both standing here,
we're looking right at it.
It's un-fucking-believable.
So...
Did you try to call?
Mike,
there's debris falling down from the thing.
See it?
See it falling?
All right,
I love you.
Bye.
I will.
We are.
I got somebody with me.
We're fine.
All right,
bye.
Mike,
let's go check it out.
Come on.
Mom,
it's Steven.
My plane,
my building got hit by a plane.
And right now,
I think I'm okay.
I'm safe now,
but it's smoky.
I just want to say how much I love you.
And
I will call you when I'm safe.
Okay,
Mom?
Bye.
Go ahead.
I'm sorry,
I got some handouts for you.
We got some incidents going over here.
Is it all the 2433 gonna be okay at 33?
I had a climate for traffic of a United 175 that just took off out of a thing.
We might have a hijack over here,
two of them.
2433,
thank you for the help.
That
United just took off and we're not really sure what he's doing.
You thought it was a United 767, though?
That's what it looked like.
Thank you, Delta.
2433,
finding a 270,
join J75,
resume on navigation.
Thanks for the climb.
To 15 stories up,
so it is our guess that whatever went into Tower number one went into it and stayed there.
We have not seen...
Here's. According to an eyewitness,
it wasn't dropping steadily lower,
appeared not as if a plane was in trouble,
no nose down.
I'm reading directly from this,
so it's obviously just some...
Yeah.
It's alright,
I'm sure,
dude.
That's fucking...
That is an inferno.
That is unbelievable.
Unbelievable,
dude.
They're never gonna get that fucker out.
USR 542,
was it a 757?
Yes, sir.
USR 542,
was it a 757?
Yeah,
it looked like a 757,
and it looked like a Delo.
If you'd have told me that that was him,
I could have got a better look at it.
Okay,
yeah,
I'm sorry,
I was busy looking at the guy in front of you.
USR,
TWA3,
traffic,
one o'clock,
ten miles southeastbound,
descending at a 28.7.
We believe it's a hijacked aircraft.
It looks like a 757,
We're trying to find out what the delivery is.
QB3
heavy is looking negative contact.
Delta 2315,
you can proceed direct to Modena on course.
We're maneuvering to get out of his way,
but
I concur with the guy behind us.
Okay,
thank you.
Delta
2315, Direct Modena on course.
Center,
QB3?
Yes.
We're in prep now at,
looks like,
3 o'clock.
Okay,
can you see what the delivery was?
It's a dark paint scheme. And if I was guessing, I would say United, but that would be just a guess.
Okay.
The center of the aircraft was light color with a dark tail.
Tell me where you are, if you would.
Right now, I'm back in the hotel.
I'm in the hotel offices here,
the front office.
Okay,
where were you when the...
I was standing right in front of the hotel.
I'm the doorman there.
And um...
The hotel,
the hotel,
which hotel?
Marriott World Trade Center.
Right across from the World Trade Center?
It's actually right in between.
Right in between the World Trade Center?
Yes.
Okay,
so you were standing outside and tell us what you saw and what you heard.
Well,
what I heard first,
an explosion.
And I just figured that it was a plane passing by.
Then all of a sudden,
stuff just started falling,
like bricks and paper and everything.
And so I just kind of, like, ran like inside to get away from the falling debris and glass and so forth.
Then after, like, everything stopped because it like, was falling in the street and the cars were crashing into each other,
then when it kind of stopped,
I heard a guy screaming.
And when I looked over,
there was this guy that was on fire,
so I kind of, like, ran over.
And I tried to, like, put the fire out on him and he was.
He was like screaming, and I just told him to roll, roll, and he said he can't. And then another guy came over with his bag and how I put the flood, the flames out on him. So right now he's been taken care of. I just had everyone called an ambulance and stuff to help him out. He caught fire as a result of the falling debris.
Hey,
Coach.
This is Henderson.
Still haven't gotten American 77.
Last he was at 35 going to Falmouth,
so I don't know where he is out there anywhere yet.
So I'm still trying to get a hold of him.
We can contact the company.
Okay.
Thanks.
FlexJet 2,
correction,
FlexJet 423,
Contact Indy Center on 134.22,
Good day.
Charleston, 59,
Line, Cleveland.
Morgantown.
American 77, Indy.
Senator,
American
2493. American 2493,
Go ahead.
Yeah,
we sent a message to dispatch to have him come up on 2027.
Is that what you want him to do?
Yeah,
we had him on the west side of our airspace and he went into coast. And I don't have a track on him. And now he's not talking to me, so we don't know exactly what happened to him.
We're trying to get a hold of him.
We also contacted your company, so thanks for the help.
Alright.
Seattle,
Washington.
Uh,
yes,
Komo Television,
I'd like to use your number, please.
No,
K-O-M-O.
I need the,
I need the...
Okay.
Battalion 2,
My eyes on you.
go.
Be advised,
we have jumpers,
battalion 2,
jumpers.
Alright,
Division 1,
be advised,
Battalion 2,
advise you have jumpers from the World Trade Center.
What?
What pro- you heard this sound,
I'm just trying to understand what happened.
You heard a sound,
that's what compelled you to look up into the sky.
You could hear a jet coming overhead and it sounded low. So many of us looked up to see what was,
you know,
because it sounded so close,
we all looked up.
And like, a-
like I said,
it didn't look like it was swerving or out of control.
It was going steadily lower.
It was definitely going steadily lower,
but it wasn't dropping. Like nose first, or anything that would make you think that the plane was in trouble.
Right.
Mike,
put your mic on.
Put your mic on.
54545.
American dispatch Jim McConnell.
This is the Indianapolis Center trying to get a hold of American 77.
Uh,
hang on one second, please.
What?
Hang on one second, sir.
Alright.
What are you trying to get a hold of?
American 77.
Okay.
On frequency 120.27.
120.27.
We weren't talking to him, and all of a sudden it's just, uh...
Okay.
Alright,
we'll get a hold of him for you.
Alright.
Division 1 to Manhattan,
did they already jump?
Marine 1 to Manhattan,
Division 1,
What's your message,
K?
That jumper,
did it already jump?
The Italian 2 has no jumper,
jump,
K.
We do not know...
In terms of injuries or fatalities, we have absolutely no information about that at this point in time. All we can tell you is that something has obviously crashed into the World Trade Center, and our eyewitnesses have told us it was an airplane of some sort. I
can't get any cell phone coverage. They are never going to get that thing. Absolutely never
wind draft.
Wind draft.
As we've heard before,
we said earlier that there was at least one speculative report.
Report that an airplane had crashed in,
whether deliberately or accidentally,
we don't know.
And they are continuing reports from people who say that they saw an airplane,
one woman saying that she saw a jet.
What did you see?
Well,
I hear the explosion.
I just walked my dog and then I heard this plane coming down.
And I'm born in 1941 in Germany.
I see a lot of bombing.
And it was always in the basement,
so I could, eeeeeeep,
and then it hit.
And then another explosion.
Did you see it hit?
No.
I live on Mercer Street, further down.
But you saw the plane?
No.
No,
I heard it.
It was a big engine.
It was not just like a helicopter.
I hope not too many people have got hurt.
Okay,
bye-bye.
How much debris,
can you give us an idea of how much came crashing to the ground?
It's just a lot.
Bricks,
a lot of bricks,
a lot of glass.
I'm like,
enough to damage cars on the street,
make cars swerve into each other,
that kind of thing.
American 77,
any radio check?
How do you read?
And it went right in.
Right in.
You heard it.
I mean, you heard him screaming.
Screaming in there.
I mean...
I thought it was a jet going over, like a military plane or something.
But boy, that thing went right in.
And just shit just went...
Out the side of the building.
Unbelievable.
I just stood there,
I was like,
oh,
I was in the building.
U.S. Air 542,
um,
did you say you thought it was a dark paint scheme?
No,
it was a light colored paint scheme with a dark tail.
I thought it was a different one.
I'm on the Yardley traffic.
Okay,
understood.
U.S. Air 542,
Thank you,
and I'm sorry I didn't tune you in to him head on as quick as I could have.
I was busy talking to the guy right in front of you.
We could have joined up.
Yeah,
I was actually much more concerned about the possibility of you getting too close to him.
Yes,
sir,
542.
Thanks for your help.
Contact New York on 134.32.
432,
yes,
sir,
542.
3-1 to Manhattan,
we're an urgent message.
You have three rescue,
okay?
Okay,
I want all but one of them here.
10-4.
Jules,
this is Ryan.
I live on an airplane that's been hijacked.
Things don't go well.
I'm looking good.
I just want you to know, I absolutely love you.
I want you to be good.
Go have a good time.
Same to my parents and everybody.
I just totally love you,
and I'll see you later.
Bye,
babe.
I'll call you.
Stuff is still falling.
Let's get out of here.
Mike,
we're going to get killed.
we're going to get killed!
Mike!
Now there's helicopters in the sky.
I can't get them. But apparently CNN is saying that a twin engine airplane crashed into it.
You did?
Seriously?
I saw the jet.
I knew the jet was in trouble.
It was way too low.
And I ran.
I saw it.
Then I saw the smoke and I said,
I couldn't...
I figured out what happened.
I can't believe he hit the goddamn Moon trade center.
I saw the plane.
You saw the plane?
Oh,
I saw the plane.
The two-engine, commercial type jet,
but it looked like a freighter.
Did you hear it?
Yeah,
I felt it.
It was like an earthquake.
I was running my nose.
That thing was soaking wet.
Oh yeah.
Just a gentle light of rain.
It came this way.
Straight through.
I mean,
debris shot out,
but...
No,
it was a Learjet.
Joining us now on the line is an eyewitness who is in the Empire State Building.
Bob Bradley,
what do you see?
I,
uh...
I saw this plane.
It didn't look like it was out of control at all.
It was a medium-sized body plane, with engines on both sides. Just fly right into the building.
I thought at first it was a shadow that was going to swoop over top of the building,
like we've seen in the past. Just sitting here in our office.
But this plane headed directly for the building.
And note,
it didn't look like there was any trouble at all with the plane.
It didn't swerve at all.
It just landed directly in the building.
It was almost like a gray-black color in nature on the plane.
And it seemed as though it just flew right into the building, without...
Yeah,
like he wanted to fly into the building.
He wasn't trying to avoid the building?
No.
This guy swooped directly into the building.
All right,
that's what it looked like from one vantage point.
That's from the Empire State Building.
Thank you very much.
You got it.
I hear alarms going off down there.
What's happening?
That's our hotel alarm, and basically,
I guess that went off automatically.
They've evacuated everyone in the hotel and evacuated all employees.
They have evacuated the hotel?
Yes.
Immediately?
Always amazed.
You know,
a plane once crashed in the 40s.
A plane crashed right into the Empire State Building.
Right in.
Right.
What kind of plane?
Was it a private,
stupid plane?
I don't have any more details.
I'm following this story.
I hope this wasn't one of those terrorist, k******* attacks.
You know what?
He's preparing to...
Let's get back to you and Pamela.
.sit. In for Dan, Rather.
That's why he's being very serious.
Yes.
Taking over Dan, Rather.
This is my audition.
We go now to Sandra Rodriguez,
who is on the site at the...
World Trade Center.
Sandra?
Hello,
Howard!
The fire is going very well right now.
Uh,
yeah,
I'm gonna be taking over Dan rather when he retires.
Hey,
Howard!
It's a very serious story,
I mean,
I'm sure there's...
Fortunately,
it's early in the morning,
maybe not too many people are in the building.
Uh,
understand right now that we do have somebody joining us on the phone.
Yes,
a Paul Schwinger is on the phone live to tell us what he saw.
Good morning,
Paul.
Good morning.
Go ahead,
take it away.
Where were you and what did you see?
Well,
I was in my apartment, pretty much right under the flight path of this plane.
In the village.
And
I heard this really,
really loud noise go by,
and I thought it was an Air Force jet on display.
So I looked right out the window,
and I saw this twin-engine plane fly right over my house,
and it was losing altitude.
And then
I saw the impact and the explosion,
this huge ball of flame.
And the plane looked either like a 737 or an Airbus.
I see the flim flim,
I see the flim Fl.
One second, Dave,
I'm told we have a witness named Jim on the phone,
an eyewitness.
Jim, are you there?
Yes.
Jim,
what's your last name, Jim?
Last name's Friedel.
Jim,
tell us what you saw, if you would.
Well,
I was looking out the window, and normally, you'll see...
Planes kind of flying low over the Hudson,
but this is a large plane.
It's something like a 727,
and it was banking,
And the only reason I kind of looked at it is because I thought it was rather low.
Banking very hard,
and then it just drove.
Right through the World Trade Center tower.
What's your vantage point there,
Jim?
I am actually across the Hudson and Hoboken,
but I have a clear view right at the World Trade Towers.
You said it was a plane.
You said a plane.
Yeah,
it was a jet,
a small jet,
like a private jet or something.
Yeah,
you heard it.
It was flying.
Yeah,
he was cooking.
You can just hear stuff breaking and popping and glasses going.
It's just,
I mean,
look at that.
I can't hear anything.
Maybe we should get the radio,
Shane.
It's getting worse,
the fire's getting worse.
It's out of control,
it's out of control.
There's no way they're gonna be able to get up there.
That's what he did!
There's a person,
guys,
there's people falling out!
That was a person.
Oh, no,
there's a person,
Tammy.
Oh my God!
Hey Joe,
you see 3321 code just southwest of Newark by about 15,
18,
20 miles?
15,000 descending.
Looking,
hold on,
southwest of Newark by about 15,
20?
We're tracking him,
made a hard left turn,
he's descending pretty rapidly.
Especially what just happened in there.
I got somebody who keeps coasting,
but it looks like he's going into one of the small air points down there.
No,
this guy's a big boy.
This guy's a big boy because he's leaving some big contracts.
I'm trying to put...
There he is, right there.
Hold on.
I'm just out of 9,500,
9,000 now.
Do you know who he is?
We just...
We don't know who he is.
We're just picking him up now.
All right.
Heads up,
man.
It looks like another one.
All right.
Mike,
sit out of his path!
As we come on air,
we have serious news of a major possible air crash in the United States.
A plane appears to have crashed into one of New York's tallest buildings,
the World Trade Center.
Oh,
you just talked directly to him?
No,
I didn't.
I can't get a hold of anybody.
That's my antenna.
Sorry.
Now,
it did seem to you that it was done on purpose?
You know,
I don't know if I can say that,
but it was a very odd type of turn.
It was headed directly,
directly at the building.
So whether that was on purpose or not,
I can't tell.
I don't know if he was trying to avoid or they were headed for it.
As Matt just mentioned,
we have a breaking news story to tell you about.
Apparently,
a plane has just crashed into the World Trade Center here in New York City.
It happened just a few moments ago,
apparently.
We have very little information available at this point in time.
But on the phone,
we do have Jennifer Oberstein,
who apparently witnessed this event.
Jennifer,
can you hear me?
Hello?
Hi, Jennifer.
Hi Katie.
Hi,
can you please tell me what you saw and give me any information about what's going on there?
Yes,
I have to tell you,
it's quite terrifying.
I'm in shock right now.
I came out of the subway at Bowling Green.
I was heading to work in Battery Park at the Ritz-Carlton Hotel and I come out...
And
I saw a big,
I heard a boom, walked up and there was a big ball of fire.
I'm now looking north at the World Trade Center, and it is the left...
You can just see it's literally debris.
Oh, my lord.
All that's above that floor is...
I'm a super cool.
Immediately, there's speculation or cause for concern.
This is the World Trade Center. That was the...
The center of a terrorist bombing some years ago.
So the questions have to be asked,
was this purely an accident or could this have been an intentional act?
I was out here,
I heard two explosions.
You know what the guy said?
Did a plane hit them?
A plane hit them.
Two explosions.
Two separate ones.
More jets.
Why the hell is the train so damn low?
You know what?
That could be a s****** train.
Those afterburners.
Turn the light one on.
Get these people out of there.
I was just in the building.
You went to see what they were doing.
I took the train,
got out on the knee.
The smoke was in the train station.
How could he not see?
He must have been in the train.
He must have.
Check with the NAMS,
do you know if anyone down there has done any coordination to scramble fighter type airplanes?
There's two big airplanes in the area?
No,
we have several situations going on here.
It's escalating big,
big time.
And we need to get the military involved with this.
Wow,
what's going on?
Just get me somebody who has the authority.
We're in a hurry to get military in the air now.
Alright.
I'll go tell them.
If you have to stay away from the towers,
you're gonna get killed.
See the pieces falling,
Mike?
Did
you hear anything when it took place?
Did you hear the crash?
Yes,
I did.
In terms of anything beforehand,
though,
no.
I mean,
I couldn't tell if...
If the plane was in distress or anything like that.
But certainly, when it hit,
there was a large explosion.
And again,
you had smoke and debris coming up the other side as well.
All right,
Jim,
thank you very much.
I've been talking to Jim Friedel,
eyewitness who...
Copy that.
Go ahead.
I'm ready.
Call 4 David,
I'm in Manhattan.
Call
4 David.
10-84 at the World Trade Center.
Call 4, David,
repeat,
10.
10-84.
Call 4 David,
we're getting reports on the 104...
I also have the
103rd floor,
Northwest room
103, with people trapped also.
I have the
83rd floor with people trapped as well.
Call Fort David to see if...
Call Fort David,
10-4.
Alright,
Timing's 0901,
462.
Wendy.
Who's on the phone?
I am.
Oh,
Wendy,
you're not.
Mike, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop. you can't. Mike. stop. please. Oh my God. Oh my
God. Mike. stop, stop, Mike. I can't. I can't.
So we were filming it a moment ago and the two of us were fine.
Now it's burning.
Big, heavy things falling at a
rate that a piece of paper would not fall.
Oh my god!
No way.
Like, that can make a...
Yeah,
I see it,
I see it.
I just,
I mean,
who's to say it's not like a chair?
Regardless,
it's gonna be so dangerous at that base.
Obviously.
Wait.
Car
9 Charlie to Manhattan.
Car 9 Charlie.
Go to fallback step 3.
Call forward to Division 1.
Call back,
step 3 has been implemented.
step 3 has been implemented,
Oh, shit!
What is it, Mike?
Somebody fell!
What?
You're fucking lying.
You're lying.
Somebody just fell.
Oh my god.
Oh shit,
people are diving out of the building.
My god,
it's just not right.
Witness said there was a huge explosion.
They thought, in fact, that the blast had come from inside.
Fan.
What do you want to know about Pam?
Um,
okay, so then you're...
We were hanging out,
we were at scores.
You're kissing her.
It wasn't like a big make out.
It wasn't like that.
But she wasn't,
she wasn't pushing you away either.
Nah,
she was just being a little bit playful, but...
So that's...
Did you feel her breasts?
What?
Did you feel her breasts being asked?
Did you feel it?
You know,
the guy's on his shoes,
I don't remember.
That's a yes.
Now you would remember if he banged those things.
I don't think I did.
No,
Did you pull a butt close?
I felt their butt.
Oh.
How then do you not close?
You were just inches away.
You closed.
You were inches away from the big one.
You banged the big one.
What?
You were inches away.
You think he did it?
No,
I didn't.
I didn't keep banging.
I never banged Pam Anderson.
We just got a report that the Associated Press is now reporting that it was an aircraft.
So that's one more.
Witness weighing in,
or at least one more source weighing in on the fact that it was an aircraft of some kind.
And as Don Daly reported,
this occurred about 15 or 20 minutes ago in downtown New York.
And New York time,
that would have been about
20 minutes or a quarter of nine.
This is a time when literally tens of thousands of people are coming to work.
At the World Trade Center.
Another eyewitness,
Elliot Walker,
who is actually a producer here on the Today Show.
Elliot,
can you hear me?
Yes,
hi, Katie.
Hi Elliot,
tell me where you are and what you saw.
Well,
I live in this area.
I've returned to my apartment,
but I was walking down the sidewalk delivering my...
Young daughter to school. And we heard a very loud sound,
the kind of sound you hear when a plane is going fast past you,
followed by an enormous crash and an immediate explosion.
I don't think we could feel shock waves,
but we sort of felt like we did.
And we were in a position where we could see the trade center almost immediately between the other buildings.
And an enormous fireball that must have been 300 feet across was visible immediately.
A secondary explosion,
I think,
and then plumes of smoke.
There must have been a three-block cloud of white smoke.
Well,
what we can see right here as we were coming up the Hudson River,
we can see thick black smoke indicating the fire is still going on right now in the World Trade Center.
For as far as the eye can see. And you can tell, right here at the top of this tower, there's a huge gaping hole, flame still inside, thick black smoke still coming out. We have not been able to see what, if any kind of an aircraft is inside the building. This is the best vantage point right here, and as you can see, just a huge gaping hole throughout the entire side of this tower. Right now.
Fucked up, get a garbage, can look at
the hole,
holy shit,
it was a plane,
it was definitely a plane?
They said a 737 plane.
Steve.
Dude,
that was a s******- that was a terrorist attack.
Yeah,
don't say it.
It's on,
you know it,
right?
I don't know,
God.
Everything's fucked up.
I just thank God my mother's on vacation.
Holy-
And you notice something?
The flames are getting lower and lower,
guy.
Yup.
They're slowly going down the building.
That building looks like it took a major hit.
It did!
It's a plane!
God!
That building's never gonna be the same again.
How could you?
Bring that building down!
You can't.
You gotta implode it.
Just mantlet it from the top!
Let's say no to people.
Tommy,
are you still there?
Yes,
I am,
Terry.
Tommy,
I'm going to reconfirm with downstairs,
but,
uh,
as far as the tape,
But Bobby Jones seemed to think that the guy said that we have planes.
Now,
I don't know if it was because it was the accent,
or if there's more than one,
but,
uh,
I'm going to reconfirm that for you,
and I'll get back to you real quick,
okay?
Appreciate it.
Yeah,
boy.
Plane's at the shore.
Breathe.
Few more details on what you've already said.
Nisha,
All we know is that it's described as a passenger plane.
We don't know how many passengers it was carrying.
It does seem to have entered the Trade Tower very high up and there are gaping holes on both sides of the tower.
It looks as if it's penetrated right through the structure of it.
We don't know precisely how many floors are affected.
We don't know the number of casualties or injuries,
but it is...
Quite clearly, a major disaster.
And we remind you again that there was a terrorist bomb that did go off at the World Trade Center years ago.
It was down in the garage level,
But we have no reason to say over and over again to speculate in that way.
Obviously no indication that this could have been related to that.
Right.
You saw it happen?
Have you heard it?
What happened?
Thank you.
Yeah,
we heard that, right?
You think that was a terrorist?
It sounded like it flew right by the building, and some guy said it flew over right in front of the building.
Terrorist attack?
I don't know,
I don't know.
They have some guy on the phone who said it was either a 737 or an Airbus.
He witnessed the whole thing.
An Airbus?
Yeah.
American Dispatch,
can we get a hold of him?
Yeah,
this is Indianapolis Center.
We,
uh,
I don't know if I talked to the same guy about American 77?
Yeah.
I,
I so called him,
but I didn't get a reply back from him.
We,
uh,
we lost track control of the guys in Coast Track,
so we haven't,
We don't really know where his target is,
and we can't get a hold of him.
Um,
you guys tried him and no response?
No response.
Yeah,
we have no radar contact and no communications with him.
So if you guys could try him again.
We're doing it.
All right,
thanks a lot.
We're doing it.
Thank you.
.plane. overhead,
And then all of a sudden, I thought it sounded kind of louder than I looked up.
Up, and all of a sudden it smashed right dead into the center of the World Trade Center.
Big flash of flame,
fire coming out from all over.
Then all of the bricks,
there's a huge hole right now.
It almost looks like the plane probably went through.
I'm not sure.
There are fire crews just screaming into this area from every conceivable direction.
We're looking at crews flying down West Street currently into this area.
We've noticed some coming across Canal Street.
And just this entire area of Lower Manhattan is absolutely going to need to be avoided.
For how long,
there is absolutely no way to tell.
Interstate
Amsterline?
Yes, sir,
go ahead.
What time,
sir?
Copy,
Alistair.
Thank you.
They have a second possible hijack.
United 175?
175.
What is it?
United 175 is the other aircraft.
Mode 33321.
Who were you talking to?
I was talking to New York.
We're skipping back,
you wait here.
Okay.
Let's go.
What's up?
Good building.
Oh,
oh,
there goes another person, guy,
Oh my god!
What's going on?
Elliot,
have you,
of course,
because of the incident that occurred in the early
1990s, have you seen any evidence,
Elliot,
of people being taken out of the building?
You say that emergency vehicles are there,
understandably so,
but of course, the major...
Major concern is human loss.
I mean,
do you know if there were many people in the building?
Oh,
another one just hit.
Something else just hit.
A very large plane just flew directly over my building,
and there's been another collision.
Can you see it?
I can see it on this shot.
Something else has just hit.
We just saw a plane circling the building.
We just saw a plane circling the building a second ago on the shot, right before that.
I think there may have been another impact.
Can you tell?
I just heard another very loud bang,
and a very large plane, that might have been a
DC-9 or a 747, just flew past my window,
and I think it may have hit the trade center again.
To be honest,
Elliot,
I didn't get the impression that it was that big a plane.
It looks big from here.
I did see a plane go by a second ago,
though,
and it has now.
.impacted? The building.
I'm trying to see if it's the different tower.
I think it may have been.
I believe the first one was World Trade Center 1,
and it looks,
from what I'm seeing on the television,
like it may have been the second building.
We're gonna see...
Alright,
okay,
I'll get whatever you need.
Well,
are you shooting?
Yeah.
It's on the...
I'm...
I burst into fucking tears.
It's really...
What's this other jet doing?
What the hell is that?
Holy fuck!
Oh my god!
Jesus fucking Christ!
Don't touch it!
Oh my
God!
Sir.
Did you see that?
Yeah,
I saw it.
Another one just hit the building.
Wow.
Another one just hit it hard.
Another one just hit the roadside.
The whole building just came apart.
Holy smokes.
Alright,
I guess you guys can be busy.
It was an end?
Holy shit!
Come on!
Get him up!
Oh my
God. Oh my
God. No.
Get out of here.
Let's go.
No.
Get out of here.
This high level,
I assume the firefighters have got to get up there and,
you know,
fight it from inside.
Oh,
if you're taking a look now,
you can see that we've just had another explosion,
and that is considerably lower.
Is that in the other building?
Is that what I'm witnessing?
That apparently does look like it is in the other building at this point.
And that looks to be lower,
which means there,
um,
you know,
obviously there are considerable numbers of stories above that explosion that we just saw.
Perhaps we can get another look from one of our Sky cams that can take a different angle.
Yes,
you can tell that. It now appears that both buildings,
um,
are suffering some kind of the damage.
This morning, my colleague
Glenn Walker has just joined me here in the studio. And Glenn,
I don't know if you received any other information,
but perhaps you can...
Apparently a large plane,
according to that eyewitness,
Jim Friedle,
vantage point from Hoboken,
that, as you look at the picture from our chopper now arriving at the scene,
Jim Friedle in Hoboken said. It appeared to bank sharply and smash directly,
perhaps purposefully,
into...
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, God!
There's another one!
Oh my goodness,
there's another one!
Seems to be on purpose.
Oh my goodness.
Now it's obvious,
I think,
that there's a second plane just crashed into the World Trade Center.
I think we have a terrorist act of proportions that we cannot begin to imagine at this juncture.
Oh my God.
My goodness.
A second plane now has crashed into the other tower of the World Trade Center.
Obviously,
terrorist attack.
On the World Trade Center.
What we have been fearing...
What we have been fearing for the longest time here, apparently has come to pass.
A disastrous terrorist attack on the World Trade Center.
Both towers,
planes smashing into each one.
Oh
my God.
Oh my God.
My God!
Shit,
I just got that!
Oh my
God! My God!
Oh Jesus!
Get the car out of the damn way,
will ya?
Come with me,
idiot!
Now we've gotten a look at least three sides of Tower number one, and that is the only building exploding right now. Tommy, We're seeing another, apparently that was another plane. We have a witness who we just spoke to a moment ago. We're here,
we're hearing from Carl Tendler,
who was at the village apartments in Washington Square.
We're trying to bring him on the air.
All right,
Carl.
That was the second plane that just blew?
Building number one.
It's been another one,
Carl.
Yes,
he hit building number one.
The other building.
Yes,
he flew right into it.
Describe exactly what you just saw,
please.
Yes,
I saw this jet coming towards the building.
He was low.
He was about halfway up.
And he flew into,
it looked like the south side.
East corner of the building.
So building number two is now burning.
Holy shit!
I got that!
That was the other fucking building!
Wasn't even the same building.
Hello!
Now can you see if there's a lot of debris downstairs,
Winston?
No,
because it looked like it inverted.
With the impact,
everything went inside the building.
Inside.
The only thing that came out was a little bit of the outside awning.
But I'd say the huge,
the hole is,
let me just get a better look right now.
Okay,
go ahead.
I'd say the hole takes about...
That's our 6th,
7th floors were taken out.
And there's more explosions right now.
Hold on,
people are running.
Hold on.
Hold on just a moment.
We've got an explosion inside.
The building's exploding right now.
You've got people running up the street.
I don't know what's going on.
Okay,
just put Winston on pause there for just a moment.
the whole building just exploded for more,
the whole top part.
Okay.
The building's still intact.
People are running up the streets.
Am I still connected?
Winston,
this would support probably what Libby and you both said,
that perhaps the fuselage was in the building that would cause a second explosion such as that.
That's what just happened then.
Attack,
folks.
You're over in Chelsea.
Did you hear the explosion from your position?
Yes,
we did.
As a matter of fact,
we heard it,
And because I was just,
like,
standing there, pretty much looking out the window,
I didn't see what caused it or if there was an impact.
So you have no idea right now?
Oh,
there's another one.
Another plane just hit.
Oh!
Plane has just hit another building.
Flew right into the middle of it.
Explosion.
My god,
it's right in the middle of the building.
This one into the East tower?
Yes.
Right in the middle of the building.
Holy shit,
Martin.
That's the other building,
that's terrorists!
That's terrorists, bro!
That's fucking terrorists!
Holy shit!
That's terrorists, bro!
I zoomed out on it.
The building,
I cannot believe it.
Oh my
God!
Unbelievable!
The World Trade Center,
110 stories tall,
built in 1973.
As you look down at the World Trade Center buildings,
you see that it is one World Trade Center, that is the one where the impact was.
One World Trade Center is the one with the large television antenna on it,
and the restaurant windows on the world is in that tower.
The other one is the one with the observation deck.
Associated Press with a story that says there is no report of any casualties. Without jumping to too many conclusions, looking at the extent of this damage and knowing how well populated that building is at that time.
All right,
Paul,
we appreciate your call and stay hang loose,
though.
Hey,
Paul,
one quick question before you go,
Paul.
Have you been over near the scene to see anything that's gone on on the ground?
No,
I can only see the smoke and the flame,
well,
just basically the smoke in the air right now,
right in front of me.
We see two sides of the World Trade Center definitely affected by this crash.
Black smoke continuing to billow out there.
But I hear a lot of sirens going in.
Oh,
sure,
sure.
Again,
your estimation,
what type of plane did you report to?
Either an Airbus A320 style or a Boeing 737.
Okay.
Where do you get your knowledge from?
How much time do you have?
In a pilot's another, Oh no, okay, explosion and explosions, multiple explosions, ladies and gentlemen, we just saw another explosion. Uh, obviously, we're just watching it again. It's the first time this is, now, this is the other tower. Ladies and gentlemen. Another explosion at Tower number two of the World Trade Center just happened live on our air. I
wasn't gonna put in the time. How'd she kiss? By the way? Oh, it was fine, it was, it was a pack, it was nothing,
no tongue.
No,
it wasn't anything serious.
I take back my idiot.
Yeah,
it was nothing serious.
Believe me,
if I saw the glimmer of hope,
if I saw the second of any kind of opportunity,
I would seize it.
I never turn down that.
That sounds like a Ganges story,
though,
doesn't it?
It does,
but it's not.
You know what a good litmus test is?
When you kiss a girl,
and if she touches you,
when you kiss her,
you're gonna be together.
It was very playful.
April.
But if she doesn't touch you,
you get nothing.
That's how it works.
I know the difference when someone...
Was she sitting on your lap?
No.
At this time?
Where was she?
She couldn't sit on my lap.
Natalie was on my lap.
And she got a little jealous.
That's all.
And so she leaned over and started kissing.
She gave me a kiss.
There's
no doorway.
Let's go,
let's get the fuck out of
here.
Get the fuck out of here.
Bottom elevator,
there's a glass,
Flames exploded out the front of the World Trade Center.
Glass flew everywhere.
It's the
North Tower of New York's World Trade Center,
which we're looking at at the moment.
A blaze with thick smoke coming out of two sides of the building,
the result of a plane crash by what's thought to be a twin-engined jet plane,
possibly a 737.
The accident is reported to have taken place at 9 a.m.
Local time.
Us now on the phone from New York is Steve Evans, who was,
I believe,
in the building at the time.
Steve,
what can you tell us about what happened this morning?
People are running away very,
very quickly.
There are more explosions further down the building.
It was calm until we came on the air now,
but I'm now looking up at this building and there is...
Smoke billowing from the very top, but then there is a fire and an explosion about 20 stories further down.
I was at the base of the building when it happened. There was one huge bang and the building physically shook, then two or three bangs and
building again shook. And people came screaming past me.
At the moment, it looks as if both buildings are on fire.
Clearly, the thing is out of control.
As I say, there is smoke billowing out from further and further down the building and people are simply moving back.
They don't know what has happened.
Initially, the assumption was that it was a bomb.
People have been coming past me.
I was saying, no, it was an aircraft.
Which hit the building.
More than that,
I cannot say,
apart from to tell you that people here are very,
very frightened.
People are crying,
people are shaking.
They've stopped running away from the building.
They are now walking away.
There is moisture raining down from a clear sky.
I only presume that comes from the disaster which is going on above me as I speak.
I know I'm looking at them at what was the West Tower, and it looks like the fire on the north side of that top
is a little bit lower. But it looks like it's the same building. You're saying, it was the other tower that absorbed the second. It looks like, exactly from my perspective, I'm done King, our director. If I could ask you to widen out and give us a shot of both towers, because I can't I.
We can't tell from this vantage point.
Oh,
okay,
that is on the second tower.
It is on the East tower.
Teresa,
hang on with us one second.
We're going to re-rack the tape of when we were talking to you to see if we can tell.
We can't see anything.
We can't see a second plane in the picture.
There we see the explosion.
Yes.
It was definitely a plane that hit it.
The first that we had heard,
the impact only affecting Tower One,
But as our producers and reporting staff in the field is telling us,
you can see now to the left of your screen, there is fire in the second tower.
Just a little bit,
you can see right at the bottom of the
TV screen,
billowing smoke from a bomb or explosion.
We do not know if it's a bomb.
I'm speaking out of turn here.
A second explosion that just happened.
The first we understand was from an airplane.
The second, we have no idea.
No idea at all at this point what has triggered it.
I just crashed into Otherworld Trade Center.
Another Jumbo jet.
I'm so scared.
I'm leaving.
No,
don't,
Megan,
you can't.
I'm making myself up.
Megan.
Hit by the wing, the wing, the plane probably broke apart and went into the. Uh, it was going at 350 miles an hour. Jesus Christ,
and right now,
that, yes,
that was definitely look like it was on purpose.
You saw a plane?
Yes,
I just saw a plane go into the building.
Why do you?
Why do you say that was definitely on purpose?
Because it just flew straight into it.
It didn't look like it was a commercial jet.
It was a smaller plane.
It was definitely a smaller plane.
It just crashed right into it!
That was a crash,
that was a dead on kill!
He did it on purpose!
He did it on fucking purpose, man!
What the fuck is going on?
Lord!
If we could take maybe a wider shot, to give us just a different vantage point, just to try to gain a little bit of perspective. And there you can see the situation.
Unbelievable ladies and gentlemen.
We're in shock as much as you are.
It can't be.
You can't be put into words,
and clearly you are looking at it as we are seeing it, as it's developing.
We have no confirmation other than Associated Press reports and CNN, as well as our crews now that a plan is being made.
Tommy,
it sounds like we're talking to New York,
but there's another one aimed at the World Trade Center.
There's another aircraft?
The second one just hit the trade Center.
Okay.
Yeah,
we've got to alert the military real quick on this.
Do we know what type,
Terry?
No,
we just got that report from the Trade Center.
All right.
All right,
we're standing by.
That was on purpose!
That was no accident!
No,
no accident.
I think I got it on tape.
Shit!
I just got that,
that was sick.
I know, right?
Marine 6 to Manhattan,
urgent.
I'm at one stand by Marine 6,
go.
You have a second plane into the other kernel of the kernel of the Detroit Center,
north of Fire.
Call Fort David,
Marine 6. Advising a second plane into the World Trade Center,
okay.
3-6,
that's the other tunnel.
That's the second tower of the World Trade Center.
Take the elevator!
I don't want to be on the 32nd floor of this building anymore.
What happened?
Oh, god.
Oh,
I don't wanna.
They did this.
Oh my
God! Oh my God!
Oh my god!
What's happening?
Really?
I think it's all about the World Trade Center.
The first that we had heard,
the impact only affecting Tower One,
But as our producers and reporting staff in the field is telling us,
you can see now to the left of your screen, there is fire in the second tower.
Just a little bit,
you can see right at the bottom of the TV station.
TV screen,
billowing smoke from a bomb or explosion.
We do not know if it's a bomb.
I'm speaking out of turn here.
A second explosion that just happened.
The first we understand was from an airplane.
The second, we have no idea.
No idea at all at this point what has triggered it.
American 77, Indy.
Back off.
They're telling us to back off.
Come on,
Cameron,
Jesus.
Almighty,
that was the second plane that did that.
Did you see it just exploded?
It just disappeared.
I wonder how many people died on the ground.
Think about all that dead engine falling,
all these people dying.
This is awful.
Look at this,
I'm shaking.
Oh my god!
This is...
Oh man,
that's not right.
This is not right.
That's the second...
That's not right.
Thank you.
That...
Did you see that?
Are we dreaming or what?
Mike,
I'm going to take you there!
Light!
Oh my god!
Someone just...
Just jumped again. I just saw someone jump again. Oh my god. Oh my God. Oh my God. Oh
my God. That's terrorists, that's fucking terrorists, that's fucking terrorist.
Watch,
watch,
watch.
All units stand by on left side.
Manhattan Calling Call 4 David,
Ken.
Call 4 David.
Call 4 David,
Manhattan.
Alright,
B and 5,
you're reporting a check-in plane that crashed into the check-in plane.
B and 5 is on the 83rd floor,
room 8311,
we have people trapped,
83rd floor.
Call 4 David,
acknowledge.
10-4.
We have people trapped from 8 3, 1 1,
83rd floor.
Call for David acknowledge
Oh,
shit!
I drove the second towel.
Oh,
jeez.
Oh my
God.
Oh my god,
who is this?
Is it another airplane?
Okay,
I was watching CNN and then it looked like another airplane.
But it looks like the other,
now it's the other tower that's burning up.
It's the other building.
I think another airplane crashed into it.
I feel like we're under siege.
The other tower is now on fire,
the other World Trade Center.
It was like an airplane that crashed into the other one.
I don't know what to do now.
What are they saying?
It's like an air...
Another airplane flew into the second tower,
Kelly.
I feel like we're under siege.
I was watching CNN and there was another airplane in and there was an explosion.
My God,
now the other one's on fire.
I can see both buildings on fire.
Because we're under siege.
I think,
I don't know what's going on.
I don't know.
It's not leaving the tongue.
It was nothing.
Watch your monitor.
They're gonna play back.
There's just an explosion.
Oh,
let me see,
this is,
what happened, Tom,
what do you know?
I mean,
all I know is that apparently a plane,
I've heard Channel 2 describe it as a,
It looked like someone was driving,
a drunk driver, driving a car,
flew into the building.
Was it a terrorist attack?
Look at that!
It's unbelievable.
It's a huge hole!
It's going on at the World Trade Center,
and about,
there's an explosion that just happened.
It's even lower now,
the explosion.
Looks like a movie!
It is,
yeah, it does.
It looks like a movie special effect.
I'm telling you,
it's Pam Anderson's jet.
Oh, stop.
Finny,
what are you talking about?
I'm not trying to be making a...
This is not even a joke.
Wait,
hold on.
Is the other one catching fire now?
Gene Simmons is in the house.
What was the Gene Simmons thing?
Gene Simmons blew up the...
Wait a second,
let me see that again.
Pull that up again.
Is it in both buildings?
Does it look like...
Yeah,
it looks like the other buildings are in one.
Hey,
I'm not touched!
Be careful,
man.
You're normal.
You're not touched.
Yeah,
yeah.
Hey!
Did they say what was going on?
Dude,
it's going national,
it's just...
All over.
Come on,
man.
Holy fuck!
Is that a fucking dude?
I can't believe, I just saw that.
Did you record that?
I did,
I missed it.
I don't have no signal at all,
man.
No signals?
Go back in there.
Where?
Back in there.
A piece of tape,
and we may actually see another plane. Enter the picture here in a second.
I wonder if there are air traffic control problems.
Let's go back to Jennifer Oberstein,
who we were talking to a second ago.
Jennifer,
did you see this happen?
Hello?
Jennifer?
Did you just see this happen,
Matt,
I...
I've never seen anything,
it looks like a movie.
I saw a large plane,
like a jet,
go immediately headed directly into the World Trade Center.
It just flew into it,
into the other tower, coming from south to north.
I watched the plane fly into the world.
Trade CENTER.
It was a JET.
It was a very large PLANE.
It was going FAST.
It went past the Ritz Collins hotel that's being built
in Battery PARK.
It flew right past IT,
almost hit IT,
and then went IN.
This is so SHOCKING,
of COURSE,
to everybody WATCHING.
I've never seen anything like IT.
It literally blew itself
into the World Trade CENTER.
Obviously now we move from what appears to HAVE...
There it is, right THERE.
AGAIN,
I'm looking from south, from south to north, and it went into the
one on the right.
That appeared to be at least a 727.
We saw it a second ago.
Here it, here comes the videotape that we just showed you.
You will see what appears to be a large plane.
It could be a 727 right there,
maybe even bigger,
flying right into the side of the World Trade Center.
It was at least a 727.
It was a jet.
I couldn't believe my eyes watching it right above me.
And now you, you have to move from talk about a possible accident to talk about something deliberate.
All right.
You can't even get a touch of active ready anybody.
People
are running away.
This is the first time I've been there.
There's like millions of people jumping there.
What is this?
Oh my god,
I love this place.
This is it.
It's an awful place.
No,
no, Tammy,
this is,
I believe what we're seeing.
I could be wrong, because the first,
I think it's terrorists.
They will target the World Trade Center.
They have targeted the World Trade Center.
I'm going to get dressed.
If you're going to do a terrorist thing,
you pick not only that high-profile target,
but then you wait for people to congregate in areas.
That's where you strike again.
I don't think we're any safer now on the ground.
Were you on the air?
Yes,
I was on como TV.
This guy,
that guy's dead right over there.
He's stuck in there.
Yeah.
That's a pig,
it's not the same bird.
They're making a tripod.
That's terrorists.
Fucking hell.
It's coming.
Oh my god,
we just saw it happen.
Where's Bob?
Oh my god.
What are you doing?
I don't have a signal, though,
I should have a signal.
I understand we've re-established contact with Dick Oliver.
Dick is on the phone.
Yeah,
Dick.
Jim,
yes,
Just moments ago,
as you know,
another vehicle, or some kind of an aircraft, crashed into the World Trade Center.
This is no accident.
This is no bomb from inside.
This is,
as you put it,
a terrorist attack.
There's no two ways about it.
Tommy,
we're gonna stop everybody.
We're gonna shut Boston down.
I suggest we stand elsewhere.
You're gonna do what,
Terry?
We're shutting the airplanes down.
We're not letting anyone go right now.
Okay,
that's a good move.
We're waiting to hear from security.
Wait!
That's just...
He did that on purpose!
Did you see that?
He just flew right into it!
He flew right into it on purpose!
What is...
I don't know if I want to go to any public buildings to reveal my...
Are you going to run into the Statue of Liberty next,
or what?
That's why,
I don't want to look at that.
How many times did you watch outside?
Another one.
And you just saw the one hit the middle of it.
And we're like,
get the f*** out of here.
Here we are.
We're trying to re-rack the tape right now.
Teresa,
do you have a vantage point to the ground from where you are?
Uh,
yes,
I probably could go down.
No,
I'm not asking you to go down.
I'm asking if you can see it.
Oh,
no,
I cannot see the ground,
as a matter of fact.
There's too many buildings in the way.
I can probably see just up about,
I would say up a third of,
I can see the top two-thirds of the building.
And how much of that top two-thirds do you see?
Do you see flames?
Do you see damage?
I would say...
Middle of the second building and the top fourth of the first building.
Okay,
Teresa,
stay with us.
We're gonna look for that tape one more time.
We're gonna re-rack the tape here and see if we can't see a plane.
Yeah,
we see it right now.
We see a plane right now coming in and impacting on what would appear to be the north side of that tower,
of the westernmost tower,
And and hitting about
10 to 15.
Stories below.
Teresa,
let me ask you to hang on with us for a second while I talk with another gentleman who is an eyewitness.
Dick,
what vantage point are you at now?
I was still at Park Row.
People are streaming down,
heading away from the World Trade Center.
Having heard the second blast,
people are running,
some of them are running now.
Vehicles still heading towards the World Trade Center.
Now,
black smoke.
I don't know if you've got a picture.
We're trying to take some pictures here for you.
Black smoke coming out of the second explosion.
This explosion seems to have calmed down somewhat.
Oh my goodness.
Yes,
there's gray smoke coming out of it,
meaning that the water is being put on it.
People continue to stream past us here on Park Row,
as well as emergency vehicles.
Two planes just crashed.
Two big ones.
Come on,
man.
The phone is working.
There's an antenna at the top.
Good luck.
Don't put them in the car.
No,
perhaps we can get another look from one of our Sky cams that can take a different angle.
Yes,
you can tell that. It now appears that both buildings are suffering some kind of damage this morning.
My colleague...
Glenn Walker has just joined me here in the studio.
And,
Glenn,
I don't know if you received any other information,
but perhaps you can,
again,
go over what we do know at this point,
which is pretty much visual, and what eyewitnesses have told us.
Well,
I would hate to speculate,
but...
Yeah,
that looks like a completely separate incident right there.
I mean,
this building has been the subject of terrorist attacks in the past,
and I certainly wouldn't want to speculate at this time,
But that is a separate explosion.
Yes,
it is.
In the other building.
Now,
we have tried to get a hold of the Port Authority,
which manages the building.
We haven't been able to get an answer.
We did call MTA,
and the MTA says a subway service,
as of right now,
is continuing,
so that's not a problem, because it's obviously very below,
but I imagine that will change very quickly.
After what we just witnessed,
that was a dramatic explosion.
Again,
it was in the separate tower than the one where the plane just crashed into about a half hour ago.
Marine 6,
Come ahead.
go with your message.
Marine 6,
That plane was a large, bomber-style green aircraft into the second tower.
Good bye.
All right,
10-4.
This is 0178.
You know,
we'll be going out,
and then I'm going to have to go back.
People out of the building.
Ali Everhart is another witness who is on the ground.
Ali,
can you hear me?
Yes,
hello.
Please tell me what you're seeing.
Well,
I live in Lower Manhattan.
I face the North tower,
the north side, where the first plane crashed.
Into the building and right now, there's a lot of chaos on the ground, a lot of emergency vehicles. Everyone from the World Financial Center has exited and is walking north up to Battery Park North. There's just mass and mass of people
walking north uptown of Manhattan.
I happened to look on the first tower,
and I actually saw people waving where the first plane crashed through,
and then it was unbelievable seeing the second jet come crashing into the second tower.
What is going on?
I think an airplane just plowed into the city.
They did.
The World Trade Center.
No,
another one.
We just saw another one do it.
Another one?
Yeah.
Holy cow,
that's two and...
One just hit a little bit an hour ago.
Yeah,
one just a moment ago.
No shit.
You have a signal on your phone?
Yeah,
you getting signal?
it must be the main tower we have over there.
No signal,
right?
And we're going to check on the second flight.
If perhaps that had happened.
This all began at about 8.48 this morning.
Again,
what we know,
in case you're just joining us,
A small plane,
not a
Cessna type or five- or six-seater,
but instead, perhaps a passenger flight,
ran into the north side of the World Trade Center.
As you can see,
the second explosion that you're looking at now, in the second twin tower, has spread much debris,
much more to bring.
Than the first explosion of the first accident.
We've
lost signal.
This is Macy's
now, one of our producers said. Perhaps a second plane was involved. And let's not, let's not even speculate to that point, but at least put it out there that perhaps that may have happened.
The second explosion would certainly back the theory
from a couple of eyewitnesses that the plane fuselage perhaps stayed in those upper buildings.
93,
Can you guys see the city from behind you there?
Not anymore.
Okay.
It looks like the,
uh,
the whole train set is on fire.
Yes,
it's the Boeing 757 we think just flew into the air,
into the building.
Are you,
you're not kidding,
right?
No,
I'm not kidding.
Oh,
shit.
Yes, sir,
Cactus 193,
climb and maintain flight level 280.
Flight level 280,
pardon me,
I'm just about 280,
Cactus,
whoever I am,
193.
Cactus 193,
roger.
Alright,
we are going to re-rack the tape and show you what happened just moments ago,
and that was an explosion in the second of the twin
Towers. And we're going to
watch it for ourselves.
Yes.
It appeared as though a second plane coming from behind crashed into the second of the World Trade Center towers.
A first plane happened about
15 minutes ago,
struck one of the towers in the upper floors.
A horrible tragedy. And now, just moments ago, another plane has struck the Twin Towers.
Of course, the target of previous terrorist attacks.
That possibility leaps to the mind again.
We got to get off it.
Keep going,
all right?
Keep going.
Manhattan calling Carport,
David.
Three Adams to Manhattan.
Three Adams,
guys.
Yeah,
I'll do the FDR drive.
Definitely something hit the second tower.
Unfortunately,
two-thirds of the way up,
you got visual fire showing out there.
Suggest to the incident commander,
Fort David,
to transmit a fifth alarm to Tower two.
President Bennett Act today.
You know what I'm saying, Steve?
I don't know, man.
Marines,
whatever.
Let's go.
An ambulance,
a fire vehicle,
and a police vehicle.
My goodness,
Ali,
if
I can only begin to imagine the carnage that has taken place.
We see an ember falling from the top floor of the Empire State Building.
It's tough to look at,
but let's look at it once again.
After a plane crashed into the side of the World Trade Center,
then another one,
as our cameras were focused on the building,
crashed into the other tower.
Jim is now a very serious fire on the South Tower of the World Trade Center.
This is about,
I would estimate,
about the
60th, or perhaps the 70th floor of the tower,
right on the corner.
Northeast corner of the South tower,
flames shooting out of the building.
Listen to CBS News on 1210.
They think it was a small twin.
I hope so.
We had several aircraft identified as the 757.
Unbelievable.
Is this a departure or an arrival?
We don't know.
We think it was a hijack.
We were waiting number one and waiting for takeoff,
and I don't even remember 7-5 taking off.
We don't know where he came from,
sir.
Actually,
we're really not certain.
Tucker 580,
Tucker,
contact the...
New York Center 134.32, 134.32,
Good day sir,
back up IRE.
It was leaking.
It was leaking?
Alright,
tell me what you saw.
Hang on.
Tell me closely and loudly so I can hear.
I was right,
I was right near the right,
right near the bottom.
What happened?
What did you see?
The fire department came in and they said,
why the airplane is leaking?
And everybody looking.
Up all of a sudden. He was going to hit the AT&T building, he went straight to the World Trade Center. It looked like he aimed it for the towers. Yeah, it was a small airplane.
I'm calling Division 1K.
Division 1K.
Division 1,
be advised.
Ray Adam reports that you have a check-in plane that cramped into the check-in tower.
About two-thirds...
The way up, you recommend you transmit a fifth alarm for that trial as well. All right, 10-4. Uncle, what's in his point?
Don't put me on hold!
I'm at the World Trade Center.
Yes,
it is.
Tammy,
watch this.
They're showing the plane hit.
Honey,
I'm...
Where?
Because of Israel!
General area of where the first one was,
but a bit farther down.
I want to say maybe about
20 to possibly 25 stories down,
and this would be on the northeast corner from what we can see of Tower
No. 1.
We now have both of the towers of the World Trade Center at this point in flames.
And you know, there are some transmitters,
of course,
on top of one of those buildings,
and that is affecting some of our broadcast friends right now.
Some of the TV stations are off the air at this point,
so we will try to describe what we have for you.
We're interrupting Channel 4.
Maria Bartiromo.
Was in the area you all saw if you were watching the second explosion, Maria was in the area. And says, In fact, a second airplane hit the other tower. Which would indicate that what you have is is. This is certainly
strong evidence of some kind of s****** attack on the buildings. But Maria Bartiromo was in the neighborhood, looking up and says she saw a...
Second plane fly into the side of the second tower.
So,
I'm almost lost for words.
I've never seen anything like this and I've been doing this for many decades.
This World Trade Center complex, as it is known,
they are twin, known as LEGO type block towers.
They are 110 stories.
They rise 1,377 feet into the air.
They are one of the defining...
Characteristics of the New York City skyline seen from anywhere.
And there you see the second plane in the Second tower going through,
and there is the explosion into the World Trade Center of New York City.
This, obviously,
if it is some sort of terrorist attack,
would not be the first.
February 26,
1993, was the day that the World Trade Center was bombed.
A violent explosion ripping through the parking garage on that day in the sub-basement levels of the World Trade Center.
Immediately, it killed six people and it caused extensive damage in several basement levels.
Resulted
in a massive fire that quickly distributed thick black smoke in the upper levels of the complex's buildings.
It was just a rumor.
Somebody just called and said that on CNN,
a second plane just crashed into one of the buildings.
Stop it!
A second plane.
Wait a minute!
They are two buildings,
and that is lower!
So it's a terrorist attack,
isn't it?
No,
that's what they're saying.
It's got to be.
Somebody just called in with that.
Oh, my goodness!
A second plane might have crashed,
and a second building is on fire.
Why does everyone go to the World Trade Center?
What are they?
What do they do there?
It's a big target.
Landmark in New York?
It's the biggest landmark in New York,
really,
isn't it?
Yeah.
It's the tallest.
Oh,
my God.
And it's a place where people can be killed.
Like,
you can't take down the
Statue of Liberty.
Nobody's going to be killed there.
Everybody's in.
Go support two to Manhattan.
Go support two,
go ahead.
Send me a ticket entering the tunnel.
All right,
count four.
They think it was two like s****** bombers.
...Carver,
Manhattan.
...field,
Tom,
go ahead,
check.
And we're 284 this box.
Do us a favor,
please,
recall. Our boss is downtown and having security in MCC,
and we're located at Broadway and Main Lane,
at Broadway and Main Lane.
Have him report to MCC.
We do need help here.
Alright,
do you want,
what is that location,
Kay?
Unfortunately, at this point,
Michael,
it would be very difficult to make that activity.
Oh my
God, who's up here with
Kate? Where she saw it?
One of those guys.
I imagine she saw the second one go right in there.
Look at that,
that's unbelievable.
Don't let me see the smoke clear out,
man.
You're gonna see like the whole...
See through the building?
Yeah,
you're gonna see right through the building.
I think it was like this.
See, this is the building like this?
It went like this.
It went through like that.
It didn't go through the whole building.
Cause you could see the whole room.
No,
no,
no.
Like a diagonal.
It's on a diagonal like this.
Do it.
That is so crazy.
So many people,
man.
From that floor up,
Good morning,
Pat.
I'm sorry,
I'm a little shaky.
This is simply the worst thing I've ever seen in my entire life.
I am at the Millennium Hotel, on the
35th floor,
directly across the street from both Twin Towers and the World Trade Center.
Out from my window,
the view I have is of the World Trade Center.
No,
I'm across the street,
so I have seen the whole,
I saw when the building started exploding and the debris started flying, and I could see parts of what looked like to me a plane. And as it was exploding, I was afraid at our window,
the debris was hitting against our window,
I was afraid that part of it was going to break through,
it was on fire.
Yes,
I was.
And the entire building shook.
And
I'm from California.
I thought,
earthquake.
I look up and the window is completely filled with flames and debris that is falling.
And as we've been standing here,
we've watched the second building get hit with another plane.
Tommy,
Jerry,
it's confirmed on that campus that we have planes.
Steve Evans,
thank you for joining us from the World Trade Center.
So clearly chaos there.
The explosions still continuing.
At the moment, it's not really clear whether there was a plane crash or exactly what went on,
Jim.
Well,
we are getting reports that a twin-engined jet liner was the aircraft involved.
That hasn't been confirmed.
That is coming from an eyewitness.
In terms of the,
we are seeing both,
it seems that both towers are affected by this.
It could be that the aircraft went through one,
right through,
and the debris has affected the other tower as well.
Oh,
come on,
Cameron.
Jesus.
So you think it was two planes?
They're not sure.
They don't know.
But if it was one of those size planes,
those are huge jets.
Oh,
whoa!
This is crazy!
We've got planes going into buildings!
We're under attack.
That's cr- Oh my god.
It's war.
Come on.
Alright,
we gotta go- this is Pearl Harbor.
We gotta go bomb everything over there now.
We gotta bomb the hell out of it.
Of them, you know who it is, I can't say, but I know who it is. I mean, that's crazy. This is more upsetting than me not getting Pam Anderson. What is that, Tom? there? it is, there it is. Yep, I see it. Yeah, yeah, what are you saying, Tom? I've never seen anything like
me, neither.
Nobody's ever seen anything like that.
Oh,
my God.
On Broadway and Maiden,
it's Dwayne.
Just to have the MCC and have our personnel be secure here at this location.
The MCC,
sir?
And I'm requesting at the disloved location.
You got two buildings on fire here.
This is Henderson,
American, 77.
Do you guys have radar on him?
Is he over Falmouth?
No,
we just moved the track there.
We never,
you know...
Alright,
you just have the track out there?
You guys never been able to raise him at all?
No,
we called company.
They can't even get a hold of him.
So there's no,
no radar.
No radio communications and no radar.
And his last clearance,
as far as you know,
was on course to Falmouth and then J134,
right?
Well,
we're just going to treat him like non-radar,
and we've already told the next sector they're going to have to sterilize for him until we find out.
Okay.
Thanks.
Bye.
Does
this scare you?
Yes,
yes, it does scare me.
We're totally too lax in this country.
Trying to tell you.
Tell me if you're ready.
Oh,
it's just awful.
I mean,
both trade towers.
Richard Davis.
Mr.
Davis,
good morning.
Good morning.
This is Bryant Gumbel.
Yes,
sir.
I'm at 59th and 5th.
Where are you?
I'm at
50th and
5th, but I'm facing south on the
39th floor.
You're facing south.
A clear vantage point.
Yes.
Talk to me about what you see, if you could.
The first plane looked like a 737.
It flew right up the middle of Manhattan.
It was clearly too low.
I noticed that by the time it was passing the Empire State Building,
it was about to hit the ground.
Building and noticed that it was too low.
There appeared to be absolutely nothing wrong with the plane and then it very deliberately flew into the side of the
World Trade Center.
Why do you say very deliberately?
Because the pilot aimed right for the building and there was nothing wrong with the plane.
The plane did not appear to be in any trouble whatsoever?
None whatsoever.
And we're talking about a commercial aircraft,
a 737?
It appeared to be at 737.
I can't...
Absolutely.
No,
obviously,
I'm not asking you to be an aviation expert,
but clearly, what you saw,
or what you say you saw,
was not a small aircraft.
It was not a small aircraft.
It was a small commercial aircraft,
like a small Airbus or a 737
Boeing. And that was the first plane?
Two-inch jet.
You,
if you were watching,
you saw a tremendous second explosion on the
South Tower.
And Mark,
I want to remind you,
this is consistent with what eyewitnesses are telling our NBC affiliate, WNBC,
which is that the plane was flying no...
Very low.
They noticed that because of that fact. And that it looked like it was headed straight for the World
Trade Center,
that it didn't appear as though nothing,
that anything was wrong with the plane necessarily,
that it was experiencing any trouble,
but that it was in fact headed for the World Trade Center.
World Trade Center.
I know.
Who would have thought that there would be two of them?
And apparently there were two of them.
And you can see the enormous amount of damage.
You know,
that may explain the spread of the damages,
not because the planes were big,
but they were loaded as bombs.
Loaded.
Mark,
I want to quickly mention,
I'm hearing from our producer that the New York Stock Exchange is being evacuated.
This might be some obvious news here.
The offices in the area.
This is an enormous disaster.
Division 3 to Manhattan.
Go ahead,
go with your message.
Division 3 to Manhattan.
Division 3,
go with your message.
Are we being assigned to any of these boxes down at the World Trade Center?
Department of Division 3,
continue it.
Dr.
J,
We're going to take a look.
Look at videotape just moments ago of the second plane hitting the World Trade Center.
That is spectacular pictures.
I don't know if you could see the plane,
and that too was a passenger plane,
if perhaps some type of navigating system or some type of electronics would have put two planes into the World Trade Center? within,
it looks like,
about 18 minutes of each other.
Olly,
can you hear me?
I hear you,
Jim.
Dave brought up the point that the mayor's emergency management office,
the so-called bunker,
is in one of the towers of the World Trade Center,
but I don't believe it's one of the two top ones.
No,
it's not.
It's about the 30th floor.
It is not up there.
And by the way,
for those who are wondering about the structure...
Not up there.
And by the way,
for those who are wondering about the structure...
.？appear. To be structurally sound and not always small pieces of debris circulating in the air around it where the explosions occurred.
The buildings themselves seem to be in...
Intact as far as their structure is concerned.
There's been talk over the years about the threat of terrorism,
making the buildings fall down onto the streets.
But I can reassure everybody that we're going to be able to get through this.
Everybody that they seem to be holding up fairly well while efforts are going forward to fight the fires and whatever happened in those two towers.
George Shea right now, who has also witnessed both or one of these collisions.
George,
can you hear us?
I can hear you.
What did you see,
George?
Well,
I was in a car to scare...
And have you seen anyone injured on the ground,
George?
A man next to me was actually hit by a tree and they...
Did you see, George, the second plane,
that jet,
fly into the other twin Towers?
No shit,
no shit!
10-4,
Divisions, Freedom at hand,
Call the car. 4. David, who's on the scene,
Do they want to institute a recall due to the incident?
I'm calling Car 4 David.
It must be a very busy scene, Steve,
are there a lot of people there?
Well, there are a lot of people,
the man whose phone it is is asking me,
he's evacuating the shop and I have to get off, I'm afraid, because he wants his phone back. And we have to leave.
I'll stay with it here.
There are people who are very,
very frightened.
Clearly,
this is a very high,
it is one of the tallest buildings in the world.
There is an uncontrollable event involving explosions and fire going on above us.
People simply don't know what's happening.
An awful lot of people are just getting as far away as they possibly can.
On Wall Street right now,
John Bussey of the Wall Street Journal is in the area.
Let's go to John and find out what he knows.
John,
can you hear me?
Yeah,
Mark,
I'm here.
What do you know,
John?
Mark,
I'm on this side of the building, that's on the south side.
I am looking up at the buildings from just across the street.
It is an extraordinary scene.
The top several floors,
as you can see,
are aflame and smoke is coming up.
The second explosion just happened.
I did not see what Maria saw because I'm probably on the back side of the building.
However,
the hole came through the back side.
There are gaping holes in the World Trade Center.
Papers flying down.
John,
let me interrupt you.
Terry,
go ahead.
Is there a way to try to get messages to the airborne aircraft to increase security for the cockpit or something,
VA cars or something?
I just do not have anybody else up there that can.
We've got internationals that are coming to Kennedy,
and we're trying to talk to them,
but we don't want to scare anybody,
But we want the,
you know,
we were talking about possibly making some transmissions on frequencies for these guys coming overseas to just,
increase...
Security for cockpit operations.
Yeah,
Terry,
we're getting a lot of traffic on this bridge.
I copied that.
Let's keep doing that.
Contact the Command center,
the ATA rep.
See if we can get the airline company operations to contact their aircraft.
I'd recommend maybe possibility of the stuff coming in from overseas,
Bangor as an alternate site,
but leave that up to them.
We'll leave it up to them,
but we're also going to let them know to increase security for cockpit access.
All right.
Alright,
that sounds like a good plan.
Sean,
it's me.
I just wanted to let you know I love you and I'm stuck in this building in New York.
I just want some milk and we just wanted you to know that I love you always.
I'm not going to call Fort David.
Shit!
Okay,
Foxy,
this is what I foresee that we probably need to do.
We need to talk to the FAA.
We need to tell them,
if this stuff's going to keep on going,
we need to take those fighters,
put them over. Manhattan,
okay?
That's the best thing.
That's the best play right now.
So coordinate with the FAA.
Tell them,
if there's more out there,
which we don't know,
let's get them over Manhattan.
At least we've got some kind of play.
Jim Fish is here with me in the studio.
It's interesting that we're not seeing any rescue helicopters at the moment,
isn't it,
Jim?
Yes.
Now,
we can only assume that there are emergency operations going on inside those towers as we speak.
Of course,
they were built to rigorous safety specifications.
They will have systems which can enable them to reach...
An accident,
a disaster of this kind,
very high up.
These were the world's tallest buildings when they were constructed.
They are no longer,
but they are among the world's tallest.
So there will be systems in place there,
emergency backup systems.
Even if the lifts are not working,
there will be mechanical ways in which they can at least try to approach the scene of the accident.
But it is surprising at the moment that there are no helicopters around.
Flying around there,
possibly trying to get out the seat of the accident.
Division 3 to Manhattan.
Division 3,
yeah.
Could you give me the box that I'm being assigned to,
okay?
My wife,
my wife,
all over the country.
I'll tell you something,
people will swipe me,
get the hell out of the city.
What's the time doing?
Yeah,
it's running out of work,
so we gotta.
It's gonna shut down a little bit.
Delta 9900,
Can you see Manhattan?
Yes,
sir.
Can you see anything unusual?
We took off,
they said. A plane rammed in the South tower.
It looks to be about maybe 200 feet high and there's belching smoke all the way around.
Okay,
thank you, sir.
I'm going to the city wide.
I'm going to Manhattan.
All right,
two big people.
You're going to two World Trade Center.
Box is 9-9-9-8.
Okay.
Version 3,
Stand 4.
We've had all aircraft operations in and around this area of Lower Manhattan suspended entirely.
LaGuardia Airport has said there are two confirmed aircraft into the World Trade Center and they want no one at all in this area.
They are,
in effect,
if you can possibly picture this,
cordoning off the entire area around the
World Trade Center and around Manhattan, from at least midtown on south.
So we will be looking at this from a far distance and describing from what we can see.
What we could see,
at least from the opposite side of the Hudson River,
We don't know what sort of restrictions will be placed upon any aircraft in addition to this,
but LaGuardia Airport confirming two aircraft into the World Trade Center,
one into each tower.
So they have requested that all aircraft leave the area immediately,
so we are complying with that.
Division 1 to
Manhattan Units call Manhattan One at a time,
K Division 1 to Manhattan One engine,
Go Division 1 to Manhattan,
All incoming units to World 1 and World 2 Trade Center are to bring additional cylinders. So many,
I feel like we're under siege or something and I don't know where to go or what to do.
I got the patience.
Harman,
that means you both of them just burning up.
I'm not going to be surprised.
I think it's not going to be that bad.
I have him here,
I will open it.
No,
no,
but he had to go through that house.
Got
some kills, dude.
Okay,
this is where I got going.
Tell Foxy to scramble Langley,
send him in same location.
Battle stations or scramble?
Battle stations only,
Langley.
Okay,
this is who's up there?
Langley.
Okay,
you're listening?
Well,
I told the FD so far,
we need to get those fighters screwed over Manhattan because we don't know how many guys are out of bar.
Could this be two?
Could it be more?
I don't know.
Just in case.
Not down in whiskey. 105 where they want FAA wants to hold.
We need to be more careful.
And stick them,
you know,
we're going to stick them.
We're working.
Yeah,
Victor.
Okay.
That is quick.
Two,
five,
two,
six on battle.
Yeah,
well,
we can't.
They're in the FFA airspace.
Well,
we can.
Langley.
Yeah,
they're ours.
Okay.
We have Maria on the phone.
Maria,
tell us what you saw.
Yes.
Hi,
Mark.
You saw the plane going right into it.
I'm standing right on Broadway, looking up.
To both towers.
They are on fire at the top of it.
I'm seeing what you're seeing,
obviously,
what is on air.
There is debris coming from the building,
and
I'm not sure what it is,
but it's clearly that there was a plane that went right into one of the towers,
a second plane.
One doesn't want to speculate too much,
but again,
On Friday, the State Department released a worldwide caution about extremist groups, and it said
American citizens may be the target of a terrorist threat from extremists.
Extremist groups with links to Osama bin Laden.
In the past,
such individuals have not distinguished between official and civilian targets.
As always,
we are taking this information seriously.
U.S.
Government facilities worldwide...
Remain at a heightened state of alert.
Now,
you'll remember that when the World Trade Center explosion happened back in 1993,
this was linked to
Osama bin Laden's terrorist network.
Alright,
Engine one,
repeat that,
you are totally unreasonable.
Division One to Manhattan,
all respond units responding into number one and number two World Trade Center are supreme. additional,
Skytel is with them.
Alright,
all units stand by, unless urgent and follow up Manhattan.
All units responding in to Number One World Trade Center and Number Two World Trade Center,
bring all additional STBA bottles to the front of the building.
All units responding to boxes 8087 and 99 and 98,
number one and number two World Trade Center,
Bring your extra STBA bottles to the front of the building.
SCBA files to the front of the building.
Ask for the division.
That can't be it.
Is it?
Yeah.
It is.
I can't see it.
It's on top of the building.
Look at the size of those flames.
Look at the size of the flames,
you know.
I'm
here right now with a bystander who actually watched the plane go in.
Tell us exactly what you saw.
I just saw out of nowhere the plane came in, crashed right into the train center and went right through and just full speed, didn't stop. Just right through the whole center, right through the whole building, and that was the second plane that actually went into the second tower. What I'm looking at
right now,
it's the top of the towers on fire,
debris falling.
The Broadway,
obviously,
is filled with watchers.
And then when the plane crashed into the second tower,
it was a large explosion,
a very loud explosion.
And everyone really ran,
ran for their lives, because it was quite loud and quite smoky.
Are you from the news channel?
11.
What channel?
11 So the second one going off.
Other units call on Manhattan.
This is for the Manhattan gang.
All bravo gang.
Hasfield, Com report to bring a vehicle in front of the American Express building on West Street by orders of Chief Ingram.
This side,
this side.
National Financial.
Hey,
Batch,
are you on stack?
On L-6,
95.
Do you want me to come in?
There's
flames that's coming down.
The FIRE.
The fire was so HARD,
it was like a fire trashing down to the ground on the west SIDE.
All the cars were running into each other
and the flames just started coming down
real HARD.
Then another sound exploded AGAIN.
What building are
you IN?
I'm in the C-TOWER.
I'm in the
C-TOWER. I'm in the C-TOWER.
I'm in the C-TOWER.
The FIRE.
The fire is on the GROUND.
Do you see people on the ground
from the TWO?
YES,
the FIRE,
the fire BRIGADE,
they CAME,
everything ELSE,
they're downstairs there right NOW.
I'm not going to be able to see ANYTHING.
I'm going to be able to see EVERYTHING.
I'm going to be
able to see EVERYTHING.
I'm going to be able to see EVERYTHING.
I'm going to be able to see, thank you.
The shaking,
the violent shaking and the exploding,
it was both.
Everything in the room was shaking.
The entire,
we're up in an upper floor,
the entire hotel was moving.
Yes,
I am.
And Kat,
I just want to mention,
if people do anything,
say prayers for the people that are in the buildings.
Because people are falling to their deaths,
jumping from the flames in the buildings.
Yes,
right in front of me.
Babe,
are you there?
It's okay,
it's okay.
Yeah,
they're attacking the World Trade Center,
not us.
Where did it come in from?
From the south.
From the south?
Yeah.
The same building it went to?
It was right there,
it just,
it looked like it was going to come back.
It was a huge plane.
What did it fly into?
Babe,
they're going to show it to you,
I'm here.
I hope nobody will turn off the camera.
I will go to the side.
It has big holes in the building.
We're going to stop everybody.
We're going to shut Boston down.
I suggest we stay elsewhere.
You're going to do what?
We're shutting the airplanes down.
We're not letting anyone go right now.
That's a good move.
We're going to stop on everything.
There's a second plane that just hit the World Trade Center.
Stop all departures out of the center,
please.
That's what we're doing.
A witness who has called in to speak to us,
his name is Kareem Haroki.
Mr.
Haroki,
Did you...
As I understand,
they're telling me in my ear,
is it true that you witnessed the first plane hit the tower?
Yeah.
Could you give me some sort of a description of it?
I was sitting in my car here in Greenwich,
you know.
I just saw the plane coming down from the left side and going straight to the building,
you know,
and going inside.
It actually went inside the building.
Excuse me?
It flew right into the building.
I saw it coming from the left.
And I saw the plane come on through to the building, I go inside. It's small plane. you say, small plane. Was it a jet? Was it a jet plane? No, no, it was playing, you know? Like they teach the people for the plane is like a small plane, you know, it's that kind of plane. You mean, like, a, uh, a small single or double engine. Uh,
yeah,
all right.
My hand is cold.
Feel calm.
You got it.
Thank you.
L-2431,
We have a message for you to heighten your cockpit security due to some activity this morning.
Oh,
and that is from a company?
Negative.
It's a general advisory to all aircraft.
This morning, an aircraft hit the World Trade Center and has been hijacked.
And we're receiving reports that there may have been a second one.
Okay,
thank you very much.
Was it a domestic carrier that was hijacked?
It was an American Airlines aircraft.
Okay,
thank you.
We have no word at the moment of fatalities,
But they are very,
very busy office blocks,
and it all happened in the morning at a very busy time.
Seeing those pictures,
I think one would have to ask,
one,
accident is extraordinary in itself,
but two,
if that is a second aircraft striking the towers,
one would have to ask the question whether this is deliberate sabotage.
Thank you.
I hear a lot of sirens out on the street right now.
You could,
one thing that you can see in the windows is all of the emergency system lights.
That was one thing we could see,
all of them were blinking off and on in the First Tower when that happened.
And I can't see them anymore.
The second tower,
I cannot see any emergency lights in the building blinking.
All right,
I'm going to thank you both right there.
4 truck to Manhattan,
K.
4 truck ahead.
Right 131 to Manhattan.
131 standby,
4 truck ahead.
Tower,
would you like us to respond in to the tower?
Order Tower 2,
K.
Giant killer.
Giant Killer's off.
This is huntress placing Quit 2526 on battle stations.
Time 1310.
Authenticate
Charlie Victor.
That is quit 2526 on battle stations.
All parties acknowledge with initial command post.
Langley Tower.
I have a command post.
OTC say again.
No,
the female.
Who is that?
There's an ethical place.
Needed.
Now you can clear to drop.
Giant clear to clear to drop.
And then, at about 9-0-3,
a second plane.
Do we have that tape to roll showing the second plane hitting the second tower?
Let's take a look.
There you see it.
And as witnesses have described,
this would seem to be very...
Very deliberate.
They described the first plane going into the first of the towers as having to bank and make a turn directly in.
But,
Lark,
as you look at that video,
it appears the plane flew directly in.
Unmistakable.
Right.
And here we're going to show it to you one more time.
You can see the plane slamming into that second...
Tower THERE.
Go to 2 Well STREET.
4 Truck 10-4.
131 GUY.
Rider 131.
We have
another WITNESS,
Janice Huff, on the TELEPHONE.
I'm not sure if it's our Janice HUFF,
but she apparently was a witness
to the second EXPLOSION.
You saw THIS?
Where are YOU?
NO,
NO.
LISTEN,
I'm watching TV right NOW.
YES.
AND,
you KNOW,
I can see the pictures that we have of the BUILDING,
the first BUILDING,
the one with the tower on the...
The TOWER.
I was looking at the tower and I saw a plane flying on the TOP.
As I'm watching it and you're TALKING,
I see a plane
flying behind the other TOWER.
I see it getting closer and closer to the building and I'm thinking, is that a PLANE?
It WAS.
All of a sudden, I see this explosion in the other TOWER.
So there was another PLANE.
So there was another plane with a second EXPLOSION.
From what I am
looking at on TELEVISION,
from the angle that I was LOOKING.
Here's a replay, right?
I noticed that there was a small plane coming around the side of the building.
You see it there on the right?
I see it.
I do see it right there.
There it is, right there.
I see it.
And then it goes,
boom,
right there.
Watch.
There it is.
You're absolutely right.
Oh,
my goodness.
So I don't know if it's a helicopter or a plane,
but it was certainly flying,
and it went right into the building.
It was a plane.
Can we show that again,
please?
I clearly did not notice that the first time.
Right.
I think we need to take a look at that again.
Maria,
David Faber wants to ask you a question.
I'd spoken to somebody in the first tower.
It appeared both had been evacuated prior to that second airplane hitting.
Is that your understanding?
I'm not sure,
David.
I know that there was an evacuation call in both towers.
I don't know that. Both buildings were evacuated.
I can't confirm that from where I'm standing,
which is right on Broadway and Wall Street,
watching the towers on fire.
And is that entire area now being cordoned off where you are?
I would assume it's filled with emergency vehicles.
Well,
I mean,
there's still a bit of a disarray going on.
To be honest,
I mean,
the fire trucks are coming.
People are still standing around.
Maria.
Other unit,
call them ahead.
I want to look at that.
We'll add a little more gas.
Which tower are we responding to?
You're going to 2-0-J-7-K-2.
Boston,
Good morning,
U.S. 1168,
checking in 280.
Boston Center,
Good morning,
do you copy advisory to heighten your cockpit security,
cockpit awareness?
Negative,
sir,
see you again.
U.S. 1168,
all FAA facilities revising all air carriers to heighten their cockpit awareness.
There has been at least one hijack this morning and possibly two.
Okay,
you're set to level.
60 At Roger,
we copy.
And just confirm that was an airliner that crashed into the World Trade Center?
That's what we understand.
Possibility of two.
Okay,
thank you, sir.
Good morning.
It's here 20-47,
have you copied this?
Yes, sir,
we did,
thank you.
Boston Center,
good morning.
Southwest 10-29,
I'm on level 320,
climbing to 350,
We copy all the reports.
Southwest 10-29,
I check.
Unbelievable video here.
John?
Yeah,
Mark,
I'm actually right outside of the World Trade Center, in a building across the street where the Wall Street Journal is located.
And we're looking right down onto the street as the fire engines arrive.
These holes in the building are what you expect would happen.
I mean,
there's furniture that rained down,
papers everywhere.
Pieces of the building are still smoking,
a flame falling from the building onto parking lots nearby.
There are cars on fire around the base of the building.
It looks like a ticker tape parade went through here,
ironically.
There's just papers everywhere.
I do not see large crowds coming out of the buildings yet.
Some of these exits have been blocked off,
apparently.
At least near the Marriott Hotel,
and I could see people leaving over a traverse from the World Trade Center building,
but not large crowds out on the street.
Partly,
Mark,
because when this happened,
I was outside, on the other side of our building.
I did not see it other than the effect.
Material went blasting out from the buildings, at least a block or two.
I could hear something come in to the building.
It was like a jet engine or an aircraft engine of some sort,
it sounded like.
And then just a massive explosion and pieces of the building falling.
You gotta go out.
Grab your guy and get him out.
Don't tell me this.
I don't care.
Get out.
What's your batch number?
Don't worry about it.
Go turn around.
44.
Who is that guy?
Get that guy out.
Where is he going?
I understand.
All right.
Tell your guy to go back where he's supposed to be at.
I'm going to show him.
I'm bringing all your activities up when you can.
Time for it.
Yes,
Islamic militants were responsible for a large bomb explosion at the World Trade Center a few years ago.
And of course, it's too early to tell at the moment,
But it certainly raises the question,
with two plane crashes into the World Trade Center at such a busy time,
whether, in fact, this is a deliberate event and not an accident.
So we have two crashes.
Here's a different angle of the same plane.
You see it off there on the left.
Boring.
Yeah.
Boring into there.
But again,
at this point,
it is restricted airspace.
It is a clear day.
So the suspicions are high that these are intentional acts.
But the FBI, at this point, is still trying to confirm that these are intentional acts.
In fact,
we've got some tape replay of that.
Do we have the tape available right now?
Here's the tape.
You see the plane coming in from what looks like the east side.
And it blows into the building, with the flames and the smoke billowing out.
The other side of the tower.
It's hard for me to tell exactly which is the north side and which is the south side,
but it appears it's coming out of the north side there.
Incredible pictures.
These happened just moments ago.
Squad Company 2,
Engine 2,
coming through the head of the tower.
At one unit at a time.
2-1-1.
Was Joseph going back inside or what?
I don't know.
Was he sure when the plane arrived?
Uh,
yes,
he was sure.
Second plane flying to the Golden.
Stay close.
Alright,
this is Henderson.
Okay.
There was an American 11,
departed off of
New York,
going to LA,
got hijacked.
Bobcat,
Moorefield 90.
77 departed off the Dulles,
is going to LA.
Dispatch doesn't know where he's at.
And confirmed that two airplanes have been,
uh,
they crashed into,
the World Trade Center in New York.
As far as American 11,
we don't know where he is,
but they say that
American 11 was hijacked off of a New York airport going to LAX.
So we don't have a track on him?
I mean,
like,
they just took off without a clearance.
No,
you mean American? 11?
Yeah.
Well,
I'm guessing,
dude,
because he was going to LA.
But nobody ever tracked American 11 is what I'm asking.
I don't know that.
I don't know where he left from.
There's no flight plan in the machine right now?
Yeah,
I just looked at that,
too.
As far as what we know,
that's all we know.
I talked to dispatch and that's what they relayed.
And they confirmed it here that
I guess two airplanes about crashed into the trade center.
All right.
And I believe we have someone with us on the line.
Ira Ferber?
We have Ira Ferber,
a former NTSB spokesman.
And you're watching these pictures as well with us,
are you not?
Yeah,
I'm with you on CNN.
What can you make of what we have seen?
Particularly with this replay we just saw moments ago.
That's absolutely inexplicable.
There shouldn't be any aircraft in that area,
much less something heading what looked like, deliberately, for the World Trade Center tower.
You don't think there's any way this could happen?
Could be any kind of an accident,
no kind of a navigational equipment failure, or some sort of a navigational quirk by beacons, or whatever?
No,
you've got incredibly good visibility at this point. And no pilot is going to be relying on navigational equipment in such a circumstance. That would cause them to crash into the World Trade Center.
Squad 252 to Manhattan K,
We have our second piece responding to the...
When you get there,
bring up all your extra STBA bottles,
okay?
Okay.
He's going to be in there.
.when? We're holding a primary election in New York City.
Now,
I would imagine...
Jim,
what you're saying could be a drone aircraft.
That's an aircraft that's guided electronically to its target without having a pilot.
Now,
that is a possibility as well.
In the meantime,
I can tell you that blades are shooting out of both towers now,
the heaviest being on the South tower,
the northeast corner of the South tower of the World Trade Center.
But there's a considerable blaze going on on the North Tower as well.
The
American 693-350.
What trade center?
World Trade
Center.
This is Henderson,
go ahead.
Yeah,
10-0 is present heading,
requested 39 as a final now.
And he's on present heading?
Yes.
I'm at 390 to prove.
A.W.
Division 3,
go with your master.
I can't pick up the units that you assigned to my fifth alarm.
Have you got it in the computer yet,
K?
They should be on there now.
Do you want to run down?
Let me try one more time in the computer,
because all I'm getting is like five units.
I'll get back to you in a second.
We'll get them on there as fast as we can,
K.
Stomach.
Oh,
he's gone.
What is it,
Joey Boots?
Howard,
hey,
I'm down on West 4th Street.
We heard the first explosion.
We went outside.
We're watching the smoke come out.
There's a hole in the side of the building.
All of a sudden,
maybe,
I don't know,
Ten minutes later,
there was another plane flying around,
and that disappeared into the building. also,
and you had, like, a third explosion after that.
How big did that plane look?
The second plane was a decent-sized plane.
It looked like it would hold maybe 50,
60 people.
Let me tell you something.
We're looking on TV,
and the World Trade Center is so big that it looks like a tiny plane.
You couldn't even believe the sight.
I mean,
I've never seen anything like this before.
We heard the first explosion.
It rocked my friend's apartment.
And he lives in West 4th Street,
and that's downtown.
And we could see the twin towers right from here.
It is smoke-filled away out of the side of the building.
There's a hole in the side.
Then we saw the other plane flying around after we were out there watching it for a few minutes,
and that plane disappeared into the building and it blew up.
They're flying right into the building.
This is them towelhead bastards.
Well,
we don't know who it is.
We don't know who it is.
I got a feeling.
You know,
it could be a...
You can't say that,
but I can say that.
It's about time we take these towelhead bastards and throw them out of the damn country.
Well,
don't overreact here.
It's nice to people,
man.
Let's find out who it is.
We're going to find out.
Once I find out...
Then we'll get crazy.
I got a lot of...
I'm sitting here watching it burn right now.
I know,
Joey.
And I just want to hug somebody now.
You know, people down there?
You do?
I do, too.
A lot of people down there.
Firefighters,
you should all report to your companies.
Again,
if you are a New York City firefighter,
drop what you're doing,
report to your company.
A major disaster is occurring in New York City this morning.
As to how this happened,
well,
the FBI is looking into reports.
Engine
1-0, What I'm gonna add.
1-0,
got it,
got it.
Engine 1-0,
inform every unit coming to this scene,
responding on West Street or Liberty Street,
not to pull up in front of the building.
We have ambulances and everybody else pulling up,
and we got debris falling from the building.
They have to stop short of the building,
either north or south.
Engine 1-0.
How far out of the way, from an approach to either
LaGuardia or Kennedy, would a plane have to be to hit the World Trade Center?
There are approaches that come up along the Hudson River,
which is to the west of the World Trade Center.
And those aircraft usually wind up going into LaGuardia.
So you can come within a mile or two of the World Trade Center,
But it is such a visible object as you're approaching New York City that it's just not possible for
Or a pilot during the daytime to have taken a course that would put it right into the World Trade Center.
Okay,
we have a five mile radius.
We need to stay back.
We're over North Bergen.
I do not hear anything.
We do not have TV up here.
Unless they can hear me,
I do not even have a cell phone.
Negative,
I do not have cell service up here.
I cannot communicate by cell.
I can talk about what
I see,
yeah,
but I cannot hear
6B.
American Dispatch,
Jim McCall.
Indianapolis Center,
did you get a hold of American 77 by chance?
No,
sir,
But we have an unconfirmed report that the second airplane hit the World Trade Center.
Say again?
You know,
we lost American 11 through a hijacking.
American was up.
The Boston-Los Angeles flight.
It was...
All right.
I can't really,
I can't hear what you're saying there.
You said American 11?
Yes,
we were hijacked.
It was a Boston, L.A.
flight.
And
77 is a dulles L.A.
flight.
And we have an unconfirmed report.
What a second airplane just flew into the World Trade Center.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
Let's go to Mike,
who works in the building next door.
Joey Boots,
stay on the line.
Yeah,
Mike.
Howard,
how you doing?
Yeah.
It's crazy over here.
It's like chaos.
It's like the Armageddon.
Of course.
The first...
First plane we didn't see.
You ought to get out of your building,
dude.
All we saw was fire.
Then the second time,
we actually saw the plane circle around.
And it's a big plane.
We're under attack.
Could you see what...
There are people flying planes into New York City and crashing into buildings.
It's chaos.
There's people all over the place.
What are the...
You saw the plane?
I saw a second plane.
What did it look like?
Did it look like a commercial plane?
No,
it looked like maybe one of those Airbus type things,
like an MD-80.
Hey,
Howard.
Yeah.
Howard,
anybody else that's out there listening now that's working at New York City Landmarks,
take my word,
be on the lookout right now,
because these guys,
they like to do these in multiple numbers.
There could be more coming in.
They're going to bomb a whole bunch of sites.
Make sure everybody takes watch.
Here's the Air Force.
The Air Force is stunned.
What?
On a more serious note,
you're a big pussy.
You didn't touch Pamela Anderson.
No,
we're back on that.
Dude,
I'm telling you.
We can talk about that anytime.
Yeah,
you can be back on me tomorrow.
I'm in the middle of organizing a military action.
Your car,
stop,
you're moving,
that's Dave,
stop.
Whose car is this?
It's your car.
Come on,
Ian.
Top of the head,
everything.
Something in line with the emails,
just,
yeah.
Stop,
take off.
Where's the last one?
That's the one.
No,
660's talking about it.
Okay,
let's do it.
Delta 9900,
if there was a couple of aircraft that I was talking to,
try to identify the aircraft in question,
and they think it might have been a Delta aircraft.
Oh.
Yes,
sir.
Is that a Kennedy call you want to go into the post?
No,
I'd like to say they said. A light paint scheme with a dark tail.
It's about as close as we could get.
Okay,
and did you say it's 660,
or what was the frequency?
1010.
We have another eyewitness on the phone.
Sir,
good morning.
Good morning,
Mr.
Gumbel.
How are you?
I'm fairly frightened,
I have to say.
Give me your name,
if you would.
My name is Frederick Schneider,
sir.
Mr.
Schneider,
where are you?
I am on Liberty Street,
which is the same street that the trade Center's on.
I'm on the south side,
and the trade Center's on the north side.
My office is on the
24th floor,
so I have a very clear view of exactly what happened this morning.
And I've been here for about two hours,
so I've been watching it unfold.
Two hours?
Yes.
I got to my office at 7 this morning.
Oh,
okay.
I'm sorry.
Tell me about the timetable of when things started to go terribly bad this morning.
Well,
Mr.
Gumbel,
At about 8.50 this morning,
there was an explosion.
I heard it first,
and then my building,
which is 51 stories tall,
shook and rocked.
And then I saw a plume of flame shoot out of the trade center over the Hudson River.
And then I saw the plane that had crashed into the trade center fall down,
and then it disappeared behind a building. That blocks my view.
There was a tremendous amount of smoke,
and then it started to rain. Huge pieces of paper.
And the paper continued to come down.
At that point,
all the news media started to learn about it,
and I turned on my radio.
And while I was still sitting at my desk,
I saw a second jet,
fairly large plane,
fly in over the south end of Manhattan. And deliberately fly directly into the trade center. Before my eyes.
Excuse me,
you guys got to back up.
Please,
please.
I understand.
News responding in to the World Trade Center.
Do not pull in front of the building on West or Liberty.
Okay.
News responding in to the
World Trade Center.
Do not pull in front of the building on West and Liberty.
All right,
John,
we have on tape the second attack.
These are attacks.
I'm going to start calling them attacks.
Watch in the upper right-hand portion of your screen.
You will see a plane coming in.
In a dive, Oh my gosh, and then hitting the side of the building. Uh, quite obviously a deliberate. These these acts are deliberate. We can now rule out any accident. Copy
that Ov.
They want to go live.
Can you just...
It's a 737, you...
Yeah,
Division 3 to Manhattan.
Division 3,
go ahead.
The summary is only giving me a few units.
You're gonna have to give it to me over the radio.
I'm ready to write.
Alright.
Engine 2-1-1.
5-1-1.
Engine 4-4.
Engine 2-2.
Engine 5-3.
Engine 4-0.
Yourself,
Battalion 1-0,
Battalion 1-2,
ladder 1-6,
Ladder 2,
ladder 1-3,
Engine 2-1,
Engine 2-3,
Engine 2-09,
Engine 2-1-2,
Engine 2-7-9,
Engine 2-3-0,
Engine 2-2-9.
4. Bravo,
this is the Hound King.
Engine 216,
Engine 217,
Engine 214,
Ladder 12,
Ladder 118,
Ladder 7,
Ladder 24,
High-rise 1,
and Battalion 11,
Division 3.
Initially,
they told us to stay in our rooms,
that it was safer because debris was still falling,
and indeed, it is.
And they indicated to stay into our rooms.
They just now told us to go down into the lobby of the hotel,
but...
To be honest with you,
it appears to me that these two incidences were deliberate.
And my fear is I don't want to be in a crowd of people. Down below,
right in front of the World Trade Center,
if there's terrorist activity. And now there's people out there.
It looked to me like the second plane was deliberate,
and I could be wrong.
But that's what my instincts are telling me,
is to just stay put.
There were two planes.
Yes.
Thank you,
Pat.
May I have your attention,
please?
Once again,
this is fire safety Director.
If you're asking that all our guests, please come down to the lobby.
All guests and employees please report to the lobby.
Thank you.
I have,
I have.
You want to stay under the old pit.
You'll be good.
You'll be good. .
The second occurrence, within a few minutes, is beyond belief.
As you can see,
there definitely is no weather problem,
so weather would be definitely ruled out as a factor in this case.
Yes,
the course is a normal course for commercial pilots coming in.
Into New York,
It certainly appeared from the video on CNN that the second aircraft was heading for the tower and that it was a commercial-sized aircraft.
Could you tell,
have a better idea about what size that plane was?
It was kind of hard for me to tell.
You're an expert in these matters.
Could you look at that tape and tell what size that plane was?
It would have to be slowed down and you need more than one angle for it because you'd want to see how many engines on it. The shape of the tail, well, this, if it's possible, gang, can we guys, could we go ahead and replay that tape right now?
Do we thank you, look?
How do you combat this?
Reagan stopped them what I'm saying.
I mean, go in there and you teach them a lesson.
We know where these people are.
We need to set the cruise missiles over there right now.
I just saw bombing the hell out of them today.
We're always worried about the innocent civilians who live around here.
You know what?
Innocent civilians,
so what?
They shouldn't be living by these guys.
Supporting them,
all that crap,
okay?
How about this?
We won't do anything.
Oh,
no.
We'd better do something.
We won't do anything.
You better do something.
GW,
you better get on the stage.
you listen to this right now.
You better bomb the hell out of those towel heads.
Howard,
what was the end result of, after the whole world
Trade Center bombing and all the trials and everything else?
How many guys...
Nothing happened, nothing right, nothing. Oh no, it's not true. Well, some guys went to jail. Big deal guys. They tried to get bin laden at three different places. Remember that, Oh, come on, we can't get bin laden. Then there's something wrong in this world. Hey Howard,
I just talked to a guy,
he just went by with a fire scanner,
said there's multiple casualties.
Of course.
There's a line of clock,
everybody's at work.
At nine o'clock, they timed it just perfectly. The opening of the stop. How did everybody go to work? How do they get a plane? I don't know. Two planes spreading out, the whole building's going up, buildings are just going to be. They're like boxes. Now. Why do you say deliberately fly into the trade Center? because,
um, there was no doubt in my mind that both planes were using the trade center as as a target.
They weren't in distress.
They weren't,
weren't falling from the sky,
they aimed for it.
And they did a very good job.
The trade center is torn open.
There's a hole in the south side of the trade center, torn open from the impact of the plane,
which fell into the street below.
Would that be the westernmost of the two towers?
Um.
The southernmost of the two towers.
Yes.
Yes,
it's a big gaping hole in it.
Flames and smoke have been pouring out since it happened about five minutes ago.
I'm a little shaken because I saw the plane pass before my eyes.
It was just about at my eye level,
so...
How close to you?
A block and a half.
We're getting news on 980 and 1210.
I do think it might be two aircraft.
There is a lot of talk that we had a couple of aircraft look like they got hijacked and...
And,
uh,
yeah,
I know at least one of them hit the World Trade Center.
We don't know what happened to the other aircraft.
Maybe both of them went in.
Mark,
These are holes in the side of the building that stretch floors.
This is not a B-24,
you know,
coming in at one or two floors of the building,
like, happened as you were describing earlier, and demolishing one or two floors.
These are several floors that are now aflame,
engulfing the entire top of the building.
And the emergency services are just now arriving.
I mean,
they have been here now for several minutes,
shortly after the explosion.
But clearly,
they're just organizing themselves.
I think this is going to be a very long day as they try to extinguish these extensive flames that are on either side of the building.
Joining us now is our New York correspondent,
Jane Stanley.
Jane,
what can you tell us?
Well,
there's of course huge speculation here about what has happened.
The two towers of the
World Trade Center,
those two famous towers,
both...
On fire.
We do know that. About nine minutes before the top of the hour,
a first plane appeared to crash into the upper floors of one of the towers,
and then, within about 18 minutes later,
a second plane, or a second explosion, happened.
But there's, of course, huge speculation already about how on earth this could happen.
Airplane,
Airplane, thank you.
Oh,
definitely. Saw the second plane.
I heard its sound and I saw it streaming in from the south.
I watched it crash into the trade Center.
You said you're very afraid,
and understandably so.
They're not evacuating your building?
No.
I'm going to leave on my own,
but I haven't heard any decisions made to that effect.
Can you see the ground from your vantage point?
Oh,
yes.
Talk to me about the scene on the ground,
if you would.
Well,
it's completely devoid of vehicles and people.
The entire street is totally littered with paper and smoke,
and several vehicles are on fire on Liberty Street in the parking lot where...
Either fuel or pieces of the plane fell onto them after crashing into the trade Center.
There's a tremendous number of emergency vehicles here and continuing to arrive.
I hear sirens from every side.
All right,
Mr.
Schneider,
you've got a great vantage point.
I'm going to ask you to hold on with me for a little while,
if you would.
Okay,
Mr.
Goss.
I know you're anxious to get out of the building.
I'm not going to keep you forever,
I promise.
Okay.
But let me ask you to sit tight for a second while I go to Washington.
You've got to know that air traffic controllers right now are scratching their heads trying to figure out where this plane came from.
If it was one that they were controlling and suddenly went maverick on them,
one that came in from somewhere beneath their radar.
As I mentioned earlier,
there is what's called VFR traffic up and down the Hudson River.
These are usually smaller planes who are just looking out for other airplanes not under positive control,
but the big jets are always under control.
Yes, sir.
We're listening to 660,
two different plane crashes.
One is a swept wing jet type airliner.
And we were talking to the last controller and he said he was tracking one at over 500 knots going into the city.
Yeah,
that's the one that hit the World Trade Center.
Have the authorities said whether any kind of warning was received about this kind of possible attack?
Certainly, that is not on the agenda at the moment.
Nobody's talking of any kind of warning.
But it must be said that people in New York have been quite conscious that since the
American Embassy bombers were sentenced here,
and one is due still to be sentenced this week,
that there could be some kind of...
Revenge involvement, of course, because of this 1993 attack. Well, we didn't see the first one, but that became we stopped, and then, while we're watching the first one, the second one. It looked like a plane, but I'm hearing that it wasn't. But there had to be the explosion that flew everything out and it looked like a plane,
one flying by, but on the second one. But apparently I'm listening to you. But that was a huge explosion. Oh, we saw the second explosion flying out and I thought I saw something go by. But maybe it was just a
inside of the building coming, flying out on the second building. I mean, it's terrifying, it's absolutely terrifying. Bill Broderick, Bill Broderick. When I was going to work to park right over next to the World
Trade Center with my wife, who works in the World Financial Center. Man alive with 10 minutes. We swear we're lucky. It's just this will put the field of Lord. I'm glad everyone wanted.
People can do this.
Pray to God, not too many people are dead.
This is really scary.
Where are you from?
From Manhattan.
You think she'll talk to me?
I know she's shaking.
I know she is.
John,
I want to bring in at this point the news that obviously an awful lot of our viewers are probably very concerned about people that they know.
In this area and they're trying to reach them on the cell phones, and the cell phones in that area are down.
So if you have loved ones in the area,
they're not going to be able to call you.
You're not going to be able to call them.
It's just an added. I realize
it just heightens the anxiety,
but that's the way it is.
So we're told that cell phone service in that area is down.
Yeah,
Lester,
We are now just getting word from the Associated Press and Urgent Wire that the FBI is now investigating a hijacking.
Also,
this from an employee of United Airlines.
He says he is hearing from the United Command Center that an American Airlines plane,
a 757 Airbus,
was hijacked and crashed purposely into the trade Center.
A second plane was then flown into the second tower,
which we have been looking at on video replay.
There you see the ISO,
and now the explosion,
the second tower,
and that happened just...
Minutes ago, I want to repeat again. The FBI, according to The Associated Press, is investigating a hijacking. We now are getting information from an employee of United that he is hearing the Command Center at United is investigating. An American Airlines plane, a 757 Airbus, hijacked and crashed into the trade Center. They want me to talk about what I see.
Okay,
what we can tell you right now from up here in Chopper 4,
We cannot get any closer than about five miles to the scene because we need to keep this far back.
But you can see the black smoke as far as we are away.
Can zoom in here for you.
First,
you saw the smoke from the one tower.
Then we witnessed an explosion on the other tower.
Now,
we think that there was a plane that actually headed into that second tower at some point,
and that's what caused that second explosion.
We are unable to get close enough to actually show you or tell you what's going on at the ground,
But an unbelievable sight here, from above the Hudson River at this vantage point.
Back to you.
Car 9 to Manhattan,
K.
Car 9,
go ahead.
Would you advise the mobile command vehicle to come in on West and Liberty Street,
West and Liberty Street,
K.
Legum,
I'm...
I already advised them to get down.
What's their ETA?
Manhattan call field, com.
Manhattan,
that's not the field com.
I want the mobile communications radar Manhattan.
Call 9-9,
go ahead.
Manhattan,
I want the mobile command vehicle,
not the field comm.
The mobile command vehicle is responding also.
I want them at Western Liberty.
Division 3 to Manhattan.
Division 3,
go ahead.
American Dispatch,
Jim McCall.
Indy Center, here.
Yes, sir.
American 11,
You guys said that he departed off of New York?
Boston.
Boston,
and he was going to LA,
and it was a hijacked airplane?
Yes.
And have you heard anything from American 77?
No.
Okay.
I told the lender in the center that I gave the information I got.
Okay,
thanks a lot.
All right.
And now the FBI is telling us that there has been some sort of a plane hijacking that they're investigating.
We have another witness on the telephone right now who actually saw the...
EXPLOSION.
I heard a little bit of a GUNSHOT.
I heard a little bit of a floor.
It just disintegrated instantly.
Can you tell us what kind of an airplane it was?
It looked like a huge...
747.
It was a big airline.
It wasn't a small jet.
It was a big carrier.
And you couldn't see anybody?
Could you see a pilot or any such thing?
No.
It was like side by side.
It was like I was right behind it.
It was huge.
I couldn't believe how low it was.
I was telling my roommate,
this plane is very low.
And I actually saw it go straight into the twin Towers.
Like,
why is he going into the building?
It was like it was almost deliberately glided into the...
Building Elena, Where exactly do you live? Where did you see this from? Battery Park City? No. I'm in the East Village on 13th Street. And you then saw the plane go into the building, and I assume you saw the resulting. You better believe it. I saw an explosion like I have never seen. And all I can say is those people
I don't know, but they're all definitely disintegrated. It wasn't most awful thing I've ever seen. It was so sad. I was like a nervous wreck. Well, and I don't blame you, I appreciate you was awful and all I can say is we should pray for those people.
Because it looked to me that it was deliberate. Unless the pilot had a heart attack, it was like this big 747 just went right into the floor of the twin towers. Well,
Elena, Yes, we thank you very much for for calling us and giving us this information.
The
they got a direct route to the World Trade Center.
Everything below 24th
Street is wide open to get down there and respond to these locations.
You want to move on the west side?
11th Avenue is wide open from 30th Street all the way south to the Ewell Trade Center,
K.
The PD's already got it shut down.
Alright,
gentlemen,
while you and Mr.
Spiney, Get over to the west side,
11th Avenue is closed down.
On the way.
Mr.
Spiney,
get over to the left side.
11th Avenue,
West side.
You okay?
Call Immovable Command Vehicle,
okay.
All right,
Don.
Okay,
we've got Melinda now, who's live,
where she's been taking these pictures.
Melinda,
tell us what you're looking at.
can you hear us?
Alright,
we're going to go to Melinda in just a few minutes.
Good morning,
you're looking at live pictures of the World Trade Center, Tower 1, from Manhattan, Lower District.
As you can see,
we have a very serious fire in the World Trade Center.
What we understand...
The information is still early in coming, but what we understand is that two separate planes have hit Tower one. Uh, which is, uh, the tower that you're seeing on your picture right now. As you can see, there are flames. There is a massive crazy day, huh? You heard what happened right now? I've heard there's one or maybe two aircraft projects.
Manhattan calling Mobile Command Vehicle 10.
10-9,
I'm unable to read.
Raise in at the top.
10-4 Manhattan,
keep trying.
The White House tells us, by the way, that President George W.
Bush is aware of the disaster in New York City.
We have not gotten any reaction yet from him or further details,
but let's head over to Lester now for more.
Hey,
we have with us at the moment Lindsey Grimm,
a witness.
Who was in the building on the phone.
Lindsay,
can you hear me?
I can hear you.
Can you tell me what you know?
Well,
I actually,
just to clear things up,
I wasn't in the building.
I was in the World Financial Center,
which is directly behind it.
Okay.
And I was...
Our part of the building faces the section,
the courtyard, where the World Trade Center is.
So we ran to the window right after.
We felt kind of this sonic boom, as if it were an earthquake.
And something just wasn't right.
We ran to the window and somebody yelled,
oh,
my God,
a plane just flew into the World Trade Center.
Is this what we think it was,
the first one or the second one,
Linda?
It was the first one because I was actually outside for the second one.
And the first one appears to have gone into the Southern tower,
Am I correct?
Correct.
And this second one.
Did you see the second one?
I was,
I had my back facing,
I was running as fast as I,
well, not running,
but walking at a brisk pace,
away from the two buildings,
when I heard it,
and people just started screaming and running.
3,
Zimmerhaus.
Crossway,
Gay.
Get a hold of field Comm,
we need them on West and Vessi Street,
Gay.
Field comm on west and Vessi.
Field
Comm, West and Vessi,
I got that.
Right,
10-4.
Command Center East.
Boston.
Listen,
Both of these aircraft departed Boston,
both were 7-6s,
both heading to LA.
And I'm looking out on the TSD,
and I think that all departures out of Boston should have heightened cockpit security.
Is there any way you can bring up every center in the country?
And relay that message so that they can tell the aircraft that are out there flying right now to increase the cockpit security vigilance on this day.
I'll get the message out.
Thank you very much.
Jim Stewart is standing by.
He's got some official reaction.
Jim,
good morning.
What are you hearing?
Good morning,
Brian.
Well,
as by happenstance,
I was talking to FBI headquarters at the moment this explosion took place.
They saw it occur as we saw it occur the second time.
Second explosion,
rather,
and their reaction was the same as everyone else.
Number one,
they noticed the clear weather there.
Number two,
they noticed what appeared to be,
in their eyes,
a deliberate attempt to crash the aircraft into the World Trade Center.
Right now,
they are...
They are trying to determine whether, in fact it was deliberate.
They have no information they can share at the moment.
And I get the sense that they're in the same mode that we are,
simply their mouth is. Or a gate trying to figure out what's going on.
JIM,
let me interrupt.
I was a lot closer than that.
I got down to Church Street.
I was standing right in between the two towers,
which, as you can see on your television screen,
the smoke,
the black smoke and fire.
I don't know which airport is that.
Oh my God.
I think it must be a foreign,
I think it must be something bad.
Don't you think?
Why?
I think it's terrorism.
There are so many people in the World Trade Center.
I go,
do you know how often I go down there?
That's where I shop.
Exactly.
And that second one looked like it was headed straight for it.
It was,
I mean,
it was like,
it was targeting it.
Everybody's on cell phones,
I can't get a hold of my own.
I can't get a hold of them.
He's going.
I've got to go.
Mark,
I want to interrupt you for just one moment.
I'm just hearing from our producer that the FBI is investigating a possible plane hijacking just before the crash.
Nick,
are you hearing if that was international?
Nothing.
Nothing yet.
Okay.
The FBI,
just want to recap,
is investigating a possible plane hijacking just before the crash.
Well,
it's hard to believe that there would be two plane hijackers, because two planes have just been...
Is this today significant?
Any religious holiday for any?
I was just thinking,
is it a significant anniversary of anything?
Does anyone have that?
Well,
let me take a look here.
We'll probably look into that.
If any, viewers...
Yeah,
zooming in.
Whoops.
You wanna take a close look?
Take a look,
a close look at it.
As tight as I can get it.
Oh my god,
it's pretty tight,
bro.
There's a lot of flame in the building,
it's fire.
I know.
There's a lot of flame.
It's gonna be like 10 feet high.
It's gonna burn out,
yeah.
See all that red thing?
And the video camera shows everything.
I think it's gonna give another explosion,
bro.
Gonna hit like a power line or something.
Yeah.
What does that antenna do?
Cause, whatever...
It's likely that two separate planes,
20 minutes apart,
would each crash accidentally into a different train center.
But the fact is,
we don't know,
and you can have one accident,
you can't have a plane coming close trying to get it.
That was planned by a terrorist group,
or it can be just that the air traffic control system completely crashed.
This is going to take a lot of...
No.
The air traffic control system...
Like a crazy air traffic control system...
See,
they're not allowed to...
Hold it.
Visually,
it's a clear day in New York.
There's no way two planes crash into the World Trade Center.
They're a legitimate news organization.
They're not allowed to say what we're thinking,
which is obvious.
You know,
evaluate some of the injuries...
How I see that second plane flying around there.
It disappeared and then there was an explosion.
You know what?
Today is primary day.
I mean,
it's pretty sensible to me what happened.
Here's the World Trade Center after two planes hit it today.
We saw the second one,
heard the first.
I know the area fairly well, working down there.
Is 9 o'clock in the morning the time when people have gathered in?
A very large number of people get there earlier or get there later.
Yeah,
I actually just happen,
I usually get here a little after 9,
and I happen to be here early for a meeting this morning.
So,
yeah.
I mean,
you see the general amount of traffic about 9 o'clock.
Is that when it happened,
right at 9?
No,
just before and just after 9.
Okay.
Can you see outside at the moment as to anything that's happening?
I am outside.
And where are you and what are you seeing?
I am west of the two buildings, looking directly at them,
and it's difficult to look at.
This is not an area which is easy to reach for emergency services.
These two buildings,
Hudson River,
there's only the west side drive that comes up there.
Is there a large amount of emergency equipment descending on the place?
There sure is.
As soon as I got out of the building,
obviously, the first thing you're surrounded by is siren noise everywhere,
and you can hear it coming by. Now, even still.
Anything else you know that you'd like to add?
Just as I was coming out of the building,
I heard somebody sort of ushering people away,
and they were saying...
You guys got to get out of here.
It's a bomb.
Many thanks,
Lindsey Grimm,
who saw this occurring,
at least the first hesitation.
Are you able to confirm anything within your airline to us?
No,
unfortunately.
How about can you tell me if we know for sure it was American 11 that went into the trade center?
We think that's who it was.
Okay.
And we're missing another flight also.
Which flight are you missing?
77.
And when was the last time you knew, for sure, something about him?
He was in...
Wait a minute.
Well,
there's a...
I don't know how he got up there,
but they think 77 is up there also.
He's out at Dulles.
Okay,
and...
Dulles,
L.A.,
And they both apparently have been hijacked.
11 were pretty sure is in there and
77 we were talking to them, according to Indianapolis Center about 45 minutes ago and in Indy Center.
I don't know how we got to do it.
Back to the trade Center.
I have no idea if that happened.
Okay,
it may not have.
We have another call sign.
Of course,
we don't know for sure any of these call signs right now,
but if we find that it's your aircraft,
we'll certainly give you a call.
Okay,
so you have two airplanes in the trade Center?
Yes.
And you don't know who, either one of them are, for sure?
Yeah,
that's true.
Okay.
If I did,
I would share it with you.
Okay,
thanks.
All right,
bye,
Bill.
You can't do nothing.
I'm right here.
One hit on the end.
One hit first thing right here.
We don't know where to go.
There's propane tanks around the corner.
Stay all over the place.
I don't know if anybody's going to see it.
I don't know if everybody's going to see it.
Car 3,
Cadman.
Hi,
Car 3,
are you 84 to Box?
We are 10-84 to Box.
We're at West and West,
in case.
Listen,
I have some for you to check out.
At that point,
we're certainly close to.
I just want to interrupt you because we're getting some information,
some more information from NBC.
This is from a
United
Airlines employee.
He says he's hearing from the United Command Center that an American...
Airlines plane,
a 757 Airbus, was hijacked and crashed purposely into the trade Center.
A second plane was then flown into the second tower.
That is what we are hearing from our NBC sources, from a worker from United Airlines.
So they were big airplanes.
What?
I don't know,
the second one looks like a military.
What?
Second one looks like a military plane.
Lauren,
I want to get out of here.
You hear creaking and stuff.
Lauren,
I want to get out of here.
Look at that falling.
Go ahead, Manhattan.
Master service,
floor is your favorite.
Master Service standby.
Car 3 in Building 2.
The number 824.
The number 88 floor and number
894. On the 82nd floor, it's the west.
I have other floors.
You ready to copy?
10-4.
Okay,
the 83rd floor in Building 1.
104th floor.
103rd floor,
northwest corner,
room 103.
106th floor.
83rd floor,
Is it 8311 room?
Each second for each side in building one.
So right now,
if those of you who are trying to get into the city by train,
don't be surprised if the train stops.
I can take the day off,
actually,
and I'm not a big fan of U.S.
Military power,
but it would be nice.
In that area,
I want to get the hell...
You guys,
are you really a...
Joey.
No,
that's far enough away.
You're far away?
No,
I'm down on West 4th Street.
I'm here on the radio.
They're talking about the plane is inside the building.
There's multiple casualties.
How would these towel heads,
I'm telling you,
we let them come to this country,
they're here illegally,
a lot of them,
we don't even kick them out.
Well,
we're letting everybody in here illegally.
Could the plane have been,
like,
loaded with explosives or something,
you know?
Sure.
Come on,
what would you do if you wanted to bomb?
Something you're just sticking up, just flying, you know, I don't know how true it is, but a couple, I think. While we were on vacation, I read in one of the newspapers that they are actually, you know, like, honoring the families of these s****** mission guys. They have over in the yellow. Does that? After they blow up an Israeli? US, you know, the family gets compensated, the family is treated like heroes.
uh...
Hamas must Joey, uh...
Thanks.
I heard an explosion.
I was at the terrace.
I heard a big bang about half an hour ago when I was having coffee.
I looked around and there was no lightning.
Then I went outside and I was driving away and I saw this huge boom of smoke going across the sky.
I looked around and I went,
fuck,
it's the trade center.
You're just holding it on there?
Yeah.
You want to use it?
Good.
You want to go on top?
You can go on top of mine.
Yeah,
it's cool.
Go ahead.
Come on.
Just one second,
I'm looking at a report that the FBI is investigating reports of a plane hijacking.
Did you have any news of that?
No,
we don't.
No confirmation of that whatsoever?
We have no confirmation of that.
Is anybody even there discussing that?
No,
the only discussion that's been going on here,
Brian,
is that the...
The World Trade Center has obvious symbolic value.
It's been a target before of terrorism,
and, frankly, it would not surprise the FBI or anyone in national security if it was a target again.
Sometimes the obvious leads you to a conclusion.
We're looking at two crashes 18 minutes apart.
Into an obvious target,
a building that has never been hit with a plane before on a clear day.
What do the intelligence people there say about that?
The intelligence community for some time has been warning in a steady drumbeat,
Brian,
that Osama bin Laden has not been heard from now,
frankly,
since the beginning of the year,
the U.S.S. Cole incident,
rather,
And they've been wondering when and if he will strike again,
and they only believed it was a matter of time,
and I believe that today that is going to be their first suspicion.
But we have no...
Confirmation of that,
I must underline.
There's no confirmation that this is a terrorist attack,
number one,
or number two,
that it's Osama bin Laden involvement.
But I can tell you right now, that is what they are thinking.
That is the working premise.
And we'll just have to see, as the day unfolds, what they discover.
Jim,
as we sit here at 9-17,
does the FBI have any choice but to sit and watch this on television?
I have never heard such a gasp of astonishment as I heard speaking to the FBI headquarters this morning. When they saw what we saw,
the explosion at the World Trade Center,
the second explosion and the smoke coming out of it.
It reminded me and them of Oklahoma City.
There's pure astonishment,
I can tell you,
at FBI headquarters this morning,
and they are trying to find out the facts, just as we are.
Okay,
we're going to get field comms set up.
We'll be able to copy everything,
okay?
Right, 10-4,
just advise me when you're ready.
.in. The United States,
John Cochran,
who was the president in Florida.
John?
Peter,
as you know,
the president's down in Florida talking about education.
He got up out of his hotel suite this morning,
was about to leave.
Reporters saw the White House chief of Staff,
Andy Card,
whisper into his ear.
The reporter said to the president,
Do you know what's going on?
On in New York.
He said he did and said he will have something to say about it later.
His first event is about a half an hour at an elementary school in Sarasota,
Florida.
Thanks,
John.
John Cochran with the president.
President's in Florida today pushing his education reform.
It will get wiped off the agenda today in view of this extraordinarily serious accident.
More information on that just ahead.
Now we want to bring in Todd Harris.
Todd,
on the scene,
saw what happened.
Todd,
are you with us?
Yes,
I had a perfect view and the plane was coming in.
I noticed it a second before it hit the building.
It looked like it was moving.
Slowly, and it lined itself up to hit the building directly.
Are you talking about the first plane or the second plane?
The first plane.
And Todd,
tell us exactly where you are,
where you had this great view.
I was on Highway 278,
like a dead-on view of the side that it hit the building.
Oh my god, that was close.
Ladder 17 I'm ahead.
17 truck ahead.
On your frequency, we locate the ladder 15.
I-10-4 17.
Do you know whether or not the FBI had received any warnings about attacks on domestic soil?
You know,
frankly,
no.
And it's a question that we ask every day.
I asked as recently as yesterday of the intelligence community, what was the latest on terrorism threats in the United States,
whether any intercept had been picked up,
whether there was any current fear here that the target,
the next target,
would be within the United States.
The answer came back, no.
They were still anticipating that the next strike against American interest would be overseas, somewhere.
Those are the most vulnerable targets.
Today would clearly be some evidence that that's not the case at all.
In clear weather,
as you pointed out,
what appears to be a deliberate attack into the heart of the financial district in New York City,
you can't pick a more explicit message to send to America if you're a terrorist than what happened today.
Leon has something to jump in here with.
Yes,
I'm checking the wires, even as we speak.
The Associated Press is reporting right now that the FBI in Washington is investigating reports that these two plane crashes are the result of foul play.
There is a report here by The Associated Press.
Of a possible plane hijacking.
They don't say two,
but they say a possible plane hijacking.
Marine 6 to Manhattan.
6 to Manhattan.
We're in the marine Division.
We will position by the Brooklyn Bridge for a possible transport of...
equipment.
Mark,
If anybody who's interested in seeing this,
I would advise staying far from the building.
There's still large pieces of debris,
huge chunks of metal falling down,
and these pieces of metal are smashing against nearby these fire trucks.
So this is kind of a disaster that's still unfolding. Steer clear of the place. Certainly,
Yes,
And
I mean,
if you do want to see this,
you don't have to get all that close. Because this is visible for dozens of miles in every direction.
And Mark,
as you had predicted,
the local television stations,
at least one,
if not two,
maybe all of them, have been knocked off the air,
at least for a time being.
I don't know if they're back on now.
Alright,
how- See,
shouldn't it be like planes now flying over,
dropping water and stuff?
Isn't that the only way they're gonna like,
put it out?
Maybe that's how they put out forest fires,
maybe that's how they do it.
I don't know anything about it.
It's inside the building, though,
John.
At that point,
that's like jet fuel,
electrical,
oof,
something like that.
Hey,
wasn't that building taller than,
what is that building?
That the big building.
Empire State Building.
Oh my god.
Wasn't it taller than it was before?
Look, how much it's disintegrated.
Oh, you are a nutcase.
You know what,
you gotta go talk to horses in the winter circle.
Oh my god.
You are such a nutcase.
No, I'm serious,
you didn't see that?
How could you live in New York and go,
what is,
you know,
what building? is the Empire State Building?
You see that building over there?
What is that?
Hey Howard,
why is my hand bigger than the World Trade Center?
Yeah,
cause you...
That don't look so big.
Cause it's on TV,
dude.
When the airplanes crashed in...
Car 9,
Manhattan.
K.
Would you have the units responding on the 5th alarm?
It's number 2,
World Trade Center.
That's number 2,
Report to Chief Barber at West and Liberty Street.
West and Liberty Street,
K.
How long were you guys behind you?
Did you get everything?
No,
I just,
I got up,
I think I heard about a half hour ago.
I was on Tombald Street when I got caught.
They closed it,
they wouldn't let us on, and they diverted all the traffic.
So we've been sitting. And then as we were driving down here on the BQE, everybody was stopped,
I mean, stopped dead watching, because you could see everything.
Two planes hit.
Holy shit.
That's what they say.
Two planes.
Two small planes.
And just as I got off the line,
I mean,
got out of the car. And they said the FBI said we were to hijack.
Yeah.
Everything's on.
That's what they just said on the radio,
they were hijacking.
Really?
Yeah.
Hi,
patient.
Everybody has no feelings?
Everybody's got no feelings of people at work.
I'm talking bad.
I'm conscious.
Everybody's awake.
So far,
yeah.
I put them in the head of Life's awake.
Yeah,
so conscious.
And it's very happy.
But they're not crying,
right?
I can't see.
No,
it's in the eye.
It's not crying.
No fight for now and no fuck,
right?
No fuck,
Oh, fuck,
that's my leave!
Okay,
you stay calm with me,
okay?
Is that the water pool in the land,
by any chance?
No,
no,
the water pool is the one where the explosion was.
The explosion in the store!
Oh,
that's the one?
Yes!
Oh my god,
it's so hot now!
So that's the big problem with an ancient fort.
That was a good thing to do.
And now,
I have a building.
I was in the building.
I was building.
Now,
what was it?
Can you believe?
I was in the building.
This was a new building.
I had to do all this.
Oh,
my God.
They just put a mountain top down.
And,
oh,
it could be funny.
And you can use that as a handle.
It's been on this mountain top.
Now,
this is the thing.
the guy who was the leader of the party was walked out of bed.
Now,
he's not dying.
And I'll be right back.
I'm going to ask you a question.
Hello,
ma'am.
Do you have a picture of a human fire?
I mean,
sure.
Do you have a picture of a fire?
I see a fire.
I don't know if you can show me the fire.
I see it.
Ma'am,
ma'am,
just go over and listen to me.
Thank you.
She's in the ceiling,
you can feel it.
Okay,
It's a heel on the floor.
We feel it,
that's the thing to breathe.
Oh my God,
oh my God,
listen to that.
This is for you.
Stay calm,
okay?
I'm sorry.
Okay,
situation,
but they're afraid to think of ways.
When they check,
do they have actions?
Do they have ways for them to get out of there?
Do they have actions that they're doing?
What are they doing?
I want to go.
And they're calm.
There,
there.
Can you just give a look,
just for the end of it?
I will.
You got it,
yeah?
Yeah.
I'm right there,
one second.
Cookie?
What's that there?
Put it in the salad?
Uh-huh.
All good,
ready?
Hold on one second,
babe.
Please hold.
Don't hang up the phone.
It's me,
the doctor.
It's me.
Please,
doctor,
take him home.
No,
no,
no.
I'm sorry,
you can go home.
I'm ready.
O-R-E-C-T-E-R-T-E-T-E.
Hello?
Hi.
Okay.
And then everyone went down.
Are you ready?
A-L-Z-R-T-E-C.
Alright.
Call up.
The police about tomorrow.
I've got to get high.
I want to have my house.
I want my house to go.
I want all the people.
I want them to walk.
Okay.
Hello?
Yes,
ma'am.
I've got to get my money.
I'm over here.
You can't look at this mother.
10-4,
Angel, 1-4,
Man in tank.
That's correct,
that's the command post for Number 2,
World Trade Center,
West and Liberty Street.
10-4,
call 9-4.
I stress again,
though,
this is pure speculation,
but it is speculation right now by the people who are going to have to solve this crime,
If in fact, it is one,
Brian.
That's a good point,
Jim.
At this point,
it is pure speculation.
The only thing we can tell you is we are looking at a very clear day in Manhattan.
On this Tuesday morning,
we are looking at two towers of 110 stories in height that are on fire right now. That have absorbed two impacts with 18 minutes apart.
Certainly, it's a little more than...
It would be an amazing coincidence,
I think we should say.
Thank you.
I want you to stand by in my direction,
okay?
All problems,
okay.
I feel calm. Reporting photos of the Financial District building on West Street,
please.
American Express immediately.
I can't believe they're on their way.
I want you to stand by.
Hey Indy,
this is pat at the command Center.
I need you to tell me anything and everything you can about American 77,
where he is,
and if you have radar or not.
Well,
okay,
I'm listening to you.
My OPS manager talked to Washington.
I'm sorry?
We were talking to him in the vicinity of
Henderson. Henderson?
What's Henderson?
Hang on a second.
Okay,
I guess we were talking to him in the vicinity of Henderson,
HNN.
We lost communications and radar with him.
Hang on a minute,
I'm going to have the OPS manager tell you the story.
Hello,
Command Center?
Yes,
sir.
This is John Thomas,
OPS Manager.
I think we need to let everybody know this right away, if they don't already.
American, 77, was over,
uh,
was just west of Charleston,
West Virginia, at flight level 350 to heavy Boeing 752.
And disappeared off our radar scope about
1256Z, a long-width lost frequency.
We were treating it as the loss started to do some procedures that notified search and rescue and whatnot. When American Airlines told us they'd had some air...
Aircraft or an aircraft hijacked.
We now believe that aircraft may have been hijacked,
although no one has,
you know,
we have nothing to verify that.
But with the World Trade Center,
we could have another loose aircraft out there somewhere.
Okay,
but at the time of loss,
what altitude was he at?
Flight level 350.
And he just lost primary also?
Yes,
lost no primary or that we could see.
Of course,
we wouldn't necessarily be able to pick up a primary there anyway.
And I'm assuming then that you're doing what you can to do a primary retrack on him,
if you can do that.
Yes,
sir.
Sure.
And then,
so 1256,
do what we lost.
Com and radar,
any
ELT? No ELTs.
Okay.
Any more information you get,
I appreciate it.
I'll forward this immediately up to the nomin.
And everybody that's standing up there.
Thank you.
Bye.
Nick,
you're on the air.
Is that really why?
Yeah,
I just called to tell you that the other guy you called and said it was the towelhead may be wrong.
The State Department yesterday issued a terrorist watch for all Americans in Peru due to the extradition of the drug lord Daniel Ochoa to America.
Well,
let's bomb them, too.
So let's bomb everyone.
That's probably not a bad idea.
Other than that,
it was Jackie the joke, man.
Let's drop A-bombs.
Oh.
But you see how it's spreading the building to the right,
Howard?
It's already going down the middle.
Well,
don't forget.
I mean, this thing's gonna burn, and you can't stop that kind of burning, it's gonna burn the whole building down. I mean, it looks like it's the one way. One is two-thirds the way up, the others about half way up. Yeah,
God knows what it looks like inside me. 110 stories. Can you imagine being above or above that? Oh God, you know what the it's all, you know what happens? The worst thing that happens in these far? He thought. Just smoke inhalation. yeah, smoke inhalation, that's how you just choke to death, which is horrible.
The skyline of Manhattan anymore.
Oh,
stop it.
What do you mean?
We must have that.
Well,
you're not going to have it.
It's gone.
The second one has to be stopped.
Yeah,
the second one.
I love it.
As bright as you can help me.
I can help you out.
Hello?
This is Carrie Feinstein,
C-A-R-R-I-E.
What did you see?
That's correct.
I was dropping my daughter off from school,
riding along the bike path along the river,
and I saw a big airplane over my head,
very low,
and I looked up and I thought,
what in the world is this plane doing here?
It's too low.
And I looked up behind...
And I saw this huge airplane crash into the side of the World Trade Center.
And then I was in shock,
as was everyone,
and we were standing there talking,
how could something like this happen?
And then, all of a sudden, a smaller airplane slammed right into the other tower.
I saw both of them happen.
It was horrible.
When you saw the second one happen,
what did it look like?
It was a much smaller plane.
Someone said it looked like a military plane,
but I'm not sure.
I don't know much about airplanes.
All I know is I saw both of them slam into the building,
and it was a horrible thing.
Did it look like they tried to stop it all or change it?
No,
no.
It looked very deliberate to me.
I mean,
how could you miss the World Trade Center?
Ovi?
Is the reason I don't have our channel because the transmitter's out?
You mean, the plane took it out?
This is like,
bizarre.
News responding into
two World Trade Center.
Respond to West Street and Liberty and T.G.
Ball.
News responding to two World Trade Center.
Respond to West and Liberty and T.G.
Ball at that location.
And here's the internet command at that location.
Which was below in the parking lot of B2.
50,000 people.
50,000.
Yeah,
understand,
understand.
4. Go ahead.
Yeah,
from the water street box, we're stuck in massive traffic.
We can't get up to
31st and Madison.
10-4,
Angel 1-4. ...
And there are indications...
That it may have been a Boeing 767 out of Boston.
We're contacting American Airlines.
They're saying,
one of you,
I think,
this is something they've been waiting to happen.
Who are you talking about?
What are you talking about?
What we were talking about is there's...
There's been a great frustration since the bombing of the World Trade Center,
which the suspects later told federal authorities were intended to take the building down,
that it didn't have a larger effect.
And U.S.
intelligence,
FBI. People for years have heard that they've always wanted to try and finish that job off,
to take the buildings out,
and that it was another viable target.
Interestingly,
ironically,
whatever you want to call it,
The World Trade Center just hired
weeks ago the head of the FBI's National Security Division for Counterterrorism in New York to augment and take over their security. Pretty much aware of the level of threat that this is as a symbolic target,
Well,
you're not gonna have it.
It's gone.
Put it back!
What's that stuff that's coming out of it?
Smoke.
Black smoke.
The white thing coming all the way down.
Is that like a ladder?
More smoke.
Oh,
you are so crazy.
It's smoke.
It's a fire.
It's a ladder.
It's a big fire,
Casey.
No,
the thing that just came out.
Do you see what I'm talking about?
No.
That's fire.
No,
the white thing that just came out.
See,
it's coming down right now.
In between the two buildings?
Yeah.
What a journalist.
There is something...
I can't see,
my eyes are so bad.
I think it's smoke from the back of the building.
No,
no,
it's white smoke.
It's Spider-Man.
It looks like somebody's moving.
What is that?
It's bigger than a person.
It's on the side of the building.
Yeah,
I think that's smoke.
I see somebody climbing down.
Hang a bed sheet,
man.
I'd do anything to get out of there.
Uh,
Bryant.
Go ahead.
Been told that,
and this should not come as a surprise.
It's standard procedure by the FBI.
Their rapid deployment team from the Washington Field office,
This is a group of people that they send to major disaster and terrorist incidents,
such as the twin Embassy bombings in Africa.
They have now been dispatched to New York.
I have reason to believe,
too,
that some members of the HRT,
that's the hostage rescue team,
have been put on alert.
We don't have any word yet that they would be sent.
And these are standard procedures that would take place any time a major terrorist incident occurs.
But this would be a group of approximately 60 experts,
people who are very good at picking up the bits of debris that we've been talking about. Falling on the streets of New York. And turning that into evidence, should they discover that this,
in fact,
was a deliberate act.
This is Jack Berger.
Mr.
Berger,
what did you see?
You saw the peak bodies falling?
I saw,
personally saw,
I worked at Number seven World Trade Center. Facing one of the towers, and I saw at least four bodies falling from the east side into the space between the two towers.
Several bodies on the ground now in between the two towers.
Did it look like people were trying to jump to safety or just falling out of the building?
I couldn't see them leaving the buildings kind of thing.
I couldn't tell if they were falling out or jumped out.
What did you see again?
I saw four or five bodies jumping out of the...
The Northernmost Tower around nine o'clock.
Jumping or falling?
I'm sorry,
I couldn't tell if they jumped or fell.
I mean,
they were falling when I saw them.
Thank you.
R9 to Manhattan.
R9,
get a head count.
Give me the company identifications that are coming to Two World Trade Center.
Just read them down.
I got four.
Engine 211,
Radar 111.
2-11,
Engine 2-2,
Engine 5-3,
Engine 4-0,
Division 3,
Battalion 1-0,
Battalion
1-2, Ladder 1-6,
Ladder 2,
ladder 1-3.
Engine 221,
Engine 23,
Engine 209,
Engine 212,
Engine 279,
Engine 230,
Engine 229,
Engine 235,
Engine 220,
Engine 216,
Engine 217,
Engine 238,
Engine 214,
ladder 12,
Ladder 118,
Ladder 70,
Ladder 250.
4,
High Rise 1,
Italian 11,
Engine 7-4,
Engine 7-6,
Engine 4-7,
Engine 5-8,
Engine 9-1,
Ladder 2-2,
Ladder 2-5,
Ladder 3-5,
4 trucks,
and Ladder 2-1.
Okay,
thank you,
Manhattan.
10-4.
Thank you.
I understand, Mr.
Davis,
you're back with me on the line?
I am.
And Ms.
Renault,
you're also back on the line?
Yes.
Mr.
Davis,
bring us up to speed.
What are you seeing?
Anything changed?
No,
but the smoke is getting thicker and I can see flames from some of the windows on the...
The first tower.
My view of the second tower is somewhat obstructed.
Where are you,
50th and 5th?
I'm
50th and 5th.
Yeah.
The officials there are anxious to, in any way, evacuate your building?
Or is this just normal workday?
I've been told that
Rockefeller Center is putting into effect security measures,
but we have not been told to evacuate.
Okay.
And,
Ms.
Renaud,
what are you seeing right now?
From the Southeast tower,
there are still flames coming out of the north side of the building.
And,
you know,
it may be just my perspective,
but it looks like something could be sticking out of that.
Also,
it looks like on the Northwest Tower that there's possibly...
You know, the fire and everything could have moved up because it seems to be that there's smoke coming out higher for higher floors on the building. You say there appears to be something out that would be the second aircraft, yes, the one at the lower level, yes. And and what, what actually do you see it?
Just there's an object that doesn't fit with the line of the building that seems to be protruding in, that foots on fire. We're getting a look at the building right now. And I must say the smoke seems to be obscuring our view enough. So that,
so that we can't identify.
We're re-racking the tape right now.
Manhattan, calling the mobile command vehicle,
K.
Manhattan calling Mobile Command vehicle,
3-0,
go ahead.
You're on your way,
4-3-K.
10-4,
you're responding to 2 World Trade Center.
Bring all your extra SCBas to the front of the building,
4-3-K.
Respond to Western Liberty and CG. Farber,
K.
10-4,
She's on the search for her new friend.
She looks quite a bit too big for her.
Talented picker.
At the second explosion,
it looked like a ticket tape parade for all of the evening.
You saw the plane when it hit?
I didn't see the plane when it hit.
So you only heard the explosion?
I heard the explosion and I was in an elevator.
I was very,
very,
you know,
panicked.
Thanks.
Whether any...
Markets operating in that area have decided to suspend trading for today.
New York Stock Exchange has been evacuated.
The New York Stock Exchange has been evacuated,
yes,
there you see it.
Well,
the American is right nearby.
I would assume that would be the case.
The stock market official...
Has the NYSE cancelled or simply we're on hold here?
Okay.
And the Nasdaq is considering the same thing.
I'm sure the New York Mercantile Exchange is in one of the towers,
isn't it?
I think it's in one of the towers.
Press lines are right there.
We can't get any closer?
I'm watching the Fox Network here,
and I just saw a thing on a thing. That said that FBI has almost verified that they had been hijacked in the earliest morning before the crash.
Really?
Oh,
so they hijacked a plane.
my goodness.
Oh,
man.
There was actually two planes.
Yeah,
right.
Two planes.
And it's actually ridiculous.
Watch it on a film.
I actually watch it on TV now.
Oh,
this is so aggravating.
I don't understand how all of a sudden, one day it's beautiful,
next minute,
no,
everything's just ruined.
What's that?
I hear him's a plane right now.
Oh,
God.
What,
am I showing it again?
Yeah,
I am speechless.
I mean,
what do you say?
What do you say about this?
I can't say anything.
You know what?
I just feel like nothing will be done.
No,
no,
no.
I'm sorry.
I think there would be such an outcry.
Something has to be done.
They've attacked the United States.
Forget it.
It's war.
We don't stand for this.
Wasn't there an attack on the World Trade Center?
Why did we never go to war over that?
We didn't have to go to war.
Because this is a plane?
Remember,
all those guys lived in Libya at the time,
didn't they,
Tom?
Yeah,
I think so.
And didn't we bomb them?
We didn't even declare war.
Remember,
we had the whole thing about France not letting us fly over their airspace?
We went anyway,
and we bombed them.
Yeah.
Yeah,
not enough.
And then what happened?
They stopped.
For a while.
They've been doing all kinds of stuff.
And the Israeli intelligence.
The problem is, you let them build up again.
Israel would take care of the problem for us,
But now, all of a sudden, we're worried about how the PLO feels.
I mean,
just let's get real.
Well,
see,
I thought that was stupid in the first place.
Yeah,
let's just get real.
Wow.
Let's go over to the nice couple.
Great.
I can't even get a cell signal in.
Second one?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So it's terrorist?
Yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
The club van is there,
so it's...
So they hit both buildings?
Yeah.
Defend the building,
we're getting FDR.
We're having a little bit of a trouble here.
Here,
you take some,
okay?
Nobody should be standing here!
Anybody?
Hold on!
Military Boston Center.
Just had a report that American 11 is still in the air and it's on its way towards heading towards Washington.
Okay,
American 11 is still in the air?
Yes,
there was only another aircraft that hit the tower.
That's the latest report we have.
Okay.
I'm going to try to confirm an ID for you,
but I would assume he's somewhere over either New Jersey or somewhere further south.
Okay,
so
American 11 isn't a hijack at all, then,
right?
No,
he is a hijack.
American 11 is a hijack?
Yes.
And he's going into Washington?
This could be a third aircraft.
.to. Washington, where White House correspondent Bill Plant is standing by.
Bill,
what are you hearing on your end?
Brian,
we're hearing that the president will have a statement to make shortly.
He is in Florida this morning.
He was supposed to do an educational event with children to push his education bill.
We understand that that event has been canceled.
There was a senior staff meeting here this morning.
Nobody seems quite to know exactly what's going on.
The National Security Council said earlier...
That it had heard nothing unusual.
This was after the first airplane impact.
We will hear from the president,
we think,
very shortly to hear what he has to say. And see what,
if anything,
they know about this,
which appears to be so deliberate.
Bill,
I asked Jim this earlier,
and again,
I apologize if you're not in a position to shed any more light on it,
but do you know whether or not officials there at the White House had been forewarned that there was an imminent attack or there was a heightened sense of alert?
We're aware they're...
Had been for some time a heightened sense of alert throughout the Mideast,
but I'm talking about domestically?
Well,
we do know that there has been a heightened sense of alert.
We do know that there have been a number of threats.
There are always threats received.
They have tended to take them recently a bit more seriously.
But it does not appear,
and I hesitate to make this for certain,
but it does not appear that they had any advance warning that anything was going to happen today.
132 to Manhattan.
Unicom,
Manhattan.
132 to Manhattan.
Okay.
We're in Manhattan,
you have any special instructions?
What unit was this again,
Ken?
132 to Manhattan,
you have any special instructions?
Try
to run the other corner.
Okay,
Third aircraft hijacked heading towards Washington.
No.
Okay,
American Airlines is still airborne.
11,
the first guy,
he's heading towards Washington.
Okay,
I think we need to scramble Langley right now,
and I'm going to take the fighters from Otis and try to chase this guy down if I can find him.
Yeah.
You sure?
Okay,
he's heading towards Langley,
or I should say, Washington.
American 11,
the original guy,
he's still airborne.
We're still getting a position.
Got a position?
Okay.
Foxy,
scramble Langley,
have him towards the Washington area.
Could be a...
We're trying to get a code on this guy right now.
We do have a tail number.
It's a...
Oh,
we're...
It's a...
What was the tail number?
November 3-3-4
Alpha, Alpha.
If we can find him.
We're trying to get...
We're trying to get the mode,
we're trying to get the position on this guy.
Then we'll run out of them.
Yep.
Okay.
Bye.
Thank you.
New York City airports are closed.
We're just learning from our NBC internal file,
as well as for our New York viewers who are familiar with this,
The Lincoln Tunnel is closed as well.
Well,
the Lincoln Tunnel was once the target of a terrorist plot,
so it would make sense to shut that down.
We know that a terrorist organization at one point, about ten years ago, was thinking of attacking the Lincoln Tunnel.
And this obviously is a coordinated...
We're
only on cable.
I think we're off the air.
That's what they were just saying,
they knocked out the transmission.
We have that.
That's Channel 2.
That's a good sized jet to hit the second time.
Israelis could kill everyone over there.
They got the manpower,
they got the bomb,
they got everything.
It's time to loosen the reins.
Yeah,
let them do their thing.
Wow.
Let them do it.
Didn't George W's father have the chance to go all the way when we went to war?
With the bomb,
yeah.
Just go right in and kick it out.
The bushes don't have the chutzpah.
They don't have the balls.
Notice they didn't do this when Reagan was in office.
No.
You need a guy who didn't grow up rich.
Guy who can die like me, who bomb things cuz he's angry. mm-hmm,
I love the bomb. I mean, part of that was, you gotta remember the U.N. And the whatever, the the writs of war that they had said it was to get Iraq out of Kuwait, and that was it. Now,
Bush pulled the plug, he had one more day and he could have finished the dole job. No question his calculation was that is, he brought the world wide sentiment, yeah, against us, blah, blah. And also he'd rather keep that guy in office and have some other guy take over.
Yeah,
because the guys behind him supposedly are worse.
They'll
come home in a minute.
They'll come back.
This is Mixeroff.
All units in Manhattan,
stand by for a mixeroff message.
Go ahead.
Still come.
Requesting send the rest of the fire department to check with the information.
Checked for.
United 93 starting to pick up some lights off at 35.
Any ride reports?
The first complaint I've had. And United 93. Contact the Cleveland Center, now on 33.07.
Saturday.
4th battalion to Brooklyn.
Saturday night,
this is Manhattan.
All units stand by and let's urge you.
Manhattan Mobile Command Unit.
Thank you.
The tower,
there's an evidently very intense fire that's underway,
and I suspect that's part of the reason why you still see very large chunks of the building raining down.
Across,
I'd say,
a good ten...
City blocks,
New York City blocks from that north tower.
There's a parking lot,
which I'm right over.
There are cars on fire that evidently got hit by debris,
and these cars are just burning, untended to the ground.
There's one completely...
Engulfed in flames. And mind you, this is a quite a distance from the this first building. And that those fires began right after the first explosion and then just got exacerbated by this second one. A few minutes, my god, there's going to be another explosion.
Okay, get down.
Jerry, get down, Jerry!
Go ahead and seal com,
urgent.
Go ahead and seal com.
That's right,
I feel, Tom.
Alright,
feel Tom,
number one World Trade Center.
The 103 floor,
southwest corner and northwest corner,
reported to be 100 people overcome at that location.
Repeating,
Stairwell Trade Center,
103rd floor,
northwest corner,
reported to be 100 people in that location.
Also,
Ladder 3 is reporting,
from the
35th floor going up on the stairwell,
they got numerous injuries,
repeating numerous injuries from burns occupied in the stairwells at this time.
Fuel com received.
Yeah,
Dominic,
go ahead.
This is no different than Pearl Harbor.
Absolutely.
There will definitely be a war,
but you're looking at the wrong country.
This comes out of Palestine.
Of course.
Not out of Iraq.
Oh,
I don't know.
We don't know anything,
so.
No,
no,
no.
We didn't say anything about Iraq.
But do you see the way that plane goes into the building?
Yes.
Those guys are happy to die for their Allah.
Oh,
yeah.
Those are some crazy people.
Your families encourage it.
Your parents encourage you sons to kill themselves.
Well,
that's what I'm saying.
How do you negotiate with people like that?
You can't.
No.
And also the whole argument.
About whether Israel should be there or not is ridiculous.
And they should drag Jesse Jackson back here and pummel him for even talking with that.
Yasser Arafat.
Now,
do you think the plane was full of people?
I'm hoping.
No,
I don't think so.
Well,
they said, if it was a hijacked plane,
probably it was.
Oh,
right,
right.
What do they care, who else is on the plane?
Oh,
my God.
man.
No.
Laneley Command Post?
Command Post,
no.
Thanks.
This is huntress with an active air defense scramble for Qwit 25 and 26.
I repeat,
an active air defense scramble for Qwit 25 and 26.
Air Defense scramble for a quick 2526 scramble immediately time 1324 authenticate Bravo X-ray scramble on a heading of zero
010, flight level 290, Contact Huntress on frequency 234.6 and backup 364.2.
Do all parties acknowledge with initials Langley Command Post.
Langley Command Post,
contact Huntress on frequency 234.6 and 264.2.
Okay,
now...
I'm a giant killer,
copy.
Just give me a call on the landline.
Okay.
Again,
this is all speculative,
Bill,
But are officials there working on the assumption that two planes crashing in the twin towers 18 minutes apart on a clear day,
not an accident?
Hard to believe that they would think otherwise,
but at the moment, they seem just as mystified as we are.
And as I said before,
we do expect a statement from the president,
who is down in Florida,
sometime within the next few minutes.
About 20 minutes later,
after the crash...
Everybody's in the...
I want to
remind our viewers as well that President Bush has just learned of this tragedy.
He was at an event in Sarasota,
Florida.
I believe he was reading to children at the time.
Pushing his education plan.
He has now cut short that trip.
He cancelled his event.
He will be making a statement very shortly and then he will be leaving for Washington.
So we are monitoring that that as well, and we'll bring that to you as soon as we sign.
Well,
I heard I was trying to get on the Williamsburg,
they closed it down.
So I tried to get onto the Williamsburg and the ramp, and I turned my car down a long way street and I got to the stop sign.
I saw one tower on fire.
I said,
my God.
The North one.
The bigger one.
Yeah.
The one that's higher up.
And then.
I saw a plane behind it, with a helicopter following it.
It was way too low,
too close,
it was going over the river.
It was way too low.
Like the Easter or the Hudson?
The
Hudson. Yeah.
And it was coming from behind the tower and there was a helicopter trailing it.
And then by the time I got here,
it was two minutes.
And then, as I'm pulling down the street,
10 minutes later,
we heard another explosion.
Did anybody tell us about it?
I did.
See,
I was having coffee on Humboldt Street,
in the back.
All of a sudden I heard, like,
I don't know,
about a half hour,
20 minutes ago,
when I looked,
I heard like, this bang.
I'm like,
wow.
And I thought it was light.
Yeah.
Or thunder.
And then it's like,
I looked around and I go,
that's weird.
And then I got out and drove and I saw that.
It's a strange thing.
I pull up and they said there was another explosion.
Somebody said,
I think that was debris from the first.
From the first tower,
they said,
Are you sure it wasn't another plane?
Could you confirm it wasn't another plane?
By the time I pulled up,
I put two and two together.
And as soon as I walked up,
some guy said,
a second plane just at the other tower.
And I said,
my God,
I wonder if that's the plane I saw.
The thing was flying way too low,
and why would a helicopter detrain it?
Right.
Holy fucking shit.
Good morning Cleveland,
it's United 93 with you at 350.
Just some light shop here at 35.
Any ride reports?
No,
just a little light shop.
Nothing worse than that.
United 93.
We're going to go right now and bring in Rose Arcee,
one of our producers here at CNN.
She's with us on the phone and has with her a number of people who have escaped the building.
Rose.
Yes,
there's a huge crowd.
I'd say there are hundreds of people on the streets that come from south to north.
I've been really thousands of people that have been running from inside these buildings.
You know,
it's a very heavily trafficked area in downtown the World Trade Center.
Many of them were inside the building when they felt the explosion.
And they say there was just pandemonium.
There was no warning,
no alarms,
no anything.
Everyone just raced from their desks,
ran downstairs,
and now there's a steady stream of folks running away from the building.
Some people saying that they're fearing there'll be another explosion.
And when they saw the second plane...
Convinced that this was dangerous.
There's an absolute flood of folks escaping downtown Manhattan right now.
There's seven things in Manhattan.
Ladder 4-7 in Manhattan.
Ladder 4-7.
On your frequency,
relocating to ladder 6.
10-4,
you're going to call it.
To give you a couple of updates on the situation,
a senior government official...
Has said that the agency,
the FBI, is pursuing reports that one or both of the planes were hijacked in the crash as the result of a s****** mission.
That comes on the heels of last Friday's warning from the State Department about...
Possible terrorist attacks in and in specific reference to Osama Bin Laden. Now we are also learning that, and through WNBC, that airports and the Lincoln Tunnel have been closed, it says. Airports plural. I don't know if that means all three of the New York City airports I would presume it does. that would be Newark, LaGuardia and
JFK Airport.
The Lincoln Tunnel,
which extends from New Jersey to Manhattan,
is closed.
President Bush appears to have canceled his event.
27,
Unicorn ahead.
Alright, Unicorn,
you're unreadable.
Okay,
I'll have with you message.
Alright,
any other units calling?
Battalion 8,
What's going on?
Hey Battalion,
which battalion are you assigned?
Alright,
all units stand by,
Battalion 8,
you proceed.
Which tower are we assigned?
Alright,
Battalion 8,
you're going into number one World Trade Center,
okay?
Number one World Trade Center.
Okay,
that's what
I'm saying.
Okay,
right now what we're running out there is two by zero by two by gun for Langley.
Two tanks.
Okay,
also,
we have the Panther,
four-five,
four-six,
zero by two, by two, by gun,
three tanks.
Let me give you another hint.
Three tanks,
affirmative.
Plus, I have more aircraft available to me if I need it from the software.
Okay,
also,
I have a tanker,
main,
eight-five.
Okay,
got tanker.
I have additional tankers.
Adam McGuire,
KC-10s,
Team Call sign.
I'm not sure on the numbers.
2-2 and
2-3, two KC-10s.
I'm sticking them in whiskey. 107.
Yeah,
and did you get the word that Langley got scrambled?
Yes.
Okay,
we couldn't find the position on the airplane.
We just got scrambled about two minutes ago.
No,
that's...
Okay,
Fo says. Forget the tail chase.
Even though we couldn't find him.
Yeah,
great.
That's great.
Yes,
give me the sticks,
Phil!
All right.
All the units,
call in Manhattan.
Brooklyn to Manhattan.
All right,
Brooklyn units,
call in Manhattan.
Brooklyn Dispatch,
urgent.
People trapped,
5 World Trade on the 8-0 floor.
3 World Trade,
that's the 101 floor and the 102 floor.
Manhattan,
receive.
That's a 10-4.
Receive and acknowledge.
10-4.
Manhattan,
a field,
come.
Undo it.
And Rose,
do you have anybody with you that could talk about being inside the World Trade Center when this happens?
Right now,
honestly,
there are scores of people that are literally running by me.
There's debris on the base of the building that has continued to fall,
even as far as a block.
Away from the building. And what's happened is that everyone seems to have figured out that there's ongoing danger. And there's just a stream of folks running as quickly as they can uptown, away from those.
Understandably,
what about rescue efforts?
I would imagine there's still a number of people inside those buildings.
Well,
right now what you see is there's trucks trying to get through,
and people have actually jumped from the crowd and are trying to help direct traffic to try to get emergency vehicles there.
There is no traffic going in the other direction,
But because of the flow of people,
it looks like some emergency vehicles are actually having trouble getting to the scene.
And from where you're standing,
is there any kind of command center,
any place that people are being directed toward?
Right now, what there is is, there's a crush of emergency vehicles and rescue vehicles,
but they don't seem to be quite organized in any direction.
There's
there's fire department vehicles on the one side where you see the smoke coming out of the building.
On the other hand,
you see groups of police officers trying to organize the crowd,
and in a more orderly fashion.
I think there seems to be some fear on their part that such a huge crowd of people might injure each other on the way out.
All right,
Rose Arcee on the ground there, near the World Trade Center.
We continue our coverage.
Back up!
Let's go!
Keep going!
Wow.
I've never seen anything like it.
This is the most catastrophic thing.
It kind of feels like...
Pearl Harbor.
Do you feel inside like, almost scared?
Yes.
Almost.
I am.
Yeah.
I just feel bad for whoever's in that freaking building.
If anyone's stuck on top,
forget it.
That's the weirdest thing about working in this city is that New York is always a target.
I know.
Giuliani said that he's made this city terror-free.
Less deaths than ever before in any administration.
Well,
he meant from each other.
You're not going to blame him for this.
What does Giuliani get to do with this?
What are you talking about,
Dominic?
Well,
but the point is that he really has...
You have no control of any of this.
Yeah,
this can happen anywhere.
You would have to treat everything, like the World Trade Center and the Statue of Liberty, like a military base.
You have to put planes around it.
They do already.
And that's the field comp.
All right,
maybe we should go downstairs.
Maybe there's gonna be another plane.
But now let me ask you something.
Now, the World Trade Center has a sprinkler system,
right?
So that's not gonna be able to...
Well, that ain't gonna do anything.
Well, that's for regular fires,
not an explosion.
This is an airplane driving right into the building.
You know how much fuel is on a plane?
Loaded with jet fuel.
So there's nothing that can be done then?
No.
When they build it,
they don't plan on planes driving into it.
No.
This was a movie.
Would you believe it?
No.
I mean,
it would be a great special effect.
Dude,
see,
I thought this was going to happen on Y2K.
That's why I stayed home.
And you should have seen when the fireworks came out.
Out, I was having, like, you know what, you know what? This is our worst nightmare. You knew this was gonna happen one day, and it's happened. Well, it's because we never settle anything, you know, I gotta. We don't, and we don't face the fact that the, you know. And I'm not saying it's the Arabs who did this, I don't know yet, but I'm guessing the
Arab world has to be taught a lesson that we are the boss and you are going to be our dogs and you have got to be spanked. Yeah, it's true, and I'm not being the leader of the...
Thoughts I'm saying, I don't know who did it yet. It could have even been one of our own people like that. No, could have been like one of our own people, it could have been one of our own people. But you want to know something,
Roger, I'm up on the boat deck, looking
United 93,
checking in
350. United 93,
350 roger.
Are they taking the Philadelphia stuff that's airborne already?
If it's airborne,
they're supposedly taking it,
so I'm taking it until they shut me off.
Okay.
All right.
Live with the live pictures as we go.
And we're just now getting word again from the Associated Press, now saying that. The crash of these two aircraft into the towers of the World Trade Center in New York appear to be an act of terrorism.
This they are quoting a U.S.
official.
They do not say which department.
This U.S.
Official was speaking from,
or the authority this official was actually carrying at this particular point,
but they're saying that a U.S.
Official is now saying to the Associated Press,
He is saying at least,
that these two aircraft crashes we've seen...
5915 Go ahead,
science.
I just got a report from the director of Morgan Stanley.
78. Teams have taken the front of the stop,
There's a lot of bodies, they said. The stairway is clear all the way up,
though.
All right,
10-4,
Scott.
What floor are you on?
Zero-one.
48 right now.
Guys,
keep walking,
we're coming up behind you.
I can't believe there's not jets,
you know,
or some kind of defense.
It's not ready to defend.
No,
it takes a while before.
It's closed.
It's sterile.
Yeah,
probably there's nothing in the air,
so if anything is in the air,
it's going to get shot down.
And in fact,
as you mentioned,
President Bush is in Florida today.
We're supposed to have an education event just minutes from now.
That has been canceled.
Our major, Garrett is traveling with the President.
Major,
Maybe you can tell us a little bit more on the president's immediate plan.
Good morning,
Darren.
President Bush...
President Bush,
as you said,
will make a statement here at Emma
E. Booker Elementary School in Sarasota on the catastrophe at the Twin Towers in New York.
Following that statement,
the president will board Air Force One and return immediately to Washington.
We are told by White House officials traveling with the president in Sarasota that he was notified either shortly before 9 a.m.
Or just shortly after.
We don't have an exact moment of the notification of the president.
We believe, his chief of staff,
Andrew Card,
told him of the events in
New York City.
The president has been monitoring them as best as he can.
He was at one moment this morning sitting reading a book to some of the elementary school children. Here, as scheduled.
Reporters asked him if he was aware of the situation.
In New York.
He nodded a bit gravely and said he would have something to say about that shortly.
Sir,
sir,
did you get the explosive?
1-1-10-4
How many units calling?
Call 9 to Manhattan,
Calling 9,
Your Message
Prisoner Chief Barbara,
have all of the units responding to Number 2 Wheelchair
Trade Center.
Report in front of number one World Financial Center,
which is on the corner of
Western Liberty.
All units coming into number two World Trade Center.
We're getting some word now on where the president was when this happened.
We're learning now from the Associated Press that President Bush was apparently reading to children in a classroom in Sarasota,
Florida,
When his chief of staff,
Andrew Card,
mentioned something about this to in his ear.
The president briefly saw him before he returned,
reading according to the wires,
asked what he knew about the planes.
The president is quoted as saying,
I'll talk about it later.
No doubt we're going to be hearing,
I would assume,
very shortly from someone at the White House.
And no doubt we'll also be hearing from the State Department and the Pentagon,
which will apparently have some reaction to what's going on.
It doesn't feel like it.
One thing seems like an isolated incident,
two things seem like a well-planned...
Oh,
clearly.
You know,
and people over there aren't thinking rationally.
They never have.
And to sit down and try to talk to them is crazy.
That's as crazy as they are.
The oil-rich Arab countries don't take in the Palestinians.
They don't want them.
And,
you know,
if this is a case of that,
it's time to end the misery for the world.
I don't think the airport's checking up anyway.
I mean,
you can...
If somebody hijacks a plane and drives it,
how are you going to prevent that?
Yeah,
when they put a gun to your face,
you do what they say.
No,
I'm saying,
how do they get a gun onto the plane?
Plastic guns.
What did you say?
I was coming outside of my apartment in the morning,
and I heard a loud buzzing.
I looked up.
The plane's like maybe 100 feet up.
Went straight.
In the morning,
100.
And just crashed.
The first plane hit there.
Blew up.
Ten minutes later,
I'm standing around, looking.
Another plane,
I didn't see it, but I heard it,
same noise,
the buzzing,
and it just crashed into the second building.
You saw both of them?
I saw the first one,
the second one, I heard it and it exploded, and people,
witnesses.
What did the first plane look like?
It looked like a passenger jet,
a huge 747 one.
What just happened right now?
Were you up,
were you closer?
Oh well, I was closer. And they just told everybody to move back because the building might be collapsing and there might be another plane coming to hit the building.
Attention All units responding into fifth alarm number two World Trade Center.
You respond to Number One Financial Center, West Street and Liberty Street.
Repeating all units going into number two World Trade Center for the fifth alarm.
You will respond to West Street and Liberty Street in front of Number One Financial center.
That's not gonna happen again.
Keep moving.
Let's go,
fellas.
Keep moving.
Oh,
shit.
my God.
Oh,
shit.
We are expecting that statement any moment now.
I can tell you, here in Sarasota, with those traveling with the president,
They are trying to sift through all of the amazing and terrifying both pictures and details as they can get them from New York City,
but no confirmation here from White House officials about what this, in fact, is,
whether it's accident or terrorism.
They are trying to gather information as best they can,
give it to the president,
and trying to keep things on a very calm and even...
Even keel, if possible.
MS.
And on that note,
Major,
it sounds like that exchange of questions with the president came at what would be a sensitive time. If he was sitting in front of a bunch of schoolchildren and not wanting to scare the children.
The PRESIDENT.
Well,
precisely.
And the president has a way of letting reporters know that he's not going to be able to get to the president.
Know that it's either an appropriate time or inappropriate time to take questions. He does that in many different environments, many different situations. Clearly, this morning, with the Smooth, a crowd of children, he wanted to keep an even keel, keep the situation under control as best as possible. He just nodded and said, I'm, we'll
talk about this later. United 93. That traffic for you is one o'clock 12 miles eastbound 370
negative contact,
We're looking at I-93.
Yeah,
that's,
she's right,
it did kind of turn.
Did you say a helicopter followed the second one?
No,
it came in like this,
like she said,
and then it turned like that.
It's just right in the way.
The first one, was it an airline?
No,
it was a big airplane.
That doesn't look like,
that hole in that northern tower doesn't look like a small airplane.
I think they were both airliners.
The second one was definitely an airliner.
I've never seen anything so far with my wife.
You saw it.
I saw the second one.
Hi,
this is Huntress calling.
I was told to give you a buzz for our mission crew commander.
Any information?
I guess. Three aircraft out of Boston are missing,
and apparently two of them have hit the World Trade Center,
and one is en route to Washington.
Did you get that information?
Yeah.
American 1-1 is not the aircraft that crashed.
It is still airborne.
Did you get that information?
That's what we just found out.
We don't know where it is, though.
It's headed towards Washington, was the last known information.
Washington better get on the moon.
Right.
And I don't know,
but somebody's got to get the president going.
This is not good.
They better start looking for this guy.
Yeah,
we just signed off.
I'm not going to say too much right now,
but
I want to give you a heads up.
Do you have any information,
though,
where American one-one is, or anything?
See this guy,
they,
Boston is the only one giving us any kind of decent, freaking input.
Just want to say one more thing to you.
Washington,
I don't know if they don't think this is serious or not,
but they are not,
unless they hear from, like the center,
if you could give them a heads up and let them know that this is
Washington Center.
They're not really,
not at all.
Okay,
sir?
We've got to get a point out on that. American Airlines.
Boston's calling
Washington right now.
While vice President,
I just talked to them.
And I'd have the president airborne,
wherever.
What's up?
Boston has no clue where they are.
And he's going to let Washington Center know that this is very serious.
Good.
He's going to believe that's serious in there.
So...
Hey.
I get a lot long.
Anybody good at math?
Take our last lot long,
and they were doing
290 knots.
Headed towards Washington.
The Z point,
that was the American Airlines one.
Our first Z point,
yeah,
that was the American Airlines.
That was our last one.
John Bussey,
have you anything to add at this point?
Yeah,
Mark,
those flames on the North Tower are getting yet more intense.
They are about half the building wide.
uh...
Where the whole is like, you see them. Presumably they're also behind the remaining people wall of the building. This is a tower that was hit first on. That's correct, correct. I thought that the claims are getting more and more into intent for the now. I have a massive fire on their their hands as well. I'm across the street, underneath that power, in the World Financial Center, just across West Street, uh...
For those who know New York, uh...
Worry in buildings that, uh...
Amex, uh...
Merrill Lynch Hoppenheimer
uh...
You've had, uh...
Offices and headquarters, and they've been evacuating these buildings, uh...
As well, though, they have it basically undamaged by this. The explosion. When explosion happened, I was outside and the debris moved south. uh...
It's this explosion somehow seem to blow material
southward down the island of
Manhattan. And some of that material,
John,
I noticed, was sort of research and papers from Cantor Fitzgerald coming out of...
Now I know that Cantor Fitzgerald...
John and Maria,
I'm going to interrupt you for just a moment.
It's just a gaping hole in the side of the building.
You can hear everything just crackling and popping from the heat of the fire.
Even from out here,
we're out on the Hudson now.
It's just,
it's really,
I mean,
look at the trail.
The trail of smoke just goes all the way out.
This is really incredible.
It's very somber,
very sad.
Go.
All right,
we're working on it.
What did you see?
I was downstairs at the World Financial Center.
We didn't see the first thing hit,
saw the explosion,
saw the glass coming down,
saw the fire.
We were sitting there watching,
saw the second plane come in,
came in low,
directly into the center of the second building,
right through.
Clearly looked like an attack.
I don't know what I got.
It definitely was,
it looked intentional because it came in low and aimed for the center.
It looked like it aimed for the center of the building.
What's going through your mind when you see a prey?
Two crash into the World Trade Center.
All I was thinking about at the time was I was worried about the people.
You started seeing some really disturbing things,
some people trying to get out of the building by jumping.
You saw people jump?
I did see people.
I personally saw about six people and I think that's when I was done and I had to get away.
What's your name?
Keith Coldstein.
Next station is going to be on Patrickville Channel.
Channel 6 has been designated a command tower and an open.
Right now,
where I am in this building is four trucks and two engines.
It's definitely terrorism.
I mean,
what else would it be?
Two planes.
The second plane,
Kelly,
you could see it.
It turned to hit it.
Block for an 89.
Are you watching the Tag-51 out there?
Yes,
I am.
You've got to get him right turned back.
We'll just put him in back direct St.
Louis, and they can put him in whatever they want.
Hey!
Marine.
Yeah,
I've got it.
If Air Canada continues this climb,
can you take him climb to 35 or 39?
I'm back in that 60-41 free-fall.
Doesn't look like it.
No,
it doesn't look like it.
All right,
thanks.
Somebody call Cleveland.
American 1060,
we're at 3700.
We're slowing due to the delays possible going eastbound.
That's American 1060.
We're not going to stay out here!
Lorraine Patterson at Adeline.
I'm at Dex,
Chicago Center, 124.
Center of America,
1060.
You got United 93?
United 93,
yeah.
Descended.
What's that?
I'm just saying,
it looks like he descended there.
United 93,
Verify 350.
verify your deployable 350.
116MF,
out of 39a for 410.
roger.
United 93,
verify your level of 350.
Cleveland.
United 1523,
Yes, sir.
turn 20 degrees, right.
20, right,
United 1523.
United 93 Cleveland.
United 93,
if you're here,
Cleveland Center,
identify, please.
Like,
10 minutes,
but you can see all the way through to the back wall of the right one.
The Northern one?
Yeah.
It's sad to hear people talking about it, too.
I mean,
thousands of people just died.
Tell me about it.
I'm looking up.
It's so weird because I'm looking down at the street below me.
Okay.
Can you bring it up?
Down the mic.
Fire's out of control.
God bless those people.
Bye.
There's another person.
Oh my god.
When they hit the ground,
they're not even describable anymore as people.
No,
they just almost disintegrate.
Shortly before the crash into the into the World Trade Center.
Let's go to Florida.
President Bush has a statement
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a difficult moment for America.
I,
Unfortunately,
we'll be going back to Washington after my remarks.
Secretary of Rod Pace and Lieutenant Governor will take the podium and discuss education.
I do want to thank the folks here at Booker Elementary School for their hospitality.
Today,
we've had a national tragedy.
Two airplanes have crashed into the World Trade Center in an apparent terrorist attack on our country.
I have spoken to the vice President,
to the Governor of New York,
to the director of the FBI,
and I've ordered that the full resources of the federal government go to help the victims and their families and to conduct a full-scale investigation to hunt down and
to find those folks who committed this act.
Terrorism against our nation will not stand.
And now, if you join me in a moment of silence.
May God bless the victims,
their families,
and America.
Thank you very much.
We've been watching President Bush,
who was down in Florida for what was supposed to be an educational event.
Instead,
he is racing back to Washington as we speak.
George Washington,
All the tunnels are closed.
U.S.
Officials are saying this is an act of terrorism.
Let's go now to our David Inzor,
who's on the phone right now,
and give us some more information on what may be at stake there.
David.
Well,
Leon,
I can just tell you that
U.S. Officials are also telling me that this is clearly not an act of terrorism.
Accident in their view, and they do believe that terrorism is at the root of this, they believe this is a terrorist act. However, they have very little other information, obviously law enforcement, a WHO, these who was flying the planes, whether they had in fact been turned
away from their regular flights and so on, so very little information.
David, David, we're going to catch up with. President Bush is speaking.
First,
you can't declare war until you know who did it.
I can think of some people to declare war on,
though.
In general.
We can all go over the list of candidates.
Yeah,
but you're using this as an excuse.
It's not something you do lightly,
though.
I know.
So coordinated.
But,
you know,
this is what we've all known is going to happen.
We're all saying we've been lucky. This hasn't happened before.
It was either going to be the Midtown Tunnel or one of these big targets,
and someone was going to blow it up,
and now they've done it.
I see it.
No,
I was supposed to be on the 82nd floor for 9 o'clock meeting and I'm about 10.
I was about 10 minutes late to get there.
And they're telling me now that planes were going through the
82nd floor area.
So I guess I was kind of covered by somebody up above.
There's no way.
I mean,
I'm late for the meeting.
Somebody told me to be that way.
There's no meeting.
This guy's got something to say.
And your name,
sir?
Steve.
Steve Housh.
Housh?
Yeah,
Steve Housh.
Spelling?
Housh.
H-A-U-S-C-H.
I just,
oh,
man.
I wasn't sure,
I'd say, go with both.
All right,
attention. All companies operating at the fifth alarm for both world trade Centers.
The elevators,
the port Authority reports The elevators on the number 44 floor is about to come down.
All companies operating at number one and number Two World Trade Center at the fifth alarm.
Do not use the elevators.
They're about to come down,
ask for the Port Authority on the number 44 floor.
Field Com,
receive that urgent.
Should we?
Just hang in there.
Just breathe slowly through the towel.
You breathing through the towel?
It's fine.
Everybody's fine.
Everybody's very calm.
Everything's going to be fine.
You just have to stay calm.
Everybody here is calm,
I promise you.
You girls don't even know it because you're in school.
Your parents are here.
They're very calm.
Just keep your head straight.
Okay,
do you see smoke by the window?
The fire department's like,
you can't see?
Do we see smoke?
Smoke by the window,
Fire Department wants to know.
No smoke by the window.
Listen carefully.
At the last resort,
break the window as small as possible, just to get a little air in.
At the last resort.
Okay,
but you foul?
Yeah.
Okay,
how so?
They said The last resort? We should open the window just a little bit to get some air in.
Can you open the window or you have to break it?
Huh?
You have to break it.
Yeah?
Break the window.
Okay,
shimmy,
shimmy.
Break the window.
As little as possible,
just get a little air.
I thought you'd get it.
A little air.
You're running out of air.
We should do that.
Billowing out of the building and how the other building is occluded.
And everybody from this vantage point is,
as Mr.
Russo was saying,
looking at it in horror,
looking at it in fear,
worried about yourself,
I imagine.
Where were you,
sir?
Right underneath it.
Right underneath the trade center when it hit.
Second one.
Both of them hit.
We ran like hell all the way up here.
Did you happen to look up?
Yeah,
we seen the second one run right into it.
We were unloading the truck.
We got right out of there.
Scariest thing I've ever seen in my life.
My life.
Didn't think it was that loud.
Didn't feel that it was.
We were there.
It was loud.
I'm gonna tell you that.
We were right there for both of them and it was loud.
Windows coming down off the building.
This is hoist in the Hindenburg disaster.
The more photos you get,
the more they'll live.
We're going to end the ride at 2-1-K.
Steelcom,
Number 1.
Steelcom.
Repeat that,
urgent.
As for the 430,
the elevators in the number 444,
that's 44,
are about to come down.
Keep all members out,
number 1 and number 2 will trade.
10-4.
Okay,
what happened here?
I'm working the top of
11 Hanover here,
and as we're on the scaffolds up here,
we start our day.
The first aircraft,
it appeared to be...
It could be an accident to me.
The first explosion, and then, you know, everything erupted.
The building went in flames on the left hand side from where I was standing.
Okay,
the second plane approached the building after I came in and let you guys know.
The second plane,
I went back upstairs and the second plane flew directly into the right side of the building.
Hit head on shot right into the side of the building.
I mean, we have a huge hold.
We have a lot of dead Americans.
American people up here.
And we need answers.
We need answers now.
We need answers from the president.
We need answers from our government.
We need to get to the bottom of this.
We need to stop it right now.
We have a lot of dead Americans up there,
okay?
This is a tragedy.
I can't believe it,
man.
My name?
Yeah.
My name is Dwight.
Dwight.
Okay,
Chef.
Chef?
Yes.
Okay,
standby, please.
looks like I have everyone on here except Boston Center.
This is the Air Traffic Command Center in TMO on Duty in the West Area.
I need to have all traffic management units do an inventory,
basically an inventory of all airborne traffic.
Ensure that you do not have any unusual situations or any aircraft they're not accounted for.
If you have any unusual situations or unaccounted for aircraft...
Identify them and contact us here at the command center.
Return to
John Bussey.
I believe you were in the middle of telling us something when that happened.
Yes,
The buildings across the street from the World Trade Center,
which the Wall Street Journal is also housed,
Has Oppenheimer,
American Express,
Merrill Lynch,
several brokerages using this office.
These are being evacuated and they're undamaged from what I can see.
You want me to go outside?
I'm looking up at the building and there is still rain, raining down.
There are fire trucks,
dozens and dozens,
as you would imagine.
But the firefighters are having a hard time getting into the building,
partly because there is so much debris that's coming down.
As Maria noted,
papers were blasted south out of the building.
And I'm now looking out over West Street, onto Liberty Street,
which...
Which is right in front of the world,
the second building that was hit,
the World Trade Center building that was hit.
And it is virtually covered with papers.
The parking lot across the street,
there are cars on fire,
chunks of metal everywhere.
It just,
you know,
it looks like you would imagine.
So these fires continue to flame.
Apparently,
the firefighters are just getting up there because these things are...
Basically out of control and getting much,
much worse.
Yeah,
well...
I have no security.
It's a piece of cake for me.
James,
tell me,
do you want me to wheel race?
Hey,
tactical net back to Boston,
FBI.
Go ahead,
FBI is on.
We have two reports,
preliminary information,
believed to be American Airlines Flight 77 and Flight 11,
flighted with World Trade Center.
Also,
a preliminary report,
United Airlines flight 175 off radar.
No further information.
Okay,
so that's American 77 and United 175?
That's correct.
Have their input of origin on both of those.
Okay,
back to FBI.
It's American Flight 77.
Second flight is 11.
Those are the two aircraft believed to be involved with World Trade Center.
Root is reported as dulles to Los Angeles for 77.
Boston to Los Angeles for 11.
United Airlines is not believed to be involved in World Trade Center.
Center at this time.
Okay,
so it's American 77 and American 11?
That's correct.
American 11 Was Boston to LA?
That's the report I've got.
Okay,
and the other one was Dulles to LA?
Dulles to LAX.
I've got two flights here now.
Okay,
so it's 77 and 11.
That's affirmative.
The other report was regarding United 175.
We had a report that it was off the radar.
Okay,
is that,
where was that United 175 from?
We're getting conflicting reports on that,
FBI,
on the 175.
Where did it go off radar?
United
175.
Stand by, please,
back to FBI.
I've got a report from Eastern,
FAA Eastern region air Traffic that it dropped off radar over Indiana.
And it's United 175.
La Departure,
quit 25,
Missoula 2-I,
on a 4.5 for 2-9-0 runway heading.
Quit 25,
Norfolk Approach,
Roger.
Maintain flight level 2-3-0 for now.
What heading would you like,
sir?
Quit 25,
if you can go eastbound,
heading, maintain flight level 2-3-0.
Quit 25,
Norfolk Approach,
how do you hear?
Quit 25,
check.
Starpro,
Quit, 25, is with you,
climb to 12,000 for 230.
Quit 25,
Norfolk Approach,
roger.
Loud and clear,
how many?
I got you loud and clear now.
Quit 25 roger,
have your third man squawk 4600.
Will do.
Quit 25,
you're going direct to the Langley 090 at 6-0,
is that where you're going?
Affirmative,
That's our second clearance,
as we had an earlier clearance of a vector and an altitude.
Quit 25,
roger.
Giant Killer 256,
Quit 25.
Giant Killer.
Flight of three,
third man squawking right now.
They are direct to the Langley 90 at 60,
climbing to 230.
Clear radar.
No beat.
Quit 25,
contact Giant Killer on 238.1.
Copy,
238.1.
Click push.
Bush there, speaking in Sarasota,
Florida,
cutting short his stop there,
saying that an apparent terrorist attack has occurred on U.S.
soil.
They're mentioning the two planes that have crashed into the World Trade Center this morning.
Says a full-scale investigation is underway to hunt down those
responsible for this,
saying terrorism will not stand.
And,
Leon,
on the heels of the president's remarks,
CNN has learned that. At least one of the planes involved in this hit on the World Trade Center was an American Airlines
767, a Boeing aircraft,
that took off from Boston.
What happened to that airplane as it took off from Boston and how it ended up at the World Trade Center,
our details will have to fill in as we go.
But...
Who's that calling?
Executive 956.
Executive 956,
go.
We were just answering your call.
We did hear that yelling, too.
Okay,
thanks.
We're just trying to figure out what's going on.
Okay,
thanks.
I got the piece to dock.
And keep remaining sitting behind the ball board.
So it's set.
Calling Cleveland Center,
you're unreadable.
Say again, slowly.
John Miller,
what are you picking up on the police radio?
There was a bit of a stir a moment ago because LaGuardia Tower reported urgently that there was another aircraft moving fast in the no-fly zone.
Now they've contacted that aircraft and they say it's a military aircraft that's rushed to the scene to enforce the no-fly zone. And literally be a presence in the area. In case there is another plane headed for the building, so that there'll be some at
least armed aircraft up to confront it.
Hunter's ID,
unsecure line.
This is Washington Center,
the operations manager.
Go ahead,
sir.
Okay,
I guess you had called here a couple times.
You never talked to me,
but if there's anything you need or anything I can help you with,
let me know.
Know where he is right now? Please? Okay, do you want me to let you know what we have going on? Sir? I would? Yes. Well, I have a pretty good idea, but yes, okay. The three aircraft missing out of Boston? I just spoke with Boston and they said that they're not sure of the third aircraft. Call sign, but they do have to. One of them is United 175,
the other one is American 1-1.
They thought that the American 1-1 was the aircraft that crashed into the World Trade Center with the United 175.
However,
American 1-1 is not the aircraft that crashed.
He said the pilot on American 1-1 was talking to him,
having a rough time telling him what was going on.
There was threats in the cockpit being made.
This was the initial hijack information that we got,
American 1-1 to 767 from Boston to Los Angeles.
Proposed rule and he was headed towards
JFK at the time that they lost contact,
but that was not the aircraft headed into the World Trade Center that hit it.
Okay.
That's what Boston's saying.
The last known,
and I'm not sure where we heard it through the grapevine people calling,
is that
American 11 was headed toward Washington.
Type your shot then,
and that's the only thing.
Was headed toward where?
Washington.
Okay.
So,
your AOR,
and I just wanted to give you a heads up.
Okay.
Okay,
go ahead.
The last known lat long that we had,
primary target only was 4038 North.
07403 West on American 11.
Okay.
But again,
remember,
nothing has been confirmed as far as which aircrafts have hit the World Trade Center,
But the other one we have is information headed towards Washington.
Okay.
Let me tell you this.
We've been looking.
We also lost American 77.
Okay.
American
77 was lost.
Excuse me?
Where was he proposed to head,
sir?
Okay,
he was going to L.A. also.
He was also going to LA?
Now,
uh...
From where,
sir?
Uh,
I think he was from Boston also.
Now,
let me tell you this story here.
Uh,
Indianapolis Center was working this guy.
What guy?
American 77 at flight level 350.
However,
they lost radar with him,
they lost contact with him,
they lost everything,
and they don't have any idea where he is or what happened.
So what we've done at the surrounding centers here is to tell everyone to look out for limited codes,
primary targets,
or whatever the case may be.
And that was the last time,
that was about 15 minutes ago, since I talked to the
Indianapolis Center.
Operations manager.
Do you have a tight aircraft,
sir?
That was a 767,
I believe.
767.
Okay,
and uh,
so I don't call Indianapolis unless I have to.
Somebody else is talking,
I'm sorry,
I can't hear you in the background.
Um,
all I need is the lat long,
last known position of the 767.
Well,
I don't know,
that was in the center,
but they said somewhere,
the last time I talked to them,
they said it was East of York.
And I don't even know what state that is.
Okay,
sir,
well, I'm going to go ahead and just give them a call.
Okay.
Thanks.
You can't find Bin Laden.
Can you imagine that?
Come on.
And you know what?
It isn't even bin Laden.
It's the whole friggin'
country.
He could be behind.
Well,
see,
that's the problem.
Why is it safe to be there?
Yeah,
you're right.
I mean,
this could...
Yeah,
forget bin Laden.
He's got money.
Time to just literally say we were just attacked.
What country,
though?
Oh,
you know who that is.
I'll tell you, the country's right off the bat.
We don't,
the CIA should.
I'm saying to you,
listen.
But it's terrorists within those countries, and it is the countries that house the terrorists,
absolutely.
Yeah,
but the government is hiding behind those terrorists.
And I'm sure they'll take credit for it anyway.
Yeah.
Everyone's gonna take credit for it.
Bush needed to make it.
The government of those countries hide behind those terrorists.
You know what,
we gotta wait and see what the deal is.
You can't rush to judgment.
Well,
we could.
It's not like Pearl Harbor.
We knew who the Japanese were.
Yeah,
they at least announced,
we did it!
Wow!
That's what I said.
Dude,
I just can't believe a fucking plane would slam into that building.
God bless us.
We're all still here.
You can hear stuff, just...
Popping and cracking, and...
How far away did you see it from?
And you just saw it come shooting in?
Yeah,
I think it's binoculars or anything.
I've got a close-up here.
You want to grab some binos?
Who?
Binoculars.
What?
To look for Shane.
I can't see.
Bring me some.
No one has been taking responsibility for this.
There have been no claims of responsibility and U.S.
Intelligence officials say they had no warning of anything like this coming along.
Alright,
David.
That transmission,
it was unreasonable.
It sounded like someone said they have a bomb on board.
That's what we thought.
We just,
we didn't get it clear.
Is that United 93 calling?
Center,
Med-X 150.
Med-X 150,
stand by if you would,
unless you've got an emergency.
Stand by.
Roger.
U.S. Air 2657,
Cleveland 125.42.
2542,
you're clear.
Left turn 99 for wind.
Your exact hit 956,
that aircraft we believe was transmitting, is 12 o'clock,
5 miles,
turn left, heading 225,
We'll get you away from him.
Left turn 95 for wind.
1225,
you're set to 956.
16,
Mike Foxtrot,
heading 120 to get you away from that.
Boeing 120,
I'm heading Mike Fox.
561 Alpha Charlie,
flight heading 090.
090,
1a,
Charlie. Roger,
American, 1060,
flight heading, 090.
090,
Roger.
Center,
is that J956,
is that traffic for us again?
Say again?
That traffic we're turning for,
is that about our 2 to 3 o'clock?
Is it 1 to 2 o'clock,
yeah,
or 2 to 3 o'clock as you turn?
Okay,
we got a TCAS,
I think we got a...
Okay,
he's climbing,
so I want to keep everybody away from him.
Okay,
I think we got him in sight.
Delta 1989,
Cleveland?
Yes,
sir.
Delta 1989,
turn right to a heading of 320.
Alright,
Delta, 1989,
heading 320.
Okay,
Delta 1989,
we're gonna go the other way.
Fly heading of 260.
Alright,
sir,
260,
Delta, 1989.
Delta, 1989,
right.
Hello?
What's going on?
Who is this?
Oh,
Aaron.
We're fine.
David is flying today.
He was going to Cleveland.
And, you know,
we can see the whole thing from our house.
And I saw this like a plane crash.
It was very scary there.
And now there are people running down my block.
And I don't know what's going on.
I brazenly cleveland.
I know
I called his secretary, he left here early this morning,
which I knew.
So
now they're saying that the planes were hijacked. And
I know I'm scared very.
I might have the whole thing on videotape.
I think I even videotaped the second plane crashing into the building.
I just set my camera up and turned it on.
It's scaring me now though, because there are people running down my street and I don't know where they're running from.
Like, maybe the subway?
She's gone now.
She always flies American.
Well,
not always,
but it's impossible to know,
Mary.
I don't know.
But I think the bling that were,
one of the bling they said, was a bling from Boston.
It was hijacked in Boston.
So I don't think that they can really hijack it in New York and take it,
you know what I mean?
There's still a great amount of smoke and fire.
And here on the ground,
everybody is very,
very upset.
There are people walking around, holding their hearts.
Women are crying.
Everybody is talking about a conspiracy.
And uh,
and uh,
those airfoils are just in the whole area as well.
I'm just going to paint every plane.
Yeah,
the patient just chopped down.
That's where I have to go,
right here,
32nd floor.
What floor?
92nd.
Oh my god.
I have workers up there.
It looks like part of the air plane wing,
the tail section on the right-hand side.
What if they didn't get on?
That looks like the tail section of the helicopter,
right there.
On the right-hand side.
Oh shit.
What is that?
It looks like the tail section of the helicopter.
Right here.
Sorry.
Oh,
Jesus.
It looks like the tail section of the helicopter.
I'm right here showing you.
Former FBI agent James Kallstrom covered the World Trade Center bombing back in 1993.
He is with us on the line right now.
Jim,
good morning.
Good morning.
You've been watching this.
Talk to me.
I shouldn't say good morning.
It's not a good morning.
No,
i apologize.
Go ahead.
I don't really know much about it,
but it sure looks to me like a deliberate act of terrorism.
I mourn the loss of the lives that
I'm sure are going to follow this.
How are you?
Just look at my eyes.
We were on the
34th floor of this building, right here,
48 Wall Street.
And we heard an explosion.
We went up to the roof and we seen one of the towers on fire.
So we're up there, actually watching the tower on fire.
And another plane comes in and hits the other tower.
And it was like a ball of flame, so big I couldn't believe it.
And actually, you felt it in your face.
And then it was just like both towers are on fire.
Bad fire right now.
Be a lot of, a lot of, a lot of injury in that building.
Michael,
I'm going to otis Elevator.
Where is she?
M-O-R-I-G-I.
Well,
you know what,
the first thing he said was,
I call the vice President.
Yeah,
because the vice president's in charge.
Dick Cheney is running the country.
Anybody who doesn't know that is crazy.
Jim Gartenberg joins us.
He was on the 86th floor of,
I'm not sure which tower,
was it the east,
north,
or south,
Jim?
It's World Trade Center 1,
and it's not was.
I am here,
and I'm stuck right now.
Now,
are you above,
Jim,
or below?
I have no idea.
I have no idea where the plane hit.
It's my understanding that it's a plane.
Jim,
there are two planes.
One went into one tower.
One went into the other tower.
What do you see around you?
I mean,
are you...
In smoke?
Are you in fire?
The first thing that I want to make clear is that I'm stuck on the 86th floor.
A fire door has trapped us,
debris has fallen around us,
and part of the core of the building is blown out.
How many people are with you,
Jim?
I'm with one other person,
and I'm told that people are aware of this.
I'm on the 86th floor, on the east side of the building, facing the East River.
And what time did you get here?
I want to tell anybody that has a family member that may be in the building that the situation is under control for the moment.
And the danger has not increased.
So please, all family members, take it easy.
That's the wingspan right there,
okay?
That's the wingspan.
So it came down this way,
and I was walking this way,
and I was so low.
Yeah,
it was like,
can you stand here?
And you're up.
That's the wingspan.
Yeah,
it was like,
I'm trying to set it to the center.
But it went in this way.
And I was like,
I'm just going to go in slow motion,
and move out this way.
And then the explosion blew out the other side.
The other side.
So that's the soft stuff.
But that is the practical thing.
The size is the problem.
Right.
Next goes an explosion to the other side,
was the biggest explosion.
It went at the second one.
The second building was a smaller one, coming in this way,
like 10 minutes late.
Coming in from like third.
I didn't see the guy standing there,
but I saw him again,
like a small one,
even later.
And I saw it blow out this side back in the second one.
And uh,
right there.
10 o'clock down,
let's go!
I'm gonna go get Nina.
Let's go.
Stop listening up and go.
The buildings are now buckling,
they're saying.
That literally...
Of course!
I mean,
the infrastructure's gotta be...
A Boeing 767 from Boston.
That's not from the chopper,
is it?
Do not go towards the trade Center.
No north.
All civilians,
do not walk towards the train station.
Oh,
it's so scary from here,
I can't even tell you.
I mean,
there's stuff flying through the air.
I totally feel like we're under siege.
I really do.
I could go downstairs.
I'm like a freaking moon now that there are people running in my neighborhood.
Well,
my nanny was supposed to come,
but I assume she's not coming today,
obviously.
You should see this thing on fire.
You can't even imagine it.
I can walk there in five minutes.
I've got a lot of questions for you,
James.
Let me kind of take it through them if I could.
Because you investigated and worked on the original terrorist incident,
I should say the terrorist incident,
back in 1993,
Can you tell me if these buildings have any special significance by virtue of who's working in them?
Well,
I don't think it's so much who's working them.
I think the towers symbolize largely as many other symbols also,
but the World Trade Center is a symbol.
That was one of the original reasons that
Ramzi Yosef and the rest of the gang,
I wanted to do. The World Trade Center as a symbol of America,
so sure, there's other symbols,
but I think this is probably the tallest one on the East Coast.
Again,
all of this is unconfirmed.
We heard the president call it an apparent terrorist attack.
At this moment,
have you any doubt that's exactly what it is?
No,
I have no doubt of that.
I would call it an apparent attack.
I think there's probably an infinitesimal chance it isn't,
but it certainly doesn't appear that it could be.
Commercial airline is number one.
You know,
are not going to direct themselves into a square hit on the World Trade Center.
If there's some sort of a Mayday or something wrong with the plane,
you know,
they're going to try to ditch it elsewhere.
They're not going to do that.
And if the reports of a second plane hitting the building are true,
then I think that probably caps off exactly what this is.
It's a cowardly act of terrorism.
We just had another report,
United 93.
Who is in Cleveland Center's airspace? Somewhere around Dyer intersection, just reported that they heard screaming on the frequency and the people have a bomb on board.
The aircraft departed Newark en route to San Francisco, was the report.
Do you know what type?
No,
I don't have that information.
Okay,
we're still tracking it,
is that, right?
Correct,
we're still tracking it at this time.
Okay,
thanks,
Coach.
All right.
Can we go back to the telephone and Richard Thompson now?
Are you still there,
sir?
Yes.
Again,
you are a licensed pilot.
You were describing to us that you saw what appeared to be a small business jet that was flying,
that came screaming by your office window and went right into the tower.
Exactly.
Being a pilot is the first thing I recognized,
that there was no way that a business jet could be flying at that level. At this time of day. Over the city without special permission.
I tried to crane my head out the window,
but within five seconds before I could open my window and look out,
it already had flown directly into the building.
I mean,
a pilot, I know that you could have avoided that.
At 99%,
if you were in trouble flying that plane,
you could have avoided that building.
And so whomever was at the controls directly flew that thing right into the side of that building.
United
93 may have a bomb on board.
Okay,
United 93. Who's speaking?
Cleveland, Center.
Okay,
Cleveland.
What's his origination and destination?
He's out of...
Out of Newark, going to San Francisco,
his position is 20...
15 east,
actually, he's farther than that.
He's east of Dreyer,
his exact position is 30 miles east of Dreyer.
Ok,
you have a transponder on this aircraft. Or did he go primary?
At this time,
he's code 1527 and we still have a transponder.
Ok,
and can you give me any additional information as to why you believe there may be a bomb?
Because he's screaming that on the frequency.
Okay,
very good.
Thank you.
Anyone else?
All right,
I'm disconnecting now.
WASHINGTON Approach Hey, this is Douglas approach Control,
we're tracking a fast moving primary heading towards the White House.
The White House has been advised.
Alright,
I'll tell them.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh,
let's get out there together and take pictures.
You know,
you might find a hand.
Message Hi Ron, it's me, just wanted you to know I love you and the girls tell my mom to. We're going down to that trade center thing. The second plane, they just crashed into that building, so we're on our way down there. I love you,
Comfort,
he's awake.
Center,
is that Jet 956?
Was that traffic as far as again?
Say again?
That traffic we're turning for,
is that about our 2 to 3 o'clock?
Is it
1 to 2 o'clock,
yeah.
We're 2 to 3 o'clock as you turn.
Okay,
we got a T-Cast.
I think we got him.
Okay,
he's climbing,
so I want to keep everybody awake.
Okay,
I think we got him in sight.
We have another eyewitness on the phone with us, Juanita Soto, in
Brooklyn. What have you been able to see?
Well, we were in the room,
my husband and I.
She stayed up late,
she took a seat in the room.
Could you,
again,
did you see the second aircraft?
Apparently it might have come in from the other direction.
No,
I couldn't see it.
I was looking at the building when it hit,
and I saw my colleague
Tim Lufkin and I saw it hit the building,
But we did not see it fly into the building.
We saw the explosion from it.
And,
again,
I guess we're still trying to figure out,
there are some reports that these planes were hijacked.
The FBI is said to be investigating that.
The one that you saw appeared to be a small business jet?
Yes.
And the second plane was obviously a larger plane because the explosion from the second plane was tenfold larger than the first plane.
Okay.
Mr.
Thompson,
we appreciate very much the information you've given us this morning.
May God be with all those people.
Hunter's ID is coming out.
Can I help you?
Latest report,
aircraft VFR, six miles southeast of the White House.
Six miles southeast of the White House?
Yep.
East.
He's moving away.
Southeast of the White House?
Aircraft is moving away.
Moving away from the White House?
Yeah.
Okay,
but what,
he was a DVFR?
We believe,
we just know it's a VFR aircraft,
we're not sure who it is.
If you want to, hold on a second.
Okay,
copy.
There's people down there looking.
Okay,
copy.
Where was that position?
Six,
six southwest.
Six southwest of the White House, deviating away.
Deviating away.
You don't have a type aircraft,
so you don't know who he is.
Nothing,
nothing.
Or he was a bomber,
so I have no clue.
Hopefully someone in Washington would have a better information.
Okay.
Is this a good number to keep calling?
Yeah,
this is a great number to keep calling.
Okay,
all right.
Washington,
okay,
so it's six miles.
You guys have a primary target only?
We just had a telecom.
We don't have any target at all up here.
We're just on a telecom.
We just heard that and wanted to make sure you got that information.
Okay,
can you do me a favor and go ahead and fill Washington in on this?
I'll try to give them a call.
I don't have a number for them.
Okay,
I'll give you a good number then.
Washington's number is nine.
What is it?
Okay,
their number BSN is.
What was New York's?
New York's number that we've got for them is...
Oh,
you don't have a DSN for them?
No,
I don't have a DSN for New York.
We have a shot line.
Okay,
I got that already.
Okay.
They do have a DSN.
Do you have an update on the DVFR,
sir,
that was 6 miles healthy?
No information on it at all.
You'd be better talking with Washington.
Or a deviating...
Deviating.
I'm sorry,
sir.
It's a deviating aircraft, or it's a DVFR.
Okay.
That's what you have?
No,
no,
sir.
On the one that was six miles southeast of the White House?
Yeah,
southwest.
Southwest?
Yeah,
southwest.
Okay,
southwest of the White House.
Was he a DVFR?
You don't have any codes on him,
but was he an actual deviating aircraft?
Well,
I guess they believe now he might have been a deviating aircraft.
You believe that he's a deviating aircraft?
Yeah.
Okay,
copy.
Get more out of Washington and Woodson.
Okay,
copy.
Okay?
Just pass the information.
Okay.
United 93th able to cross the clock trip, please.
What is the best place for him to be?
You're going to ask me questions?
Yeah,
just go ahead.
Stay there.
Come over to the...
Just look at me.
Relax.
Okay?
Go ahead.
First thing,
just tell me...
Tell me your name and where you work,
what you were doing here.
Went straight into the north side of the World Trade Center.
And it kind of went in with slow motion.
It looked like something out of a movie. Where explosions just kind of bubbled out the north side, where it impacted,
and then a huge explosion blew out the south side,
and then little explosions went out east and west.
And,
I mean,
it was just huge explosions.
You were walking down the street,
and you saw the plane collide with the building?
First thing I heard.
Was an airplane flying really low and I thought that had to be a fighter or something to be flying that low.
And I looked up and it's a huge passenger airplane and it's kind of tilted on its side.
And I thought,
you know,
there's no way that that thing's going to miss the building.
Or,
you know,
it's either going to swerve left or right because it's too low to miss the building.
And
I just couldn't believe it when it went straight into it, and it was obviously intentional.
And then,
you know,
ten minutes later,
a second plane coming from the other direction hit the other building and blew out the other side.
You know,
I just saw the explosion coming out the second building.
About 10 minutes later,
but...
Could you see what kind of jet it was?
Were there any markings?
Was it an airliner?
It looked like an airliner.
The first one,
I didn't see the second plane.
The first plane looked like a jetliner.
Like a 737, you would get at the airport with engines on both sides.
It looked like something,
any normal jet,
like a 737, maybe.
You said it looked like it was intentionally headed for the building.
What makes you say that?
Was there no smoke or could you tell the plane was in distress?
Well,
the engine was making a lot of noise,
but I think that was more because of the dive it was taking.
It didn't look like there was smoke or anything.
It just looked like it was coming straight south and then it veered.
You know,
you can see the cut of the incision into the building is sideways,
so the plane was slightly on its side,
and that's why it made me think maybe it was in distress.
But then when it obviously hit...
Yeah.
There was almost no doubt that it was intentional.
You were walking in the neighborhood.
Was there debris flying off or people on the street hurt?
I wasn't that close.
I was about five blocks away from where I saw it.
But what we did see for the next five minutes were people jumping out of the building in suits.
And even 10 or 15 minutes after the first explosion,
people were still jumping.
It was unbelievable.
What do you mean, people jumping out of the building?
You would just be looking at the building and you would see some debris kind of
flickering down,
but then you could clearly see people in suits jumping from floors above.
And
I don't know if people jumped from below where it impacted,
but definitely from where the hole is,
people were coming to the edge and just jumping out.
And I saw like three people.
People around me saw like at least ten people jumping out of that building.
I mean,
that's about 70,
80 floors up.
You're saying they jumped from the open hole?
I guess they saw there was no escape.
I mean, that's what we saw.
I don't know if people were falling out by mistake or jumping on purpose,
but it was pretty incredible.
Thanks for talking to us.
We're the leaders in the world.
We have all the technology to spank these douchebags and fix them for once.
We've been lenient.
We're too liberal.
We're trying to let everybody solve their own problems.
When parents are too liberal,
the kids get spoiled.
I thought this show was going to be a good idea.
Come on,
I'll just go right down the middle.
I'll go right down.
No!
What?
That light?
Right at the very edge.
Yep.
On both sides.
Just a little below the
You see anything?
No. .
2940 Manhattan,
All units stand by on the search.
Manhattan calling field com K.
Manhattan calling Field, com.
Steelcom,
go ahead, man.
Alright,
Steelcom,
you ready to ride?
I got 4 of you to check in both Building 1 and Building 2.
Everything we have up to now.
Ok,
give me building 1.
Building 1.
92 floor,
the 106th floor,
the 89th floor,
104th floor,
the 100th floor,
the Northeast side,
the 88th floor,
the 82th floor,
East side,
the 105th floor,
the 68th floor,
106th floor,
northwest,
103rd floor,
room 103.
Room 8311.
Let me know when you're ready for building two.
Proceed with building two.
Okay,
The 82nd floor West side,
the 88th floor,
89th floor,
73rd floor West side,
105th Floor East side,
104th Floor East side,
47th floor,
73rd floor,
West office,
83rd floor,
room 8300,
and 80th floor northwest.
That's what we have at this time.
Okay,
I'm received.
Thank you.
In New York City,
President Bush has mentioned this as a possible terrorist act.
We have people on the ground telling us they have terror in the streets in Lower Manhattan.
People panicking,
people crying.
One witness has told us he saw a couple of...
Difficult building to extraordinary, obviously, because of the height of the buildings. But the plans in place for evacuation are. Are they, from your experience, state-of-the-art?
I think they are, I think. The whole security of that building, both from a physical security standpoint and from an evacuation standpoint, was certainly reinvented and looked after. After that tragedy that happened
back in the early
90s, and they're probably as good as they could be.
But having said that,
you're talking about one of the tallest structures, or two of the tallest structures in the United States,
and whether or not the elevators are working,
they're probably not.
They're not used in case of fire.
You've got a massive evacuation problem on your hands.
Let's see the film,
man.
It's fucking nice and slow.
Go for a 06.
Traffic is 11 o'clock and 5 miles northbound.
Fast moving type and altitude unknown.
Go for 06.
You have the traffic.
Do you know what kind it is?
Can you see?
Looks like a 757,
sir.
A 757.
Can you estimate his altitude?
Looks like he's at low altitude right now,
sir.
Go for 86,
thank you.
But it was self-inflicted, without attacking any target.
Here, we have a precise use of the airplane, basically as a bomb.
And this is very new in the Arnold.
Of terrorism,
particularly in modern times.
Professor Vianoff,
may I ask you,
if we compare this with the earlier incident in 1993,
you're talking about? In there? A situation where terrorists allegedly rented a rider truck,
drove it into an unguarded basement,
a garage, rather,
and then blew up the explosion.
Here, you're talking about a lightning increase in terms of the sophistication,
the technology,
and the coordination needed to mount this type of an attack.
Given that,
wouldn't it be likely that you could eliminate many of the smaller groups and concentrate?
Could this be, in fact, the act of a government,
an adversarial government?
I
came from Boston.
Oh,
we're good.
Turn and burn and crank it up.
All right,
here we go.
This is what we're going to do here.
A monster of a motor.
Okay.
What happened?
From FAA.
Is that airliner?
No.
Run them.
This is team 2-1.
Do you want us to relay?
Authorizing FEO right now?
You want to authorize it?
I can't get through.
Yeah,
we're hearing them loud and clear.
What are we doing?
We're going direct to East City.
No,
I'm getting FEO.
Unbelievable.
Really?
Bridges,
the tunnels closed.
No air traffic.
Helicopter traffic can get anywhere near the World Trade Center.
The TV helicopters,
our Chopper 880,
no one can get close at this point.
The airspace around the city.
Our question here is,
our aircraft that we have has climbed,
turned,
and is not top.
Talking to us.
So do we want to scramble?
We've got a couple of local military here.
Okay,
that's a decision that has to be made at a different level.
Or is someone talking about it, at least?
What's the call sign again?
It's United 93.
He's right over Cleveland.
Over Cleveland now?
Yeah.
Okay,
we'll call you right back.
Would it be highly unusual,
Mr.
Kallstrom,
for these attacks,
if that's what they were,
to have taken place without some degree of advance warning?
Well,
I don't know the answer to that.
Obviously,
the FBI and law enforcement,
the people that come to work every day and suffer through immense criticism when little things go wrong,
these are the days that everyone hopes that they have a very formidable,
highly motivated FBI and law enforcement team.
And
I suspect we do.
And these are the things that they try to not have happen.
These are the things they try to have the intelligence to avoid happening.
International terrorism,
if that is what this is,
and I don't know what it is,
is very hard to penetrate. Because it's not very,
it doesn't have a hierarchy of authority,
and it's cellular,
and it's a lot of different people, motivated for religious-type reasons,
hatred reasons,
And you can necessarily not know a lot about what's going on in an agency if you're in it at some level, because it's so segmented.
That traffic for Gopher 06 is still on.
Descent down northeastbound.
Alright,
thank you.
SWAN,
Swan 91.
Gopher, 86,
climb and maintain a...
You got a military?
Yeah,
stand by.
Gopher, 86,
turn right and follow the traffic, please.
turn right,
heading 080,
we're gonna back to you for the traffic.
Okay,
080,
Gopher,
let's go.
Dallas,
I'm keeping the Gopher 06 with me for a while.
What is somebody waving?
There it is.
Yes.
Do it.
Someone's waving at us.
I have no fucking chance to get the fuck out.
See?
You see it waving?
Did you get it?
You see the hand holding it?
Just keep it up.
Keep it.
Zero.
I don't know what's going on after this.
Who did the stun hit?
Maybe it's like a...
Wow,
that guy's got a fire on his head.
He's going back in.
Oh,
I see.
Come on,
come on.
Come on.
Oh,
just blew up.
You see that blow out?
That's a shot.
There's another soul around here,
bro.
No.
I think he's hanging on something.
It's being lowered.
He's getting low.
He's in a clear,
uh,
finish.
Very far.
Oh,
he's getting low.
There we go.
See that thing falling?
That's a man.
See?
See him?
Yes.
You got him?
Another body.
Traffic is out of 41,000,
outfinding.
All right,
we're down here in Soho.
As a matter of fact,
you're looking at a picture from Prince and Worcester Street,
and on the ground, you can see what has happened all over Manhattan.
People are stopped and they're staring.
They're looking up and they're trying to figure out all of what's happening.
In talking to some of these people,
I met someone,
Philip Russo,
who actually witnessed the whole thing.
You were driving east on Bleecker Street,
that's correct?
That's correct.
I was driving east on Bleecker Street.
Have you step around this way,
put it on the background.
I heard what sounded like a jet flying very low.
I looked up,
I saw a blue and white jet,
two engines,
going obviously in the wrong direction.
You were thinking jet,
you were thinking 737,
something like that,
a large jet.
A large jet,
a large commercial jet,
but with no markings that I could identify other than blue stripes on a white plane.
It sounded too low,
I looked up,
it looked too low,
going in the wrong direction,
and I followed it into the building.
Flew straight into the building?
Flew straight into the building,
dead on,
disgusting sight.
Then you continued to look up at the building and you saw the second jet.
Well,
then we were looking for about five minutes,
just in horror at what happened,
saw a second jet coming from the west that looked identical,
both in color and in form,
and it smashed right into the second building.
Huge explosion on this side facing us.
Now we're all standing out,
we're staring at the building,
all of us,
in horror.
Yeah,
it's the only way to describe it,
horror,
sadness,
disgust.
You talked about fear and being scared.
Yeah,
it's going down.
The fire goes up.
Where'd you come from?
Came in from Grand Central.
Squad
401 to Manhattan.
Squad 401,
stand by.
Alright,
I'm going to have to announce something.
As for the citywide tour commander,
all lost duty firefighters and all lost duty officers,
you are to report to your check the station and wait for further instructions.
Repeating,
all lost duty firefighters and all lost duty officers,
you are to report to your check the station and stand by waiting for further orders.
Oui.
In Sarasota,
Florida. now,
Major Garrett joins us.
Major,
what are you being told?
Hello.
President Bush has notified,
untalked, rather,
to Vice President Cheney.
He has talked to the FBI director, Robert Mueller,
and he has also spoken with the governor of New York,
Governor Pataki,
about this catastrophe.
The president will convene a national security meeting upon his arrival.
Back at Washington.
Those are the four pieces of information we have gathered here in the moment since I just spoke to you on the telephone.
The President,
as we just saw a few moments ago,
identifying this as an apparent act of terrorism against the United States,
said there will be a full investigation.
The entire apparatus,
the United States government,
FBI,
National security,
CIA.
The vice president,
who you may remember,
was placed in charge of a domestic terrorism study group within the White House. To monitor and develop plans to deal with a catastrophe of just this kind.
All those parts of the government have been mobilized.
The president...
All off duty firefighters.
And all off duty officers,
you will report to your check the stations for a total recall and wait for further instructions.
That's part of City watch.
All off duty officers,
you are here by total recall.
We report to your, check the stations and stand by.
And in fact, that was the second explosion that we had seen, with the second plane going into Tower number three.
I don't know,
I'm trying to say we should stay here.
I think we're pretty stable.
If it falls, it would hit us.
If it fell our way, it would hit us.
Yeah,
I don't know.
they took over like a dominant work.
Welcome to New York.
The police are now investigating the incident.
Again,
I'm getting a report now that it was a United Airlines plane that plowed into the building.
We don't know whether that negates the American Airlines reported hijacking or whether or not that was a second plane.
So at this point,
we're getting different reports.
Go ahead,
Mr.
Kelfman.
Yeah,
I mean,
you're telling me that,
Brian,
if that is a commercial airline,
a United or American or whatever it is,
you know,
that...
I mean,
my initial thought there is that this plane was somehow commandeered by somebody.
hijacked,
taken over,
and flown into the building.
I don't know that for a fact,
but that's certainly what it looks like.
Yeah,
as I'm looking at the second tape right here,
and I don't know if you're watching on the line. With us,
that is definitely a commercial-sized aircraft now that we've blown it up in size.
You know,
it's beyond belief,
but it's not beyond belief.
I mean,
we've seen this hatred find its way into the...
Embassy bombings in Africa.
We've seen this hatred at the U.S.S Cole.
We've seen it at the World Trade Center in 93.
We've seen it around the world in acts that take place almost every day.
And,
you know,
for this to then transform itself into this size of an incredible tragedy,
to me,
although I certainly would never expect it,
never, ever want it to happen,
is not that unbelievable.
Yeah.
James Kallstrom,
Let me ask you to sit tight for a second,
if you would.
They
want the Empire state building safeguarded.
I'm sure everybody's out of that building.
No,
they want,
but I'm saying they want everything safeguarded.
Yeah.
Copy.
The first one you can look at and say,
well,
it was an accident.
The second one,
you can just immediately change the whole thing.
All right,
let's do it again.
I'm trying to bring me up there any higher.
I'm on the 40th floor.
What can I do for you?
We're going to have to host it.
Attack 1 to attack 1-Alpha.
Battalion 7,
I don't want to follow through.
What's more...
All right,
I'm going to try to get a couple of CFRD engines on the 40th floor.
If they send any victims down here,
I'll start up the staging area.
Okay,
I'll find Mr.
S.
Elmer,
who works for the party.
If he gets some more cars in those banks,
he'll be all right.
I can't go.
We could go to different sites.
I think it's because...
We had the first one in the middle.
We were right up here.
We were under it.
You know,
it was century 21.
We're across the street.
We were like,
well,
not down.
We were like a block down.
We were like, by the first one,
not the second one.
But we were just across the street.
I was stupid to go down there.
.me. Like we...
Jane,
we're just getting a report that there's been an attack on the Pentagon.
This is the Pentagon.
This is from the network.
This is the Pentagon in Arlington,
Virginia.
This...
These are pictures that have just come in to us here at News Channel 4.
You are looking at live pictures of what appears to be an attack on the Pentagon.
Um,
we can tell you nothing more than what you are looking at.
this...
This is approximately an hour ago that we had one airplane crash into the northern of the
World Trade
Center towers, and about 18 minutes later, another airplane crashed into the southern of the towers. And now we have this.
We also hear that the first plane that hit the World Trade Center was apparently hijacked after takeoff from Boston.
That means there's a very good possibility that that plane did have some passengers on board.
Um.
Senator,
did you hear the 10-6 was here?
Probably just said he had a bomb on board.
Say again?
Is that United 93?
Senator,
United...
United
636, Go ahead.
Yeah,
yeah,
there was a,
they said that the fuselage must have been insider fuel or whatever that blew up again.
Oh,
we're okay.
So.
Keep moving,
everybody's got to keep moving,
please.
Washington.
Washington,
Hunter.
Boston just called us.
They said that they had information about some aircraft that was six miles southwest of the White House that appeared to be deviating.
Boston does?
Boston called and said that I'd have to get the information from you on it.
They don't have a call sign for the aircraft.
They don't have any codes for the aircraft.
They just know that there's one that's six miles southwest of the White House.
Okay.
Well,
Boston's airspace doesn't even come close to that.
I don't know how they got that information,
but we don't...
Hey.
She's here.
Okay.
Okay,
we don't know anything about that.
you don't know anything about that.
No,
we do not.
And it's probably just a rumor,
but if you might want to call...
National or Andrews,
somewhere like that,
and find out.
But we don't know anything about that.
Probably.
Okay,
bye.
Bye.
Mark,
I hate to make reference to another movie at a time like this,
but,
you know,
sometimes life does imitate art.
When I was standing outside on the other side of the World Financial Center and this first explosion occurred,
I heard what sounded like jet engines coming.
Coming in low were not too far from National Guard Center. Sometimes these planes come down the Hudson and buzz the uh...
The Statue of Liberty. A bit, I thought, that's what it was. And tell this massive explosion, which at first sounded like a sonic boom. Then I looked up
and there was debris raining down out of the sky. Like scenes,
unfortunately,
from the movie Armageddon,
where,
you know,
asteroids hit
New York City and pieces of buildings get blown out.
It was,
in fact,
just that dramatic as these chunks of the building fell down onto the street.
Yeah,
it is incredibly dramatic.
Now,
understand, you still want to go for 06 Descendant 2000,
sir.
Gopher 06,
You can maintain 3000 and turn left heading 270.
Okay,
left.
Gopher 06,
approved as requested.
Gopher, 06.
Gopher 06,
okay,
they're asking if you would go ahead and move away now. Towards the west,
270 heading and 2000 for now.
Roger,
we're climbing at 3000.
Alright,
thank you.
Yes.
And Washington,
this is Gopher 06.
Gopher 06,
guys.
Yes,
sir,
that aircraft...
Gopher, 86,
Thank you.
Descend and maintain 2,000.
Okay,
we're down to 2,000.
And this is Gopher 06.
It looks like that aircraft crashed.
Gopher 86,
Gopher
06, Thank you.
Yeah,
it's tougher for people on tragedies.
Do you advertise through it or not?
God.
But yeah,
she called her family.
I was able to get through to mine before it became overloaded.
And all the airports are closed.
And did you hear that? The second plane...
Hey,
Dulles here.
Listen,
the eastern region has us on the phone, and they ask that you be on a continuous hotline with the White House if you're not already doing it.
We're doing it.
Thanks,
man.
The whole floor is floating.
Oh yeah.
It's coming out all around the whole floor.
.with. The President,
he would make a statement.
Before that statement,
he was actually sitting down with some children here at the elementary school,
reading them a book.
The reporter asked him if he was going to the Twin Towers.
He nodded and said he would talk about it momentarily.
In fact,
he did.
He just read the president's statement, declaring this an apparent act of terrorism
But on the first tower and would therefore create much more of a zone because fire naturally tends to travel off.
That's correct,
Mark.
It is the hole that I see,
at least,
out of the south side of the building,
which I believed was the exiting wound to the building,
not the entry point of the building.
If you're looking at the south side,
that would be the exit point,
yes.
That's right,
because I saw,
as I was waiting to speak with you,
I saw this explosion go out from the south side of the building.
It likely entered the other side.
It is,
as you point out,
several floors below the other structural damage to the building,
to the North tower.
But the flames so far,
while I can see them in the South tower,
they're nowhere near as intense and as engulfing as they are in the North tower.
Yeah,
that's what we're looking at on TV.
And I just want to make sure that,
you know,
we are only seeing roughly half of the surface of each building as we look from one direction.
But the South Tower...
So far,
does not appear to have broken out in the kind of raging fire in the North Tower.
And again,
at times like these,
I just marvel at the firefighters who are actually going to go up there.
I mean,
there is just a massive hole in the side of the World Trade Center.
That looks like an airplane.
Yeah,
I mean,
it is just unbelievable.
Yeah,
it is.
I went to believe it,
but I didn't see it.
I mean,
that's second chance.
Chris,
it's getting worse.
the smoke is getting worse.
I think we should go.
Look at the smoke now.
All of a sudden,
it got much worse.
Yeah,
there was another.
We're going to go for it,
just to make sure.
I don't know if there was another explosion,
but the smoke is much,
much worse now.
All of a sudden.
Okay,
well,
I'll give you a call.
Bye.
Do you think we should leave the apartment?
Richmond unsecured Line,
How may I help you?
Collins Coggins,
Boston Center Military.
Yes, sir.
Third aircraft,
Delta, 1989.
Okay,
give me...
Delta, 1989.
Okay,
type aircraft.
Type aircraft?
Yes, sir.
Code,
can I give you a code?
Yes,
give you the code.
1304,
presently due south of Cleveland.
Okay,
Heading westbound,
destination Las Vegas.
And is this one a hijack,
sir?
We believe it is.
Are they going to squawk hijack?
I don't know.
They're squawking 1304 now if you want to try to track him up.
Okay,
type aircraft is what,
sir?
Type aircraft on that Delta?
Delta 1989,
I think he's on there.
767.
And altitude?
Yes,
please.
350.
350,
okay,
copy that.
And where did he take off out of,
sir?
He took off out of Boston.
Boston?
Yeah,
we'll try to get to a tail number on that if you want.
Alright,
copy that.
Do you have any chance to know what's on board?
Uh,
no,
we don't have any.
You don't have any of that.
There you go.
Copy that.
Thank you,
sir.
Okay.
Do you want me to read it?
I'm gonna make a...
We're gonna try to get to a tail number,
okay?
Okay,
thanks.
Bye.
Um,
Brian Jenkins,
a terrorism expert who's been with us quite a few times,
as I understand,
on the line.
Brian,
you there?
Yes,
I am.
Talk to me.
Well,
obviously,
you know,
we don't know the details of what happened yet.
We should have details coming out fairly quickly,
though,
as to the identity of this aircraft.
We're talking about crowded airspace in New York, with major airports in the area,
both in the immediate area of New York and in the surrounding cities.
There should be information fairly quickly that will identify these particular aircraft.
And indeed,
we should be able to confirm fairly quickly as to the identity of the jet. And perhaps even some last second broadcast that may indicate.
Okay,
go fucking super.
You need to be.
I don't care how many windows you break.
Finally,
I've moved to the other side.
Why'd you go up there?
Because the guy pushed out of my house.
Damn it.
Okay,
push him back.
This time,
it's going to be a surprise.
It's going to be a surprise.
Thank you.
Captain,
I would like to go on the board and I'm going to the next board and remain quiet.
Okay,
it's United 93 calling.
United 93,
Understand you have a bomb on board,
go ahead.
And center,
executive,
956,
that was the transmission.
Executive 956,
Did you understand that transmission?
Affirmative.
He said there was a bomb on board.
That was all you got out of it also?
Affirmative.
Roger.
United 93,
Go ahead.
Many people discounted them,
but at least the embassy personnel got warnings for that one.
Mary,
let me interrupt you if I may,
and please stand by.
We're going to join WNBC's coverage right now as we see the thick brown and black smoke billowing from the twin Towers.
A few moments ago,
like there was an explosion of some kind here at the Pentagon.
We're on the e-ring of the Pentagon.
We have a window that faces out toward the Potomac,
toward the Kennedy Center.
We haven't been able to see or hear anything after the initial blast.
I just stepped out in the hallway.
Security guards were herding people out of the building,
and I saw just a moment ago, as I looked outside,
a number of construction workers who have been working here have taken flight.
They're running as far away from the building as they can right now.
I hear no sirens going off in the building.
I see no smoke.
But the building shook for just a couple of seconds.
The windows rattled and security personnel are doing what they can momentarily to clear this part of the building.
Again,
I have no idea whether it was part of the construction work,
whether it was an accident or what is going on.
We're going to try to find those details and get them to you as soon as possible.
But interestingly enough,
one intelligence official here in the building said when he saw what appeared to be the coordinated attack on the World Trade
Center, his advice was to stay away from the outside of the building today, just in case
United 93 go ahead.
Jet 9 56
turn right to a heading of
140. Turn right to 140 for 956.
Is that aircraft going East now?
Say again?
Is that aircraft,
you can't get a hold of it,
Has he turned to the East now?
He just turned to the east also.
Get the familiar engine,
also.
And like I said,
we should hear from Mayor Giuliani in the next couple of minutes.
But again,
to reiterate,
we know nothing about what happened to the people who work in those floors,
in those buildings.
So we are simply waiting to find out about injuries and casualties,
if indeed, that's what happened.
I'm getting it from this way.
You see my shot?
If you want to get a different angle.
Okay,
she's been located.
He's gonna meet us at Chelsea.
Here,
I had a radio contact.
Roger that.
Thank you for telling us.
Inside the potential tie-up up here at Chelsea.
Roger that.
If I'm asking you to repeat something,
I'm having a little trouble hearing you.
Do we know exactly where the president was,
when he was told?
He was just arriving here in Sarasota at M.I.E.
.Ilker? Elementary school.
He had taken an early morning jog this morning in Sarasota,
had just arrived here with a presidential motorcade.
Then the spectacular,
horrific pictures began appearing on television sets here at the elementary school.
The president received a telephone call from...
Condoleezza Rice,
National Security Advisor.
Then he received an update from his chief of staff,
Andrew Card,
traveling with him.
Then it was made clear to the press traveling with the president, he would make a statement.
Shortly before that statement,
he was actually sitting down with some children here at the elementary school,
reading them a book.
Reporters asked him if he knew about the situation of the twin Towers.
He nodded and said he would talk about it momentarily.
In fact,
he did.
We just heard the president's statement declaring this an apparent act of terrorism.
Yes?
Oh!
I mean, that helicopter got me.
It was standing right here.
And then you saw it crash?
We didn't see the first thing.
It was an explosion.
We were like,
Oh my god,
we're going to be on fire.
And then,
like 20 minutes later,
it was like 10 minutes later.
I saw the actual phone going up.
Where's it going up?
It just crashed over here.
It went in?
Yeah.
What's going on?
There's no one in there anymore.
No.
We're looking for the first one that goes up there.
Oh,
that's what they said.
That's what they said.
What did they say?
Another plane might be coming,
so...
Now again,
nobody has any indications of exactly what happened,
but it appears that there has been some kind of,
it felt like a small blast of some kind.
Again,
the window shook,
the building...
The building shook,
the windows rattled,
and people,
if
I'm looking out the window now,
and the construction workers are still keeping a good,
oh,
I'm sorry,
the construction workers are still keeping a distance,
that's all I can see.
And I see no other extracurricular security activity right outside.
But to get more information,
I'm going to have to break away and walk down the hallway and see what it is. Exactly that happened here just a few moments ago.
Washington.
Washington, DC.
Once again,
this is your fire safety director.
The building is evacuated.
If there's anyone on the floor,
if there's anyone in rooms,
you need to come down to the lobby to be evacuated from the building.
Once again,
the building has been evacuated.
We ask that if anybody is on the floor,
employee or otherwise,
come down and evacuate through the lobby.
This will be the last announcement.
Again,
please,
if there's anyone on the floors,
if there's any employees in the building,
please evacuate through the lobby.
We're not west of it.
We're trying to find a spot where we can see it from the west side.
And hopefully get it there.
What happened?
Mr.
Jenkins,
I'm going to interrupt for just one second because we're getting word that they are evacuating the White House.
uh...
Down in Washington right now, well, this would have been through. This is not surprising. I mean, first of all, uh...
And and and action of this magnitude is something that, uh...
uh...
Does suggest a great deal of planning and preparation.
Thank you.
United 93,
you're here, Cleveland Center.
American 10-6,
you can contact 9-56,
We just lost a target on that aircraft.
9-56,
we had a visual on him,
just stand by.
You have a visual on him now?
We did,
but we lost him in the turn.
We'll just make a quick...
Well,
I had a 37 aircraft right behind you, on a vector also.
That may be who you saw.
Do you have a visual on him now?
Executive 956,
If you can make a turn back to a 220 heading,
let me know if you can see him.
Yeah,
he's still there.
We got him for 956.
He's still there?
Is Northwest to be about 25 miles?
Affirmative for 956.
They
want to know how much fuel we have,
how long can we stay.
Can stay for about another hour before we need to fuel.
I'm so excited to go to the beach.
I'm excited to go to the beach.
United 93,
We spoke about him before.
Yes.
He is reversing course over Akron.
They just lost his transponder.
He's heading eastbound.
What kind of airplane do we have?
Just a second.
757.
The aircraft is descending.
Okay,
he is descending.
Correct.
Heard that.
The second one happened at 9 o'clock.
The first time over there,
that happened like at 8.40.
This one happened at 9 o'clock.
It's two different times.
Playing 20.
Um,
is it what you're asking?
Okay.
Hello?
Here,
Chris,
take this.
Hello?
Who's this?
Who?
Lisa?
From planes?
Yeah.
Where'd you come in from?
How'd you get in?
From me?
Yeah,
they let you in the office?
I didn't even have an idea,
I had to talk to the security.
Where'd you come in from?
From the side.
I mean, from the front.
No,
what trains?
Train rails.
Not from the front.
So no,
are people in the train station,
is it packed?
Yeah,
the trains were all fucked up already.
To be kidding me.
I'm like,
Oh man,
they're not going to believe me again that the train's fucked up.
I swear,
I swear. It was a half hour delay.
Look at the flames on the second one.
Yeah,
how back in the spark...
What if it gets really bad?
Is that gonna...
I mean,
it's...
How do you put it out?
It's a strong structure,
right?
Is that...
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
it's a structure,
but all that shit's just gonna start...
...pounding.
Firecrackers,
I mean.
Wow.
They couldn't blow it up because that was a structural everything.
But if nobody saw any markings,
then there's a very inexplicable and interesting kind of a fire. That's in fact a face.
This is a cessna that can create a 30-story fireball,
which is what it looked like as the second plane flew directly in.
I mean,
a cessna loaded with the same kind of explosion. That made a hole in the side of the pole,
yes,
that could make a giant hole in the side of the pole.
Smoke billowing out of a building in Washington,
D.C.
Oh my
God! We are breaking into the special live coverage of what's happening at the World Trade Center in New York to tell you about something going on right here at the Pentagon.
You are looking at both pictures,
the smoke that you see on the...
Left-hand side of your screen is right here in the Washington area at the Pentagon.
Looks like the helipad area of the Pentagon over towards
395. There were reports of an explosion.
People said the building shook.
They felt the building shake,
and they're evacuating that building.
We're also getting word that the White House may be under an evacuation order right now.
Again,
we don't know exactly what happened here at the Pentagon,
but you can see the result of whatever. It was near the area of the heliport.
Is lots of billowing smoke,
dark smoke,
and workers reported hearing something and then feeling the area rumble.
What do you hear,
Tom?
Indianapolis Center.
Indianapolis Center,
reference Delta 8-9,
Do you have any information about that aircraft?
I wanted to give you a heads up,
this is another hijack aircraft.
Boston to Las Vegas,
he's on a mode. 3 of 1304,
we do have contact via...
What was the number again,
Delta?
Delta 8-9,
It's a 767 out of Boston,
heading to Vegas,
and he's on a mode 3 of 1304.
I have an exact lat-long if you need it.
Go ahead.
Delta
8-9, quick.
4-1-2-1 north,
0-8-2-1-5 west.
Okay.
And just to give you a heads up,
that's all we have right now,
But he is confirmed hijacked.
Okay,
we're not showing him in our system at this point.
You are tracking him,
you say?
We have him on the radar,
sir,
but he is headed your way.
He is headed our way.
Delta 8-9.
Okay,
off Boston to
LAS, right?
LAS.
LAX?
I've got Vegas, or whatever Vegas is.
Oh,
LAX,
okay.
Las Vegas.
Okay,
because we're not showing him in the system anywhere.
he's on a...
Do you have, like, Mode 3 capability or anything?
He's on a 1304 code?
Correct.
Okay,
we'll bring that up.
Alright,
sir.
Okay,
thanks.
We got to Luton?
Go ahead,
this is Chopper.
About one hour,
one hour.
Copy that,
you want us to refuel in half hour.
Heavily defended,
And this plane circling the White House adds to the trauma that people are feeling today,
but we have no idea precisely what that means.
John Miller,
you're listening.
The scene is still in some degree of chaos,
but the police have set up a major mobile...
Point just outside the building and they've set up a tactical mobilization point. The major mobilization point is for the responding units involved in the rescue. The tactical one is actually an armed mobilization point for security
outside the World Trade Center.
Thanks very much.
Let's go to the White House.
Claire Shipman is on the phone.
Claire,
what's that we're looking at?
Well,
that's what we're trying to figure out right now.
All we know is it's a gigantic plume of smoke coming from behind the old executive office building,
and we're told that the White House itself,
the West Wing,
at the very least,
is being...
Okay,
so you don't know who's the one.
What's the third?
Okay,
what's the third one?
The third aircraft?
You guys don't know who's...
We believed it was Delta 1989.
However,
when we asked him to respond to aircraft,
therefore...
And that's the one by...
I don't know if he's a hijacker or not.
I really don't know.
Okay,
well...
I can't confirm that he is.
Okay,
do you remember when we were talking about the aircraft by...
Do you guys have any idea who that aircraft was by the White House?
Yeah.
We had thought, for some reason, to believe it was an 11.
I don't know if we heard that from somebody else, that they had a visual on them,
the American Airlines or what.
We just don't know.
So we don't know.
Which aircraft that was.
So we have three call signs.
We don't know who the third call sign is yet.
So we have two aircraft in the Towers and one in the Pentagon, and we don't know what that third call sign was.
You don't know what the third call sign was?
No,
we originally thought Delta 1989 was it,
but now that we have the third call sign, that means there's possibly four aircraft.
Are you still tracking Delta 1989?
Yes, sir,
we still are.
Is he descending into Cleveland?
Right now,
no.
He's at
28,000 feet,
396 knots.
Still squawking his coat.
Still squawking his coat?
Yeah,
it looks like he's by Toledo.
By Toledo.
So it doesn't look like he's landing.
No.
Okay.
Now he's at 27,000 feet.
He's at 27?
Yeah.
Oh,
and he is at
27? Yes.
Excuse me,
I'm sorry.
Where would he be right now if he was going to be landed in Cleveland?
Would he be descended?
He would be descended now.
He would be descended and speed would be slowing?
Speed would be slowing.
Well,
it looks like he's not going to go there.
It doesn't look like he's going to Cleveland.
Nope.
Okay.
Yep.
This just came over. That says the White House was threatened with a terrorist attack,
a source says.
We have another report from an eyewitness at the Pentagon.
It says it was a huge fireball,
a huge orange fireball.
And another witness said that it might have been a helicopter that exploded.
We've had an AP reporter who says it appears to him to have been a large airliner of some sort.
And we do have reports that,
of course,
the
FBI is investigating.
Reports that it could have been hijacked aircraft that crashed.
As a matter of fact,
the FAA has just now halted all air traffic throughout the United States.
So as of right now,
there are no commercial airliners in the air.
I doubt that that has ever happened before in this country.
I don't think so.
So, again,
we still on fire.
You know, the second one.
That first, I was on fire, too.
Yeah.
You see how the whole is coming down in the second?
A lot of people just have been flying out right now.
Senator Ted Kennedy in Washington.
Chris Plant,
a CNN producer,
is at the Pentagon, where there is a significant fire.
Chris,
you're on the phone.
Can you hear me, okay?
Yes,
I can hear you, just fine.
Tell me what you know.
Well,
arriving at the Pentagon a short time ago...
There was a huge plume of smoke, which continues to rise from the west side of the Pentagon over in the area where there is a helicopter landing zone.
It's along Route 27,
if you're looking at maps of the area.
The building is currently being evacuated.
And police and emergency units are, of course, responding from all around the building and from the local Arlington County Fire Department.
The plume of smoke is enormous.
It's a couple of hundred yards across at its base.
It is billowing into the sky hundreds of yards.
It's impossible for me to say from this side of the building, whether the building itself is on fire or up in flames. Or exactly what caused this.
I did not hear an explosion,
but there is...
There's certainly a very,
very significant fire in this enormous office building on the west front.
The building is being evacuated.
The Defense
Protective Service officers,
the police force for the Pentagon,
are on a very tight string right now.
As I arrived,
I was told at gunpoint...
Chris,
let me interrupt you for a second.
Just hang on.
Don't go anywhere.
American
1060,
we're locking descent if it's possible.
American 1060,
roger.
Plating,
fly heading 180.
180,
sir.
Executive 956,
plating 180.
Okay,
we're making a turn at 956.
He appears to be heading right towards us.
Say again,
sir.
He appears to be heading towards us.
We're in the right turn to 220.
Exjected 956.
Make it a 180 heading, then.
180 on the heading 956.
Exjected 956.
Contact Cleveland Center 135.17.
135.17,
956.
Good luck.
Ah,
well...
All right,
we are back with CNBC programming.
What you have been watching is
WNBC programming.
Nick,
what was that last message you gave me?
There are now reports of a fire at the Pentagon.
This is the Pentagon.
Oh my goodness.
You are looking at the Pentagon.
The United States has been attacked.
Forces unknown.
Thank you.
What's Brian?
It's a...
It's on fire.
And I'm in it.
And I can't breathe.
It's all over when I love him.
I don't get out of here.
Goodbye.
And this message.
Manhattan call,
Steel
Comcast. We're merging.
Manhattan,
Cornfield,
Compton,
American,
K.
Proceed Manhattan,
Cornfield,
Compton.
Alright,
Mail Hangar, in front of a window,
near the antenna in Building 1.
Top floor number?
Colleges up on the top floor,
10-4.
All 9-4,
Phil.
Yep.
The plane just crashed.
I mean,
we were sleeping awake,
you know.
We heard it,
we knew that's what it was.
We woke up and looked out the window and saw the World Trade Center,
like stuff flying off the World Trade Center.
And so we ran down to see what was going on and we were like, ducked under a thing.
When the second plane crashed into it,
we were downstairs.
We didn't want to be upstairs in our apartment,
you know,
in case,
I don't know,
you know,
in case it started falling or whatever.
And so we went downstairs and we were like ducking underneath the cover with like hundreds of people.
And when the second plane crashed and all of this metal and stuff was flying and everybody was like running, trying to get away from it,
it was,
yeah,
it was scary.
Well,
just,
you know,
like, a little debris and stuff.
But,
you know,
nothing is damaged.
Mostly, it's just,
like,
paper and stuff like that.
There's,
like,
all this paper flying around the building,
and it's kind of like the streets are...
New information we want to share with our viewers...
Here in Washington,
that there is a report of a fire at the Pentagon,
and we have seen some smoke,
so we're trying to get some more information on that.
We do not know what's happening at the Pentagon,
which brings us to what you were talking about,
the Middle East and the Bush administration policies toward the Middle East.
Okay,
these are live.
We have live pictures now of the Pentagon.
You can see this thick black smoke.
This is no trash fire,
folks.
So obviously something has happened at the Pentagon.
This is a live picture of the Pentagon.
This is not New York City.
So we are obviously getting crews there to find out what has happened.
Has something set off?
Let me ask our producer,
do we have any indication that a plane was involved here?
Keep in mind,
okay,
the Pentagon is not very far from
National Airport.
Some instant causing thick black
smoke has happened at the Pentagon.
So,
Professor,
have there been particular unhappiness from these terrorist groups with policies of the Bush administration?
We know they've been unhappy about Iraq.
Any other...
Mark,
I'm going to stop you right here.
We do have an urgent wire now saying another aircraft,
unbelievably,
has crashed into the Pentagon.
This is a preliminary wire.
We will seek to confirm this,
but this word just in to us from our newsroom that perhaps another aircraft went in there.
They obviously figured out a red fire state building.
There's no chance of a signal.
Obviously,
we're getting a signal from another airplane.
I assume it's going to be a perfect take chance to get a signal.
Two jet airplanes.
First hitting the North Tower on the north side.
Second, hitting the South Tower on the south side.
Creating a raging inferno inside the World Trade Center towers.
People have been falling to their deaths.
It's tragic.
I cannot believe this has happened.
May the Lord keep them.
Now these are the pictures right now outside of the Pentagon.
Let's listen to Jim Miklaszewski,
our Pentagon correspondent.
The airport is a helicopter landing area right next to the Pentagon, just adjacent to the E-ring. The office is nearest the the uh...
The uh...
Heliport area uh...
Our U s army, uh...
Reserve
officers and the Army Reserve.
Our offices are located there.
But as you can see,
it appears to be a pretty significant blast.
To give you some perspective,
we are almost on the opposite side of the building,
the world's largest office building.
And as I reported to you,
we could feel the building shake and the windows rattle.
And as I was in the hallway just a few moments ago,
I could smell an acrid kind of smoke,
the kind of almost what you'd smell when a fluorescent light goes bad,
that kind of ballast smell.
And authorities are clearing the building.
I don't know if you can hear the sirens outside.
Right now, uh...
But uh...
It appears, uh...
That in what had? I think people are here in the building are already describing as a highly sophisticated, coordinated attack, not only against the World Trade Center. uh...
But against the the Pentagon and U. s military right here in Washington,
do
the right thing.
Right over here,
where are you?
American 1060,
Do you see anybody northwest of you?
Can you see back that far there?
We're looking now,
sir.
Okay,
there's an ejection at 39, right in front of you, heading south,
and he said he thinks he sees him behind him.
I don't know if he sees you or somebody else.
He probably sees us.
We're directly behind him.
Okay,
that's what I thought.
He might have seen you.
That aircraft is a 757 that we're looking for,
United.
Sir,
is there any chance that we can descend?
American 1060,
contact Cleveland 135.17.
Thanks a lot for the help,
and he can give you a descent,
Claire.
135.17,
okay.
Now we're hearing that the Associated Press is quoting witnesses as saying it was an aircraft that crashed into the Pentagon.
And that is what we're looking at right now. From Arlington,
Virginia.
Our Gannett cam looking at this huge,
billowing,
dark smoke.
A plane.
So we got two planes that plowed into the
World Trade Center up in New York.
Now we've got a plane that plowed into the Pentagon here in Arlington.
Stay with us.
We're going to get you more information just as soon as we can.
Apparently,
the Pentagon being evacuated.
There are reports that the White House may be under an evacuation order as well.
The west wing of the White House has been evacuated,
according to AP,
amid terrorist threats.
That's the AP news alert.
Just moved across the wires.
The White House is ordering an immediate evacuation of the White House.
Mark,
The AP,
Alina,
is reporting an aircraft has crashed into the Pentagon.
Witnesses say,
being cited by The Associated Press,
an aircraft has crashed into the Pentagon.
Into the Pentagon,
that on the AP,
according to witnesses.
According to NBC's Jim Miklaszewski,
he is reporting a bomb detonated at the heliport at the Pentagon.
I'm not sure if this is separate from that or in addition.
Must be in addition,
too,
because this is the building involved right here.
A fire at the Pentagon.
It's just the
White House.
The medic out,
I said.
It's okay.
We're going to war.
Jimmy.
I know we're going to war,
right?
We're going to war.
If they know our country is...
They're going to bomb everybody.
Yeah.
They're gonna bomb everybody.
John.
The Pentagon.
The Pentagon,
what?
All right,
here we're going.
Stop it,
what,
is there another explosion?
Wait,
what's going on?
Is there another explosion?
They attacked the Pentagon.
They just attacked the Pentagon.
Turn off the TV.
Hold on,
wait a second.
Oh,
no.
Let's go back to the,
one second.
I've killed our commercial break.
Tom,
our general manager in New York, said, Because of what's going on now in our country, that we're just going to come back and be with you.
The Pentagon has just been attacked.
By a plane.
Team Mol 3,
Dukeman.
Cleveland Center,
Hunter's ID.
We are obviously having a pretty bad situation going on with aircraft.
I wanted to give you a heads up.
Did they get into the bike?
Hold on,
please.
Okay,
go ahead.
Folksy,
you are not going to see another day like this,
I assure you.
Let us hope, not.
Let's bring everyone up to date.
This is breaking news live from the Pentagon.
The Pentagon,
you can see,
almost totally obliterated by smoke.
Apparently, an aircraft has crashed into the Pentagon.
We'll make it clear when you say obliterate, simply that you cannot see it because we are not suggesting that the building has molested.
We are not sure the extent of the damage could be considerable,
but we do want to make it clear that. In some of the pictures, you can see the building is still standing.
But the smoke is so thick that you cannot even see the building at this point.
Okay,
we do want to make that clear.
my name is Sarah Kopp.
That is a service by the White House.
It's now near the Pentagon.
I don't know where the hell they're getting it,
and I'm sorry,
but Washington didn't have a clue when I called Washington about it.
They didn't know what the hell was going on.
No!
There's a third plane coming.
Yeah,
but I'm still going.
You're gonna see fucking military jets here.
Which hand is he walking?
No,
I can't do the playoff.
Change the channel.
I wish I was there right now.
Cleveland Center,
Delta,
1989. 16 Mike Fox,
Contact Cleveland 119.32 19,
Sorter 2,
12.
Roger.
Cleveland
Delta,
1989. Delta 1989 go.
Company wants us on the ground in Cleveland.
Say again.
The company wants us to diverge to land in Cleveland.
Delta 1989 Roger Fire Present, heading, descend and maintain flight level 330. Expect further vectoring for Cleveland.
Delta 1989 330 Present heading.
Delta 1989, Roger and contact Cleveland 119.32.
1932.
Came from Boston, where it was hijacked.
The west wing of the White House has now been evacuated, and its turret is stretched out as a...
Negative,
Kai.
Well,
all right.
Easy as well.
And from that distance,
it's difficult to get a sense of how big an airplane it is.
And that's some of the information that we expect of what will be coming out.
All right,
let's see it.
Wait,
wait,
all right. .
And then, as this is going on,
we're also following the horrific situation in New York City. With the planes,
two of them apparently having crashed into the World Trade Centers,
the twin towers you see there.
One of those, now,
we have fair confirmation,
an American Airlines flight hijacked after takeoff.
From Boston. now,
that leads to all sorts of other questions.
We don't know who was on board that plane,
how many people were on board.
How many people were on board.
Let me just get back to this Pentagon situation,
of course,
developing in our own backyard.
Of course,
this is the military center of the United States,
the Command center.
An Associated Press reporter saying that...
Channel 7's in all my shots.
Sorry.
United 93,
Cleveland,
Do you still hear the center?
United 93,
Do you still hear Cleveland?
Clear.
Turn to Toronto.
Oh, really?
Cleveland,
Air Canada 560,
We just got a message,
operations would like us to turn around and go back to Toronto.
Air Canada 560,
I understand that.
Stand by a second.
I turn...
All right.
Lauren,
are you there?
Lauren Ashburn from USA Today,
Can you hear us?
Yes,
I can,
Andrea.
Lauren,
we understand you witnessed what happened at the Pentagon.
Yes,
I did.
What did you see?
We were standing in the USA today. Towers at 1000 Wilson Boulevard,
And as we were getting ready to record,
we watched what appeared to be a huge explosion over top of the Pentagon.
At that point,
we were immediately told to evacuate the USA today. towers.
As many people know,
they're very tall towers that overlook
Washington.
Tall silver towers. And the picture that you're seeing right now is actually taken from a camera that is on top of the USA today building.
We're getting a report,
Lauren.
See if you can confirm this.
An Associated Press reporter saw the tail end of a large airliner plunge into the Pentagon.
Could you tell what type of aircraft?
We could not tell what type of aircraft it was.
The only thing we could see was a huge cloud of smoke.
And what looked like some flames at the onset of that.
We couldn't see.
I don't know if you can hear right now,
but emergency trucks,
I've seen about 20,
25 of them screaming down Route 110. Here in front of the USA Today headquarters.
All right,
Lauren,
stay on the phone with us,
can you?
Lauren,
where are you?
Did you get that,
Amanda?
No.
Anything could happen.
Further terrorist target is now being closed down as New York City and apparently the capital go into.
The Pentagon,
How do they get a plane through to the Pentagon?
That's what I wanna know.
Well.
Isn't that what.
On the Washington Mall.
So there's only,
there's now two.
How is the Pentagon?
It's 48 minutes since the first attack on the World Trade Center.
And they got a plane crew.
This is terrorism?
Well,
we know it's terrorism,
and I'm telling you,
a country has to be...
You know,
this reminds me of Japan attacked us in World War II,
Pearl Harbor.
They were the only country ever to attack the United States like this.
And we took an A-bomb,
and we blew the daylights out of them.
Harry Truman knew.
They were still screwing around at the end of the war.
Four years later.
They dropped an atomic bomb on their ass.
And we've got to drop atomic bombs.
There's got to be a war.
But a devastating war where people die.
No stopping them.
Burn their eyes out with atomic bombs.
And don't want to hear about casual civilian casualties.
We've got civilian casualties.
If this guy Bush doesn't go to war right now,
I'm telling you that you've got to know where to go.
We know where to go.
Well,
you know what?
The other side of that building is incredible.
It's just steel beams.
The face of it blew out.
9. David to Conrad on input. 9. David,
K.
Ready to write the...
9-David,
go ahead.
You ready to write the identity?
Go ahead.
Engines,
240,
201,
249,
278,
281.
228-219-280.
The four truck companies will be 102,
119,
114,
113.
Three chiefs I gave you would be the 3-2.
The 4-1 and the 4-2, all coming through the battery tunnel.
I'm not identifying any fast truck.
If you want a fifth truck,
let me know and we'll send you one.
That's a negative.
That last engine was 2-1-0.
Negative,
2-8-1.
Okay,
thank you.
10-4.
I'm across the street watching the game play.
I said this,
I complained.
I can't feel my eyes and so,
you know,
I'm bringing in the server.
Yeah.
And then I fall on my side and I'm like,
oh,
smile.
Do you see me now?
I called the Summer Tour director.
The plane crash was on the way,
so I came around to the main office.
I was sitting down in the office.
I got a seat up.
I'm with the right actor.
And then I was walking around,
and I hit, boom!
And I ducked, like,
oh shit,
something hit me in the head.
I almost felt like something hit me in the head.
And now the second plane comes through.
And I'm the guy that's in the office.
We saw the second plane go.
I'm fine.
Scary.
They can do this,
they can't do this.
What do you mean?
Okay,
hold on.
What did they tell you?
.The. TVs before the showdowns,
they're telling us earlier, cell phone communications have been disrupted.
Much like communications were disrupted from the TV stations for at least a brief time.
The second one was actually
twin engine huge plane that didn't look that big when it hit. No, it was huge well after it hit. You can see the glass shattering right now away from this guy. And back to Dunkirk Air, can a 560 fly heading two niner zero expect direct Dunkirk Direct lane? I don't know if we should be
in here.
The plane that was hijacked in Boston happened to foul.
Witnesses say that another commercial airliner has slammed into the Pentagon down in Arlington,
Virginia.
The U.S.
Capitol and the White House have both been evacuated,
and we understand that the White House had received a threat of a terrorist attack.
Now we're looking back at the Pentagon again.
You can see the smoke billowing from there.
We have no other information at this point about casualties or injuries, or exactly what it was that smashed into the Pentagon earlier.
I see it.
Tell everybody.
Ask somebody.
Are you the news or something?
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
Woo!
I can sit here.
I can go in and have a seat.
Is this your home?
Yes.
That's what I'm saying.
This is great.
We'll get to him in a second.
Greta van Susteren is at National Airport in Washington.
Greta,
what are you hearing?
I just got off my plane.
I headed to New York.
Planes were stalled.
I'm at National Airport, on the parking lot.
I heard a huge noise.
I looked over in the direction of the plane.
Of the Pentagon.
There's a huge plume of smoke coming from that area.
I can't verify it's the Pentagon because there are these buildings in the way.
You see particles coming down in the air,
some sort of white particles.
I can't tell what that is.
I heard a noise slightly before I'd seen the smoke.
I don't know if it's an airplane or a plane.
Plan for the bomb,
but it was certainly something.
And obviously,
there's a terrific fire going on.
The skies are clear here,
except for the tremendous amount of smoke that's coming from there.
Lots of sirens from all different directions,
and, of course,
a lot of uncertainty here at National Airport.
I watched the plane.
It was like,
Oh my god.
It was like a rip.
It was a big jet.
Construction on the ground is 2 by 11.
Okay,
United 93.
Go ahead.
It's 29 miles out of,
29 minutes out of Washington,
DC.
D.C. and tracking towards it.
This is the one who reversed cars in Ohio.
Yes.
Go ahead.
That's all I have.
Okay,
the
United 93 is 29 minutes out of where?
He's heading towards the Washington area.
He was at flight level 350.
He turned around in Akron,
Ohio,
and is tracking toward the Washington area at this time.
All right,
they're pulling Jeff away.
They're going to talk about United 93.
Do we want to think about scrambling aircraft?
Oh,
God,
I don't know.
That's a decision somebody's going to have to make, probably in the next 10 minutes.
You know,
everybody just left the ring.
United, 93, is 2-0 miles northwest of Johnstown.
2-0 miles northwest on primary.
Well,
that's a report from another aircraft.
United, 93, was waving his wings as he went past the VFR aircraft.
They don't quite know what that means.
Rocking his wings.
Okay.
Today,
that happened, what,
25 minutes ago,
20 minutes ago?
Something of that sort.
One of the other pictures we saw,
where she saw a military in full fatigue.
Outside the White House.
Outside the White House,
fully bloated and ready to go for anything.
We expect that Giuliani is going to be speaking shortly.
As you can imagine,
I'm sure there is a scene of much confusion now at downtown in Manhattan,
outside the World Trade Center towers.
We have just been told that the Pentagon is being evacuated.
Amanda,
use a double-edged sander.
Oh,
I like your deal.
They saw,
he saw,
he or she saw the tail end of a large airliner plunge into the building.
Again,
a large airliner,
so it's leading to suggest,
again,
this might have been a coordinated hijacking of airplanes.
To fly them in s****** missions, using planes as bombs,
as the professor put it,
planes as domestic planes as weapons.
It would appear at this point not to be overly dramatic. On a horrible,
horrible day.
That, uh...
Some of the major parts of the United States terms of public procedure under siege right now. Okay, one more area now that we are going to be checking out the National Mall is a picture building on the mall. Mass-produced OK report of a fire on the National Mall, of course, will be checking that out as well. The
president was, uh...
Told of the first incident this morning in Sarasota, Florida, he left immediately after making phone calls to the vice president, the governor of New York. This was before the scenes you're seeing here now,
here, as Locke pointed out,
you can see.
The buildings of the Pentagon,
and of course, the Pentagon is constructed in a series of rings,
appears to be intact at this point,
which is a good sign.
Which is a good sign.
We're hoping now,
And you can also see, just off the right-hand side of your screen,
a helicopter circling just to the right.
We're hoping to get more information about the Pentagon.
We do have a crew on the way to New York as well,
we might point out.
There was only one.
It was an explosion.
It was a stupid explosion.
Where's my new gun?
It's my fake.
I don't know.
Manhattan calling field Com,
correction,
field com calling Manhattan.
Alright,
on the 804,
northwest corner,
50 people trapped gang.
That's in building 1.
10-4 Manhattan,
ready?
All right,
4-10.
Field
com to
Manhattan. Thank you,
sir.
We ought to see how much bigger the camp is.
I was on the phone with him and I asked him.
Ariel?
Ariel.
Yeah,
are you turning that Med-X away from that primary up there?
I,
the Med-X,
we're in Venice talking to Med-X.
I see him turning them out of the United States.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Put your primaries up,
Bill,
because I'm pretty sure that's him.
I've got it.
Go on the track.
Okay.
What did they say?
They didn't say anything.
A plane crashed into the Pentagon!
What?
Sharon,
this plane just crashed into the Pentagon.
At this point...
Um,
we're looking back at the whole Trade Center Palace here.
It just continues to drill.
The fire is clearly not under control yet.
Jay,
we have another witness on the telephone of the,
uh,
the second plane slamming into the second tower.
His name is Robert Thomas, from Brooklyn Heights.
Can you hear me,
Robert?
Yes,
I can.
Can you tell us exactly what you saw?
I was on the roof deck of my building watching the fire from the first explosion when I was on the phone with my parents in Florida.
And I watched the second plane coming in from the Staten Island-ish area.
Um,
and I was thinking about it,
telling my mom on the phone.
Whatever that debris is down there, that's fire.
Those will be fucking live tonight.
Those will be taken out.
We'll start around the corner.
We're all getting over it.
All these countries are jealous of us,
our way of life.
They want us to be miserable like they are.
Right.
And we are now miserable.
And now is the time to not even ask questions.
Nope.
Just to be pissed off and drop a few atom bombs,
do a couple of chemical warfare hits,
let their people burn and suffer until they understand.
Stores of everything. Because we haven't been bothering anybody, right? They started screaming about colonialism, we stopped. John Flattery I'm sorry, Dominic. What is it, Elsa? It's Lynn. Um, I only have a minute, I'm on United 93. And it's been hijacked by terrorists who say they have a bomb. Apparently they, uh, flown a couple of planes into the World Trade Center already and it looks like they're going to take this one down as well. Mostly,
I just wanted to say I love it was.
I'm gonna love you.
And please give my love to my dad.
And...
Mostly, I just love you and I just wanted to tell you that.
I don't know if I'm gonna be able to tell you that again or not.
My stuff is in the safe.
The safe is in my closet, in my bedroom.
The combination is you push C for clear and then 0913 and then it should,
and maybe pound, and then it should unlock.
I love you and I hope I can talk to you soon.
Bye.
Flight
3M, in the south.
Number 561 Alpha Charlie,
Contact Cleveland 119.32,
sir.
1932,
Good day.
United 93,
Cleveland.
Allegheny?
Allegheny.
I believe that to be the primary that's associated with the United 93.
Do you want to put your primary buttons on there?
I got the primary buttons on.
Okay,
do you want to just take the hand off in case he calls you or calls somebody down that area?
I'll do that.
He's not answering me anymore.
All right.
And we don't know what, allegheny...
To these after that.
Okay.
Okay,
we put it out to Imperial and everybody below.
All right.
Okay,
we do know,
or at least the Associated Press is now reporting,
that an aircraft crashed near the Pentagon,
and the West wing of the White House,
as Claire Shipman told us,
was evacuated amid these threats.
Manhattan calling field com K.
Field com K.
Okay, Field com.
104.4 Northwest corner.
50 people trapped.
Fire,
burn and belief.
104.4 Northwest corner.
What building?
That's building 1 K.
I'm a social activist because a lot of the communication is on top of the media.
So all the network television stations,
most of the networks,
all the media networks,
most of them are national.
If you hear anything about the Pentagon,
get in there.
National Defense.
That's ridiculous.
Every branch is on there.
The president could have been there,
we don't know.
He's on a plane right now,
I'm sure.
He's on the ground somewhere.
He's on the ground, on a plane, someplace,
you know,
talking to his gentlemen.
They want his head.
He's on the ground in some War games type place.
And now, apparently two other things that are happening,
Mark,
just want to bring you up to date on that. We've just gotten word in that, the U.S.
Capitol,
we believe,
is being evacuated, along with the West wing of the White House.
And there we see over the old executive office building,
you can see in the distance,
someone in the way there,
but you can see right behind that technician there,
the flames coming from the Pentagon.
Going down another block,
get another angle?
Yeah,
we can if you want.
Did you get a shot of that debris?
I know I interrupted you.
I'd like to actually take a look at it.
There's glassy sliding through the building.
Well,
that's from the building.
Building you don't think that's from the plane, though. how can you tell it's insulation, insulation, glass inside the building?
We need to spray a little more before we leave.
Tuesday,
9.47 a.m.
Hi,
baby.
Baby,
you have to listen to me carefully.
I'm on a plane that's been hijacked.
I'm on the plane.
I'm calling from the plane.
I want to tell you I love you.
Please tell my children that I love them very much,
and I'm so sorry.
I don't know what to say.
There's three guys.
They've hijacked the plane.
I'm trying to be calm.
We're turned around,
and I've heard that there's planes that...
And then going into the World Trade Center.
I hope to be able to see your face again,
baby.
I love you.
Bye.
End of message.
This way,
folks.
They're going home.
Oh,
come on.
Yeah,
they're going home.
Come on,
boys.
Keep moving.
Okay,
the
United 93 is 29 minutes out of where?
He's heading towards the Washington area.
He was at flight level 350.
He turned around at Akron,
Ohio,
and is tracking toward the Washington area at this time.
I did photograph and videotape some of the medic units treating some of the injured immediately as I moved forward.
The ambulance says I was able to get out.
John,
this is coming from the North Tower.
This is coming from the North Tower.
These are people who I see jumping out onto the west,
what would be the West side.
Highway passing in front of the building and as you can imagine, Mark, it is a gruesome scene. It's just blood or red from.
I can't confirm it is that that athlete bodies, but I can see it
looks that way,
then red splotches on the street in front of the building.
Mark,
A couple of things I want to pass along very quickly.
According to The Associated Press,
the White House has been threatened with a terrorist attack,
according to a source.
The West wing has been evacuated.
We want to mention now the Capitol has been evacuated as well,
as well the U.S.
Treasury.
Marriott Call Field, com.
Field com K.
Alright,
Building 2,
80 is the floor.
Sir.
80 people trapped K.
Floor.
804,
804 on building 2,
80 people trapped.
804,
10. floor.
Are there anybody here that doesn't have a roof?
Ron is trying to get real clear on this.
I think that was the black smoke bomb.
Two!
There were two planes.
Another plane hit the same place or the other go?
The other go.
So you saw that happen?
Yeah.
How big a plane was it?
It was a small room.
And then what is it?
It was a firewall that was at the top of the building.
On the left one?
On the left one.
And then, just like,
it was like million pieces of paper.
You know,
there was all the other things that I knew was in there.
And then you would see them.
Is it very good, or is it just a little piece of the pizza?
I don't know.
United 93,
Do you hear Cleveland Center?
Chris Plant,
tell me what you've learned since we last talked.
Well,
in speaking to people here at the Pentagon, as they're being evacuated from the building,
I am told by several people that there was,
in fact,
an explosion.
I was told by one witness.
An air force enlisted,
senior enlisted man,
that he was outside when it occurred.
He said that he saw a helicopter circle the building.
He said that it appeared to be a U.S.
Military helicopter and that it disappeared behind the building where the helicopter...
Landing zone,
excuse me,
And that he then saw a fireball go into the sky.
I'm attempting to make my way around to that side of the building in my car right now to see if I can get a better visual perspective on the scene on that side of the building,
but I can tell you that security has certainly clamped down the
U.S. Park police and other federal law enforcement department has arrived in force on the scene.
There's a park police helicopter over
overhead.
Every car that arrives at the gate where I was located was being stopped by officers at gunpoint.
Everyone is being forced out of their vehicles as they arrive at the Pentagon.
It's a very tense situation,
obviously,
But initial reports from witnesses indicate that there was in fact a helicopter circling the building,
contrary to what the AP reported,
according to the witnesses. I've spoken to anyway.
Smoke and fire problem.
Walls are breached,
so be careful.
Yeah,
10-4,
I saw that on 68.
6-1-1,
go.
One for the town,
you can't move it.
As we also see on the left hand of our screen,
the flames coming from the Twin Towers,
the World Trade Center in New York.
This could be the start of a major event in U.S.
Foreign policy.
Those events are probably going to unfold in the next couple of hours.
We're hoping for more information as to what exactly the United States will response.
The amazing thing at this point,
Larkin,
would appear to me, would be the simultaneous hijacking,
not of small planes that you can rent,
but of major commercial jetliners.
Major commercial jetliners.
We had a professor from America.
University who was talking about this as being an escalation of terrorism,
a different technique that we have not seen.
Of course,
we've seen individuals strapped with explosives.
We have seen trucks packed with explosives and cars.
And now again, to...
Still calm,
K.
Still calm.
We're not able to raise the Division 3 messenger van regarding the extra handy walkie talkies,
K.
10-4. We are behind the scenes,
all walking to the east side, east side,
You're not in the phone place,
you have to keep the streets clear,
let's go.
I don't know why I'm going to you, but...
California.
Why?
Yeah.
Something in the Midwest.
Or something in the West.
That's West.
I mean,
there's obvious targets,
but I mean,
Chicago,
LA...
Chicago or something in...
Boy,
they're going to every...
The Pentagon!
They're doing it!
They've shut down Wall Street!
Can you imagine they bombed...
They actually crashed into the...
Pentagon!
How do you get to do that?
I thought that that's like, so...
Like that, airspace is completely protected.
And how are they not on alert?
Well,
everybody's on alert now.
It's 48 minutes later.
So what?
I mean,
that's certainly enough time.
I'm saying this.
I'm agreeing with you.
You know, this is a huge country to try to protect,
though.
I know.
But the Pentagon is a target that is considered a highly desirable target.
But you know what?
They probably are sitting there going,
nobody would ever do this.
Just like they did during World War II.
After the White House,
what's the next biggest target?
It's got to be the Pentagon,
right?
What's bigger than that?
Pentagon is bigger than the White House.
It's where we have our nuclear capability.
Now,
where does all the Cabinet and the president go when you evacuate them?
Where do they go?
They have bunkers if they have to.
They have bunkers.
What do you have,
Baba Boo?
We can go to your apartment.
We'll get a better view when the plane comes.
FAA has shut down all planes.
Nothing in the country can take off.
Joining us by phone now is Don Chauncey.
Don,
are you there?
Yes,
I am.
You witnessed what happened at the Pentagon.
What did you see?
From my office,
I was able to see a white jet,
like a Gulfstream-type commuter jet,
I guess,
just came at a high rate of speed.
I can see National Airport's tower from our office.
Right.
And it just increased.
As it got closer to the Pentagon,
and then I just saw the big yellow ball of fire.
Don,
exactly where is your office from?
Where are you watching this?
Our office is right at St.
Barnabas Road and the Beltway,
so I overlooked the Beltway from my office.
office.
Could you tell, Don, did the plane come out of National?
No.
No, it did not.
Absolutely not.
There was a it appeared to be a U.S. air commuter jet that went over top of our building, which is a normal flight pattern, I guess, for the commuters.
Yeah.
And this looked like it was coming from,
I'm guessing, down Columbia, Pike and Arlington, down that way and then just picked up a high rate of speed.
I mean, from my desk right now, I can see
the Pentagon,
basically where the metro station is and the buses,
I can see that to the right,
but I can't see,
I guess,
the South parking area.
Don,
what's the reaction of others in your office?
I mean,
watching the World Trade Center and then seeing this right, literally in your own backyard.
Well,
myself and another co-worker that sits besides. Both of us were actually on the phone, looking out the window when it happened,
and both of us dropped the phone. And we picked it back up and said,
we have to go.
It looked like somebody,
it was a plane crash, either,
at the airport.
At the Pentagon.
Don,
hold on with us for a second.
We're just getting this bulletin.
Topper
4 Local Desk for Pete.
Yeah,
just so, you know,
when we go down to refuel,
we will not be allowed back up in the air.
I have a friend tonight that is breaking my heart.
I'm in the office.
I don't need parking.
Let's go,
everybody, out of here!
Come on,
for your own safety,
get out of here!
Overclimbing bridge is a disaster.
They're in the building.
There's a breeze.
Oh,
my God.
shit.
All right,
they're pulling Jeff away to talk about United 93.
Do we want to think about scrambling aircraft?
Oh,
God,
I don't know.
That's a decision somebody's going to have to make, probably in the next 10 minutes.
You know,
everybody just left the room.
Can you imagine if there was something in those planes that crashed?
There was something in there.
No,
no,
I'm saying, like, a chemical or something like that.
That's right,
that's all they need.
No,
no,
he's got a point.
What if there's some killer gas in there?
Some chemical.
That's a good point.
I think everybody would be dead.
There's no air in this building.
Not to make a joke.
We're the only ones left.
I swear to you,
I'm getting queasy.
There's every reason to be.
I'm having trouble breathing.
There's every reason.
Who do I sue?
We are under attack like never before.
Howard will be the only casualty.
No,
I'm telling you,
I'm starting to get agitated.
Well,
don't have a heart attack before you find out what's going to happen.
I feel like I'm very angry.
I know.
Read it through a paper bag.
I'm very angry.
I feel that people need to suffer now.
You're not going to class tonight,
subways are closed.
If we had stayed here and just taken video,
we would have had a perfect view of it.
Commence in Wanda.
Hi Wanda,
I don't know if you heard,
but we had a crash into the Pentagon by a 737.
I think it was 737 or 757.
Shut down all rivals in the national Airport.
Crash into the Pentagon,
National is shut down.
Right.
You National?
National?
The Federal Aviation Administration has shut down all aircraft takeoffs nationwide.
All aircraft takeoffs nationwide have been halted by the FAA.
What's the shot scale?
I'm sorry.
I'll wait.
Jay,
we have another witness on the telephone of the second plane slamming into the second tower.
His name is Robert Thomas, from Brooklyn Heights.
Can you hear me,
Robert?
Yes,
I can.
Can you tell us exactly what you saw?
I was on the roof deck of my building watching the fire from the first explosion,
and I was on the phone with my parents in Florida.
And I watched the second plane coming in from Staten Island area, and I was thinking I was telling my mom on the phone that plane is too low. I can't believe it's that close to the building after the first one hit and it was a gray on the top plane. It was about the size of one of the shuttles, maybe coming from
from D.C. area.
It was not a small plane.
It was like a 737 or something.
And whatever airline is gray on the top.
And I saw it hit the building.
I have a very good friend who works at Windows in the World,
the pastry chef Heather Ho,
and I hope to God she's okay to die.
Have you attempted to reach her?
I tried to call her at home.
The work number is busy,
of course.
And I tried to call her at home and got her message.
Okay.
Again,
we've been talking about how the FBI is reporting or is investigating. Reports that at least one aircraft, if not
not two, were hijacked earlier today.
So, from your vantage point,
what you could see appeared to be the size of perhaps a shuttle aircraft.
Right.
It was not a small plane.
It was a big plane.
Okay.
I know people have been saying a small commuter,
but it wasn't small.
It was definitely a,
you know,
it definitely held a good group of people.
Could you see,
could you see anybody through the windows of the cockpit of that aircraft?
No,
it wasn't that close,
but I could clearly see the plane coming in.
I could clearly see it aiming straight for the building.
It was in a long swoop.
Motion It wasn't a jerky flight, it went straight into it and it was way, I mean, it was so low, it was unbelievable to watch.
I tell you what I'm scared right now. Yeah, thank you. We appreciate your comments and we thank you very much for for giving us this information. Because of course, we are, we are trying to find.
Oh man,
what happens when people are working on the
LFT?
10 miles west of Morgantown,
Code 3404-350, direct Charleston.
How fast is he going?
415 knots.
Let me talk to him here.
Alright,
Emma.
Hendersen,
Allegheny, 59.
What was the call sign there,
Allegheny?
This is Hendersen.
Yeah,
Moorfield has to talk to you, sir,
2654,
I'm gonna give them control for turns and put them on him.
That's approved,
Emma.
Alright.
This morning.
That's right.
I'm Carol Costello.
Don Hudson.
We want to go live to Sam Ford right now.
He is live at Reagan National Airport with an update on the air crash at the Pentagon.
Sam Ford,
tell us what you can.
Well,
Carol,
as you can see,
there is this loud,
this huge cloud of smoke behind me,
and that is the location of the Pentagon.
We had come here to National Airport to,
you know,
continue our coverage of the situation in New York because the airports had been shut down.
No sooner had we gotten here.
And stopped the car.
Then we looked up and there was this cloud of smoke billowing from the Pentagon.
There had been a traffic accident here at National and a number of emergency vehicles were dealing with that.
Then suddenly we saw this, and I would say, within a couple of minutes, they were all tearing out of here, heading toward the Pentagon.
We asked folks here,
One of the police officers told me that he had heard a plane had gone into the Pentagon.
Obviously more of the situations in New York.
People here are extremely nervous and some are saying that they wanted us to leave this area.
We don't know if they're going to shut down the airport or evacuate this place.
This is a concern.
At this point,
people are still here.
But there is concern about the safety of this place.
Obviously,
with these bombs going off or planes crashing into buildings all over the place.
You just heard some news?
They don't know about the sentence,
but they said the first U.S.
Agent was hijacked from Boston.
They didn't hit the first one,
they didn't hijack him.
This is all unconfirmed,
it's all over.
Everybody's saying all kinds of things.
27 now in the state,
I'll be right.
Every aircraft in the air has been ordered to land at the nearest airport immediately.
This is obviously a step to clear the air of all innocent aircraft.
Whether there remain any guilty aircraft is debatable,
but at least what the government is trying to do is clear the air. And obviously,
well,
not obviously,
But it looks like what they will do is they will then put up military planes. And anyone still in the air is going to be killed.
Saw a helicopter circle the building. He said that it appeared to be a U.S military helicopter, and then it disappeared behind the building where the helicopter was. And that he then saw a fireball.
I'm going to this guy.
I'm attempting to make my way around to that side of the building in my car right now to see if I can get a better visual perspective on the scene on that side of the
building.
Oh,
I know.
It's nowhere.
Tell me again.
I worked at the Pentagon as well,
and it is a huge building.
I mean,
it's mild.
Miles and miles of offices.
At what location did this seem to have detonated?
It's at the heliport.
The heliport, which is
as you sit in the Pentagon,
you have the Potomac River and Washington,
D.C.
On one side,
and the heliport is located almost exactly on the opposite side of the building,
along one of the highways.
Easily accessible,
even though that they've increased security here significantly at the Pentagon within the past couple of years.
I want to mention to you,
Mick,
that we are hearing,
again,
unconfirmed reports that this was the result of a plane crash.
Crashing in the area as well.
I have no idea, Katie.
All I know is that people who were in the building, who came running from that part of the building, thought it was a bomb of some kind.
This is in Sarasota, Florida. President George W.
Bush about to board Air Force One, heading back very quickly to Washington, canceling all of his events there. And he will be heading over to the situation room with top officials,
including national...
So they were commercial friends?
Yep.
Looks like you don't want to go.
So they were hijackers?
They were hijackers.
They didn't hijack from P.
Boston.
Huh?
They had.
The White House.
They hijacked it from Boston?
Yeah.
Oh,
yeah.
From Logan Airport?
Yeah.
Isn't Logan under construction?
Evacuating the West wing of the White House.
It's time to stop screwing around with these people.
And I'm talking all the way down to Saddam Hussein.
Yeah,
they're begging for it.
Yeah.
Countries like Yemen and the United Arab Emirates.
Yes.
Who house these people and let these people do this?
All of them,
blow them all to sky high.
They are begging us for major attention.
Adam Bond.
Nuclear strikes all over the world today.
Nuclear war.
Just do it so that they're flattened out and it turns into a paved road.
And we need to build amusement parks over there.
And we'll take the oil for ourselves,
by the way.
But that,
that's it here.
As you can see,
the smoke, and you can see,
you know,
paper flying about.
Yes,
Carol.
Sam,
a question for you.
We understand that there is a tail section of a plane sticking out of the Pentagon,
and a plane did hit the Pentagon.
Is that true?
Well,
at this point,
Carol,
we are at National Airport,
so all we can really see is the flames.
Now,
I understand we have some photographers over at the Pentagon.
I cannot tell you exactly,
but from our vantage point,
we see smoke.
Sam,
If I can interrupt,
we do have an eyewitness who actually saw...
This event take place. They're on the phone with us now, is it, mr.
Or ms.
Gurman Okay, mr.
Gurman Tell us what happened. I saw a big explosion, a bowl of fire, my window. right now. look that it was a big bowl of fire and smoke coming out.
I'm looking at it right now. Is mr.
Navy Annex and mr.
Pentagon, it's like so many high-rise buildings, probably a parking, or there's a cemetery behind the Navy on it.
Mr.
Gurma,
did you actually see a plane?
I didn't see a plane.
I heard the explosion.
I thought it was a flyby because I live next to the airport.
My window rolled.
I looked out.
I saw a bowl of fire and just smoke coming.
Are you feeling nervous right now,
Mr.
Herman?
Very much so.
I thought I was hit.
I mean,
the building shook so much.
As I move further still,
I was focusing on the impact site and the firefighting, directly across from the fire engine and the control tower at the heliport.
Looking for,
and again,
seeing videotape and photographs, and reading information about airplane crashes,
I'm looking for wreckage.
I don't see anything discernible.
I can't find a piece of any...
Jet Jet 956 turn right heading 260.
OK 260 for Jet Jet 956.
Have these guys got a target on another airplane?
We believe there's one up there yet.
OK, we might be able to see them when we come back around on the turn.
We had visual on them before.
American 10-6-3-3-0, United 93. We think is probably
I see the primary there, that's the primary, we think that's him.
We're not sure of the altitude,
but I can tell you that security has certainly clamped down the U.S.
Park police and other federal law enforcement department has arrived in force on the scene.
There's a park police helicopter overhead.
Every car that arrives at the gate where I was located was being stopped by officers at gunpoint.
Everyone is being forced out of their vehicles as they arrive at the Pentagon.
Very tense situation,
obviously.
But initial reports from witnesses indicate that there was in fact a...
The building,
contrary to what the AP reported,
according to the witnesses. I spoke to anyway,
and that this helicopter disappeared behind the building and that there was an explosion.
That's about all I have from here.
Okay,
let's do this,
Chris.
Why don't you continue reporting and we'll catch up.
Let's go to Atlanta.
Chad Myers can talk to us a bit about the air traffic problems.
Chad,
are you there?
Aaron,
yes,
All of the airports across the country have been shut down.
We started with Zone New York,
which includes Islip,
Newark,
JFK,
LaGuardia,
all the way down to Philadelphia.
To try to calm us down,
the only person I can think of is on the phone,
Cabby,
crazy Cabby.
Yes,
Cabby.
Can you make sense of all this?
Yes,
Cabby.
Howard.
Yeah.
I live in Brooklyn,
and I'm standing on the roof of my building,
and it's...
Disgustingly sick. What is going on.
Who did this,
first of all?
And second of all,
it's time to stop toying and letting these people come into our country and blow things up and do it all over the world.
You know,
we keep...
Guys like Osama bin Laden around because we need enemies. We need a reason to build bombs. And
I swear to God, if this isn't a reason to wipe out every freaking terrorist on the planet Earth. Today, we have the technology, we know where they are, we can do it, it's just do it. We're afraid of the world reaction now. Now, don't be afraid, that's what I say, screw the rest of the world.
I mean, you talk about attacking us at our heart. We're on the building with binoculars
and so...
And somebody said they actually saw,
they think they saw somebody jump out of the building because the building's on fire.
Oh,
my God.
This is just un...
This is...
I can't...
I'm in shock.
I'm in shock,
too,
and I'll tell you one thing.
I'm getting increasingly woozy from this.
And they're closing down all of Manhattan.
We will not be let off this island.
I have no idea.
There you can see people hurrying back up into Air Force One.
And we are reading on the associated.
Press wires that the West wing of the White House has now been evacuated.
The West wing of the White House.
Let's go back and listen to the continuing description at the Pentagon by Jim Miklaszewski.
Well,
nobody's given us the official word yet,
but
I think that's probably a safe bet.
Thank goodness, that was a helicopter that just flew by.
I'm just a little nervous right now when you hear...
Hear aircraft go past, but uh...
They have, uh...
In fact, evacuated that portion of the building. Usually, they have sirens that go off in the building, alerting you to the fact that, uh...
It's time to get out. I haven't heard those yet, uh...
But just judging by the pictures, uh...
It's it's clear that that part of the building, uh...
uh...
That is not damaged, at least, has been evacuated. Like I said in the hallway, it was pandemonium, people were rushing from.
And you're in your office at the Pentagon right now,
Mick,
reporting to us.
I am in the office.
You did?
I was on the fourth floor.
I saw a cat in my bag.
Was it an air lighter?
Yeah.
I was in the line.
That's where it went in.
You played this?
Yeah.
Where were you when that happened?
I was on the fourth floor.
I work in the Post office.
Where is that at?
Right next to the Trace Town.
Do you know what time that was?
The last one happened about 2 minutes after 9.
And the first one?
About 8.30.
I just hit out the lunch at 9 o'clock.
You're lucky.
You didn't even get to hit out the lunch.
I got about two minutes after 9 to last night.
I just hit the window.
Is that a carrier station you work at?
Yeah,
it's a federal building.
It came from George Brogan.
It came this way and then I fainted.
Right.
And what happened?
Did it go into the building?
Thanks,
Bob.
What kind of explosion?
Explosive bomb impact.
You saw that, too?
serious.
Yeah,
they were coming out of there.
No choice.
A guy just dropped about 15,
20 minutes.
Allegheny.
Allegheny,
we need to get Chautauqua 4878 out of the way.
I see that.
Because he's going right at the United.
Somebody turn him to one.
I'll get him.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
Well,
you're watching.
You got your primary?
I see the primary out of the United 93.
Okay.
We don't know an altitude.
That's what we don't know.
I promise.
Okay.
Executives 956 Contact the Indianapolis Center 133.77. Appreciate your patience.
3377 for 956. No problem, good luck on everything.
Well, we're now getting reports that the White House has been threatened here. We're also getting reports that Capitol has been
evacuated,
the West Wing and the White House evacuated. To go along with all this.
What started at 840 this morning in New York is now threatening,
of course,
our city,
our safety,
and a lot of folks very concerned.
The pictures you're looking at right now are from our live cameras.
You can see smoke pouring near the Pentagon.
Mr.
Gurma,
do you want to add anything?
I can hear you're still on the phone with us.
I'm trying to get out of here because I live a few miles from the Pentagon.
Okay,
you get going,
Mr.
Gurma.
We understand.
Thank you for joining us.
Let's go to a White House shot that we have right now.
The White House West wing has been evacuated,
as we understand.
We know that President Bush is not there,
but he is on his way back to Washington.
You can see the armed guards on top of the White House keeping watch.
But at this point,
they,
as well as we,
don't know exactly what's going to happen,
but everyone.
One is on standby, as you might expect.
And as you mentioned, in case people are wondering and didn't see President Bush in Florida for an educational issue down there,
He made a brief announcement about this and said he was on his way back here to deal with it. And, of course, saying that the terrorist acts will not be tolerated and that they will be looking into it.
But after he made that comment is when the thing when it happened at the Pentagon.
At that time, only the two planes had crashed into the Twin Towers,
the World Trade Center in New York.
We wish you could tell you more about what's going on in our own backyard at the Pentagon.
We don't know if there were any injuries.
We do know there was a construction site.
Scene on the scene at the time.
We do know when they heard something explode,
they turned around and they started to run.
We do not know if anyone inside the Pentagon or around it was hurt.
We have dawn on the phone now,
who was another witness to what happened at the Pentagon.
Dawn,
can you hear us?
Dawn?
Hello?
Yes,
Dawn.
This is Andre in the newsroom with Mike Buchanan.
What did you see?
I saw the,
it was an American Airlines 757,
and it came in and hit the side,
It hit the heliport,
came down Columbia Pike and hit the heliport next to the Pentagon.
I live in an apartment building on that side of the Pentagon.
And it just crashed right into it.
I don't know if it damaged the side of the Pentagon,
but the Pentagon doesn't look that badly damaged.
But I know it hit at least the heliport on the side of the Pentagon.
You said it was a 757?
How could you tell?
Could you see that?
Yes,
I could see it.
And my roommate is an airplane person,
and he saw it too.
I mean,
we saw the whole thing.
It didn't come out of national.
It came in from the west?
It came right down Columbia Pike.
Low and with throttles on.
With the full,
like full throttle?
Yeah.
He actually added power right by the Sheridan.
And that's what we heard from Don as well.
Added power and went straight for the Pentagon.
So this was no accident.
No,
no.
It was deliberate.
This was aimed right at it.
But unfortunately,
I think it hit the heliport and didn't look like it damaged too much of the Pentagon.
All right.
Don,
thank you very much for calling us with that.
Andrea,
listen,
yeah,
thank you very,
very much.
10-Core,
field Com.
Field Com,
Ken.
OK,
building 2,
104,
Northwest Conference Room,
people trapped.
Building 2,
104,
Northwest Conference Room,
10-4.
10-4,
all night,
5-4-3.
Engine 6-7-1-8,
Engine 6-7-1-8.
Yeah,
we're 10-8.
10-4.
What we're seeing now is that there's information that the aircraft at the Pentagon crashed in a helicopter landing pad near the Pentagon.
Again, the West wing of the White House evacuated amid threats of terrorism.
As well as the U.S. Capitol and the State Department.
Where are these planes coming from?
They're coming from Boston.
That's Air Force one you see in Florida,
the president on board.
Obviously extraordinary security around the plane before the president got on.
And the president is heading back to Washington.
A short time ago, the president made a statement.
He said Terrorism against our nation will not stand.
The government will hunt down those responsible.
Let's go,
let's go.
Sir.
Watch your back.
Whoa.
Get the camera.
A man was shot dead in the back of a car in the city of San Francisco on Tuesday,
June 23,
at a local bus stop in San Francisco.
The driver was shot dead in the back of a car in San Francisco.
The driver,
I mean,
I...
I think this building is going to be open today.
No,
not that building.
no,
no.
I mean,
just the...
A lot of people may have nothing to do with it.
Yeah,
but from a safety standpoint,
it just isn't safe.
Like a jet?
That building,
even several alterations, aren't being opened at all.
I can't keep this a constant.
Mr.
Bush said Today we've had a national tragedy.
Two planes have crashed into the World Trade Center,
an apparent terrorist attack on the country.
And we also have a report now that it was a plane that crashed into the Pentagon,
and we have a large fire at the Pentagon.
The Pentagon is being evacuated as we speak now.
The White House has been evacuated as well.
No,
obviously not.
Probably a commercial airline that was hijacked.
Think of all the people on these planes.
They just said a plane was hijacked from Boston,
one of these planes.
767 is,
I called my wife,
and she said the report she heard was that it was a 767 out of Boston,
and that is probably the second plane.
That's the first one.
I think that's the second one.
really?
Gabby,
thanks for the call.
1010,
1010.
All commercial,
but no people in it?
No.
No,
you can't get anything out.
No clothes on.
Don't take anything.
Shut down.
Howard,
This is one of the biggest travesties to ever hit the world.
It is the one.
It's certainly the biggest travesty.
In our lifetime.
I cannot believe it.
I'm disgusted by humans and we better take care of business or we're all lost.
Yeah,
our way of life will be destroyed.
We are now,
now we have to sit and fear.
Now it's time to get busy.
If we sit and fear,
we deserve to have our lives destroyed.
Right,
don't sit and listen to these other countries like,
France,
you fakes!
Wait and see.
Yeah,
how many times did we bail their ass out?
They house terrorists, too.
Oh,
absolutely.
Get rid of them, too.
.planes. That was involved in this disaster. This morning,
apparently, both towers of the World Trade Center are hit by aircraft,
and additionally,
a report that a plane has crashed into the Pentagon this morning.
Last week,
the lighthouse has been evacuated...
President Bush was not there when all of this occurred.
He was at a school in- We're trying to get this right now.
But I don't think we can,
and it's not safe.
Everybody get this guy out of the way.
Your successor,
George Pataki,
is in New York City right now.
There are a number of state offices,
aren't there,
Governor,
in the Twin Towers?
Oh, yes,
my office.
My office and
I think the governor moved his office out of the World Trade Center,
Governor Pataki.
But my office was there, and
I think there are still some other offices there,
but not as many as there were when I was governor.
Be prepared to take it. And then everything's being shut down.
Baltimore has it.
Okay,
National,
are you up?
No,
I'm up now,
Becky.
Are you in the tower?
Yes.
What's going on?
There's a 737,
I think it was,
crashed into the Pentagon.
Off of National?
No.
Where did he come from?
He came in from the West.
Came in from the West?
Untagged.
At 737,
you think?
I think it was 7.
What do you guys think,
737?
737 or 75.
You didn't pick him up on radar?
Yeah,
we did.
We did.
Okay,
but it came in from the west.
Right.
Okay.
Thanks.
All right.
I was destroyed.
Right.
Don't sit and listen to these other countries like,
France,
you fakes!
Wait and see.
Yeah,
how many times do we fill their ass out?
Neha was terrorist,
too.
Oh,
absolutely.
Get rid of them,
too.
You know what?
Just blow them all up.
There's debris falling onto the street from the World Trade Center.
Flames and smoke from both towers.
.and. Come to a standstill,
everyone just standing,
looking at the smoke pouring out of the World Trade Center at this moment.
There are certain people trying to call their families.
All the cell phones are down,
and you can't imagine since they are the tribe.
And that's the World Trade Center...
Cleveland,
stock 4870,
Any idea how long this will be before we get turned in the general right direction?
Just curious.
Hey,
stock 4870,
there's an aircraft that we've lost communications with.
Potential hazard to you, and we're vectoring you away from his direction, we're not sure of his altitude or, uh, where he intends to go here. All right, that sounds good to me, then that's a good plan if you ask me. Thanks for the info, Roger. Have the, uh, we have a man named
Sean on the line, who?
I'm sorry, sir, your name please? uh, Sean Lansdowne, What'd you see, Sean?
I'm sitting in my bedroom back at home, and um, where's that, sir? It's right in Arlington. I'm like four minutes, three, four minutes away from the Pentagon, right? And I was sitting in my living room and my building started shaking and I knew that no, no plane supposed to make my building shake. Well, when I turned around and looked up, I see this plane. And I agree with the young lady that was just speaking.
It was like a 757.
Sean,
we're going to stop.
stop.
The woman.
Oh,
no.
Any time you see something going fast like that?
Yeah.
That is a shame.
You know what it is?
It's that damn smoke.
Yeah,
it's smoke.
That's right.
Aaron,
I'm standing in Lafayette Park, directly across from the White House,
perhaps about 200 yards from the White House residence itself.
The secret Service has pushed most people all the way back to the other side of the park. Trying to avoid having that done to me at the moment.
Just moments ago,
they started slowly evacuating the White House about 30 minutes ago.
And then in the last five minutes,
people have come running out of the White House. And the old Executive Office building,
which is the office building right directly across from the White House.
About 10 minutes ago,
there was a white jet circling overhead.
Now,
you generally don't see planes in the area over the White House.
That is restricted airspace.
No reason to believe that this jet was there for any nefarious purposes.
But the Secret Service was very concerned,
pointing up at the jet in the sky.
It is out of.
Site now,
best we can tell,
But they've evacuated the entire White House staff and the old executive office,
as well as some townhouses that are government offices.
Many of our viewers might know Blair House,
where other international leaders stay when they are in Washington.
That block of townhouses has been evacuated as well,
and they are pushing us.
Now back toward H Street,
which is the next main street to the north from Pennsylvania Avenue, across from the White House.
John,
hang on one second.
We're also getting reports at the Capitol.
Look at his big camera.
You'll tell your grandchildren.
You were there.
You were there,
although this will probably be happening every day when you get old.
Really?
This is like the movie Brazil.
Wow,
there's a photo for National Geographic.
Right,
what's next?
What is next?
I never thought the Pentagon...
See,
you can't get...
There's no getting off Manhattan now,
everything's closed.
If they plan three,
they can do five.
Oh yeah.
They could be all day long with this.
This could be going on every day now unless we act swiftly and no investigation.
You know what countries hate us.
You see what I say?
See,
I'm always,
you know,
considered an extremist.
But I say, you declare war on everybody, and then whoever surrenders doesn't get killed.
Right.
But how do you kill every son and child?
I would!
Because they grow up to be terrorists!
You know which countries have to be flattened out.
They're in collusion.
I think we gotta get out of here.
Let's go!
It's the police!
We're under arrest!
Everybody, please get on the sidewalk.
Clear the street.
Let's go!
The hell is this?
Come on!
See you!
What's that?
I read the notifications,
mate.
What's that?
I saw,
what's the telephone number waiting for our FC to pick up?
What's the telephone number you're calling?
It's the AOC.
441-2623.
26. 23.
They're going 150th corner,
northwest corner,
right?
Right.
That number 2 well traced.
There's a guy here.
There's a guy hanging off the side of the building.
He's here now?
You can see something there.
Where?
Right in the middle of the left tower,
just below the black.
No,
no,
it's just a lens.
It's 500 meters.
You can see something there.
Where?
Right in the middle of the left tower,
just below the black one.
No,
no,
it's just a lens.
It's 500 million.
I haven't used this lens in six years.
I don't see the two guys.
I can see them from here.
From here?
Yeah,
from the lens.
Where did you see them?
Did you see them on the camera?
Yeah.
But I think that could also be the breathing,
the hanging out.
Might be debris,
might be people.
That's debris.
Is that debris?
Is it debris or people?
You see something here?
Yeah.
Oh.
Yeah,
people probably,
right?
That's debris.
Debris?
You see constantly falling down.
Because Dave Statter is now on the scene.
We've heard from others that it's a 757.
Dave,
are you there?
I'm here.
The west side of the Pentagon,
the helicopter port off of Washington Boulevard,
plane into the side of the building.
There's a bit of a hole on that side of the building.
All it's in fire and rescue,
military fire on the scene,
putting foam on it.
The plane did not seem to go into the building, like the World Trade Center attacks.
It seemed more to glance the side of it and certainly do some damage to the left side of the building.
But it's right if anybody's coming up Washington.
Boulevard,
which is still open,
amazingly,
northbound.
It's right where the helipad is.
Believe this when I tell you,
everybody here is scanning the skies, looking for a possible attack.
Every fire and rescue crew has been told to beware of that.
Every police officer has been told to beware of that.
We cannot tell you at the moment,
and as far as casualties,
any injuries at the moment.
Dave,
So it hit more of the helipad than it did the building?
Well,
it definitely hit the building,
certainly.
But it did not seem to be a gaping...
Hole like we saw at the World Trade Center.
I can't even tell you what size plane it is because it's pretty much consumed.
Should be getting a live picture from us shortly.
We're trying to call it in now.
We do have a microwave truck,
so we should be able to give you some live pictures and you can look for yourself.
Right now,
it looks like National Airport Fire Department.
Is that or is it?
I can't tell yet.
It's Metropolitan Airport Fire Department putting foam on this side of the Pentagon to try to put out the fire.
A few minutes ago,
there was still a great amount of fire.
The fire has lessened somewhat.
All right.
Get a picture up.
All right,
Dave,
we'll let you go for just a second.
I want to tell you, the White House has been evacuated.
The entire White House.
.a.t. This point.
Everyone's still trying to figure out what's going on.
I ran into this woman named Susan.
She was supposed to be in the World Trade Center today at this very moment.
I'm going to take you to the hospital.
Air Force one is now leaving Sarasota,
Florida,
on its way back to Washington,
D.C.
But let me just read directly the bulletin from Associated Press.
The White House was evacuated today after the Secret Service received credible threat of a terrorist act against the presidential mansion.
Call a fire.
Oh, please,
will you?
It's fire department,
four away.
Fire?
This is 15- Let me talk to the caller,
PD.
15-97.
Let me talk to the caller.
Where is he?
He's on the line.
Let me talk to him.
Where's the fire,
sir?
Oh,
it was smoke.
3-0-105-2-PIRE.
Alright,
sit tight.
We'll get to you as soon as we can.
Yeah,
he's just throwing up.
The smoke's really bad,
man.
That's all we can do.
Where are you?
What's throwing you guys up to?
We're getting there.
It doesn't feel like it,
man.
I got young kids.
I understand that,
sir.
We're on the way.
He's on the 150th floor.
I don't know.
No problem.
You're an operator?
Yeah.
Come on,
man.
I know you're stupid because I'm seeing that you need to have these lots of people abused.
I understand.
Reports at the Capitol,
the Treasury building also being evacuated.
John,
is this evacuation from the White House,
was it orderly?
Did it seem panicky?
How would you characterize it?
It started off as orderly,
much like we get when there are occasional bomb scares near the White House,
but then...
Again,
in the last 10 minutes or so,
the people who came out. The last several hundred I saw leaving the grounds were told and ordered by the Secret Service to run.
They were running through the gates.
These are,
of course,
professionals in business suits.
I'm also told that prior to that,
and we don't know the current situation,
that the virus...
The vice president and other administration officials on the scene were meeting in the White House situation Room,
which is in the basement of the White House.
Whether they have stayed on the complex or not is unknown to us at this moment.
I spoke to an administration official shortly after the president delivered his statement,
who said,
obviously,
the operating assumption here is terrorism.
The initial assumption,
this official said,
was that this had something to do,
or at least they were looking into any possible connections with Osama Bin Laden.
The administration recently released a warning that they thought Osama Bin Laden might strike out against U.S.
targets.
Keep moving,
please keep moving.
Let's go.
To us.
So it is not something far away.
It is coming right here at us, as we can see today, in these extremely dramatic events that are totally unexpected.
I don't think that we have ever had a day when the White House,
the Capitol, would ever quit it.
Professor,
let me interrupt you for just a second because we have yet another development here.
The State Department is being evacuated.
The building is being evacuated again.
Not that there's been an incident there.
Let's clarify that.
Precaution.
Is this a precautionary?
From that floor up,
man.
A lot of people died.
I know you go out in the building and you're in the top.
Smoke rises,
you can hear it there.
We're on the floor,
we're in a window.
And then I read the green light.
Can't see.
Okay.
Just try to hang it there.
I'm gonna save it.
It's really easy for you to stay here in an air conditioned building.
What the hell happened?
Okay,
I'm still here.
He's been trying to fly the car and he's trying to get to you.
Does it feel like it?
Okay,
try to calm down so you can conserve your oxygen,
okay?
Try to,
try to...
It took time to blow you in from the left.
We're going to go back to our Sam Fort,
who's at Reagan National right now.
We understand the FAA has taken some action.
Sam,
can you tell us what it is?
Yes,
Carol.
Because of this situation,
the FAA has shut down all aircraft flight...
Across the country.
They,
I think it is a situation where it is too dangerous.
Right here at National Airport,
you normally would have planes taking off and landing.
There are no planes taking off or landing here.
The skies are clear and there is smoke covering the air.
This gentleman is named Todd Nelson.
You were just picking up, what?
Debris.
What is it?
Some sort of...
It looks like insulation.
I was just standing here, watching and all sorts of paper and debris and insulation.
I'm sorry,
yeah.
This is what...
All sorts of paper and debris and insulation were just flying down,
landing on us over here.
And it's just amazing.
Yeah,
some sort of insulation or some sort of debris that looks,
appears to have come from the Pentagon crash coming through the air.
You could see papers flying through the air,
things like that.
So that's the word from here.
FAA has shut down air traffic across the country because of this situation.
Understand.
Not safe.
It's not safe here.
You want to head uptown,
you get a shot uptown,
but it's not safe here.
Do me a favor,
move.
All right.
Okay?
All right,
Mick,
thank you very much.
We want to move a couple of miles away from you right now, to the White House,
where Bob Kerr is standing by.
And Bob,
we understand that building has now been evacuated.
Let me just read,
while we're listening to Jim Miklaszewski,
another eyewitness,
Paul Begala,
Democratic consultant,
was near.
Near the Pentagon, and, uh...
He said This is to quote. It's a huge. It was a huge fireball, a huge orange fireball, uh...
At the Pentagon, another witness, uh...
Told him a helicopter exploded. But the
the best information we're getting is from an Associated reporter, who said,
quote,
I saw the tail of a large airliner.
It plowed right into the Pentagon.
There is billowing black smoke.
And, of course,
there you see it on the television screen.
Two of them,
actually.
OK,
Chris,
do you know about the FedEx?
I don't yet,
but go ahead.
OK,
he's a PAY-2.
He's eight miles northwest.
He's coming in on a visual to...
What's your address?
23,
White House,
233,
And I have Kelly, Foxtrot,
Mike, Delta,
Echo,
PH,
and Kelly.
Okay,
he called on the 97 line a couple of minutes ago.
He's coming back to you, too.
Bye,
thanks.
KM.
The White House has been evacuated as well.
CNN's John King joins us on the follow-up.
John.
Aaron,
I'm standing in Rockland Park, directly across from the White House,
perhaps about 200 yards from the White House residence itself.
Receiving services push most people all the way back to the other side of the park.
I do avoid that.
It has touched me at the moment.
Just moments ago,
they started...
If you can hold on for just one second,
We want to listen in,
Governor,
to Jim Mikulaczewski,
who is reporting from the area of the Pentagon.
The Pentagon,
again,
has been evacuated.
The second floor buckled upward,
and then the third...
Floor above him actually collapsed downward.
The scene on the other side of the building,
as it's being described to us,
there are people being removed on stretchers.
Security forces are evacuating the building right now.
And according to the officials here at the Pentagon.
They still don't know exactly what it was,
but as you reported,
Katie,
eyewitnesses reported that, in fact, it was a plane that crashed into the Pentagon.
And Mick,
any idea,
I wasn't quite sure if you said this,
about the number of people who might have been hurt or worse in this?
No idea at all,
Katie.
As you know,
having worked here on any given day,
this is a small city,
25,000 to 30,000 people may be working.
Here at any one time.
That portion of the Pentagon,
by the way,
had just been remodeled and just reopened.
If the crash had occurred just a few months ago,
that section of the
Pentagon would have been virtually empty.
But at this time of day,
early morning or mid-morning,
the Pentagon's very busy.
It's impossible to say how many casualties there may be,
but there have been.
A large number of people cited being removed on stretchers.
And again,
as one survivor said,
the floor just buckled up under him and the roof caved in on him.
What do you mean?
Hijack 767,
American Airliner.
As regards to that report,
the New York Stock Exchange was evacuated.
It is close.
That's probably not a bad thing.
I'd like to see a future without a massive amount of...
Just to add...
Add, John, a bit to what you've been saying. We're getting a report from Associated Press now that the White House was evacuated after the Secret Service received. What AP is describing is a credible, excuse me, a credible threat of a terrorist attack against the White House itself. Okay,
I saw this plane going out of control and then hitting the tower. And
then, like 20 minutes after, I just saw another plane coming on the backside, making a huge turn and then hitting the other tower.
Where was the first plane coming from?
From north.
What did the plane look like?
Like a 737,
like a jet plane.
Like a jet plane,
I mean, like a normal plane,
commercial plane.
It appeared to be...
It was apparently going out of control, like before they hit the building. Like if someone tried to get out of the way. And then
it was really like if someone was telling the pilot, go straight and hit the tower.
United,
like, probably like the French and blue sign.
Wow.
It's just like there's bodies everywhere falling down.
There are bodies falling down?
Yes,
you see it.
I mean,
people just throwing themselves through the...
The name is Kwame.
It's K-W-A-M-E.
EDUC.
About 30 minutes ago,
and then in the last five minutes,
people have come running out of the White House and the old executive office building.
The building, which is the office building, right directly across from the White House.
About ten minutes ago,
there was a white jet circling overhead.
Now you generally don't see planes in the area over the
White House.
That is restricted airspace.
No reason to believe.
Most probably of what is happening here,
but I wouldn't just limit it to the conflict between the Israelis and the Palestinians.
I think that there is the whole issue of the sanctions against Iraq.
There is still the whole issue of Afghanistan,
Syria.
Syria,
Iran,
and other areas where a conflict between the U.S.
And the western world and Islam is festering.
So I think that it will take some very bold steps and deep engagement on the part of the Bush administration.
Stay here,
please,
move it out.
Please,
please,
let's go,
move it out,
please,
move it out.
The world has changed in a good light.
Today, we are standing on a meeting that was done with us before we came here to the World Trade Center.
We are now in a second light,
in the measures of the second generation of the World Trade Center.
Everything is so much better.
The plane, apparently...
.The. Flight has been evacuated.
.The. Treasury also having been evacuated,
but we have not heard of yet...
.The. Flight has been evacuated.
Does anybody else want to try it in here?
We're young men,
we're not ready to die.
I don't care.
I don't care,
I'm gonna get my ass down,
I need oxygen.
They're going to see,
they have a lot of apparatus on them.
If you guys ever see a naked lady,
you get them in from all over.
They're going from Jersey,
I don't give a shit.
I'm sorry.
Mine's Cosgrove.
I must have called about a dozen times already.
C-O-S-G-R-O-V-E.
My wife thinks, I'm all right.
I called and said I was leaving the building.
I was fine.
I'm banged.
It's really frustrating.
My Delta Echo.
C-O-S-G-R-O-V-E.
My wife thinks, I'm all right.
I called and said I was leaving the building.
I was fine.
I'm banged.
It's really frustrating.
I don't have to echo.
So we have traffic out there that's heading your way.
He's about 20 miles behind you right now.
We think he's at 7,500,
and it is a
United 757,
and we think he's at 7,500.
I'll keep you advised.
Okay,
Mike,
go back.
Very good.
Okay.
3,000 on the data.
Stay here.
We're going to leave the air.
Let's go.
We're walking to the east side of the United States.
All units,
stand by.
We're heading to field com,
urgent.
We're heading to field com.
Tower number two,
19th floor,
firefighter down.
Tower number two,
19th floor,
firefighter down.
There's debris flying right outside the window.
They say debris is flying to Brooklyn.
Papers and stuff.
You watching the news?
And you can see the flames.
Oh,
God.
And Brian works here.
Brian Vandepoel works in the World Trade Center.
Where?
Call the city wide.
If you are here west,
let's see if West is the thing that you're prepared for.
Look at the wide,
because what's unique about our shot is this mass of people.
Shut up!
This is now over an hour after the initial blast,
about an hour after the secondary blast.
Guys say,
you know,
it's not an accident.
We're not two bikes,
we're one baby.
Seriously fucking bad.
This is the worst thing I've ever,
you know,
it's the worst thing I've ever.
No,
this is just the beginning of it.
$35.01,
essential.
No,
I'm talking about it.
This is really fucked up.
Apparently, they got the Pentagon.
Sounds like there's a major assault going on.
Let's see.
Did you see those white flickering things over there?
That's the only one on the spot.
What?
Well,
they always have terrorists.
The specific location on the Tribal bridge was a bomb down there right now.
Exactly.
You're a serious shit, dude.
I've been here on the top floor in the trap,
I can't get down.
See how many of these bags have been moved?
That's a force of love.
Yeah,
but most of us are friends.
They're not letting us out of the bag.
You can't go back that way.
You know, I want to walk over to touch,
but Keith's over there.
You can't even walk that way because that's the route before they hit us.
I thought it was church when it was locked down.
And they said that they walked the fifth one.
I don't have my hat on.
Where's my hat?
I'm walking on 3rd Street and Church.
Yeah,
please.
Hello everyone.
I'm here at the
this is the one.
I see it!
Tell them that I am the one!
Hi,
how are you?
How's it going?
Are you the news or something?
Uh-huh.
Thank you,
gentlemen.
We speak church.
What are we speaking?
Oh.
In where?
In the city.
I don't know.
We're just talking about where everybody can walk.
Like you are.
See?
I know.
That's the thing.
That's why I'm looking out here.
I said, you're behind the line.
I'm not.
This is what I'm saying.
This is great.
I'm going to give you track control on that. United 93.
Alright,
thank you.
Okay,
this is 766.
They said he's going to Morgan Damage.
That's okay.
Okay,
Charlie Foxtrot,
Mike,
Delta Echo,
sir,
you're good to go.
John,
tell me when you're able to.
That's okay.
If you could take a look or have somebody in the back, take a look and see. If you see traffic,
he would be in your 5 o'clock position in 10 miles.
We think he's at 8,000 feet.
Mike Deldeco is looking at negative contact at this time.
You said you wanted us to go direct Johnstown?
Direct to Johnstown,
sir.
You can start that descent again.
Mike DelDeco.
Sir,
I've lost the primary on this guy, too.
I think he's to your south now,
though,
but I'll keep you advised.
Thank you,
and we're still negative contact.
They're looking at
5 o'clock.
We have another eyewitness on the phone right now.
His name is Charles Tanner.
Mr.
Tanner,
tell us what you saw.
I was in the,
I live in the overlook apartment and I was doing some exercise,
jump, roping,
And this plane came increasingly fast,
almost close to,
it was headed this direction,
hit the building that I'm in,
which is an eight-story building,
But it was aiming for the...
In the direction of the Pentagon. And then all of a sudden I see this puff of smoke. And I just ran over to Columbia to get a better view of it.
So, Charles, you didn't actually see it hit, you just saw it to a point, and then you saw the smoke?
I just saw this plane coming very, very fast, going to that point.
That direction as I was listening to you guys talk about what happened at the World Trade Center.
And where you live,
obviously,
it's close enough to Reagan National,
but that's not a flight path you normally see.
Right.
Well,
I'm closer to the Pentagon than to Reagan National.
Okay.
But obviously,
planes flying over there on a daily basis.
This is usually not the flight path of any aircraft.
Mr.
Tanner,
we do have more information about exactly where that plane crashed.
We understand right now from the AP that it crashed near a helicopter landing pad near the Pentagon.
ON.
We know it didn't crash directly into the Pentagon.
But did you see it?
No,
I don't.
I just see metals and everything coming down.
That's all I see.
Can I talk to you for a second?
So you saw this,
right?
Can you guys come over here,
please?
A Palestinian organization,
the DFLP,
was said to have been responsible,
but a senior official for that organization has denied responsibility.
So at the present,
we do not know who was responsible for these attacks. In the United States, at the World Trade Center in New York and at the Pentagon in Washington.
How's it look?
Good.
Division
3 Lobby Command to the Field Comm Command post.
Operations Tower 1 to Battalion 9.
Battalion 9 to command post.
Battalion 7, Operations, Tower 1 to Battalion 9. I need you on the floor, folks. 79.
We have access stairs going up to 79.
Ok.
Alright,
Mom,
I'm on my way up,
where are you?
From where you are,
Mr.
Tanner,
are you okay?
Are you safe?
Oh,
well,
unless the plane decides to hit this building,
yes,
I think I'm very safe.
Can you believe that this is happening in Washington,
D.C.,
Mr.
Tanner?
I want to say yes,
ma'am.
I understand, though,
okay,
because of different terrorist activities and things of that nature, and because of what happened at the World Trade Center,
I would say that it doesn't surprise me.
I'm just a little shaken that it has happened.
And I'm not sure when we talk about that helicopter pad, if it's the...
It's the one that's on the west side, where you drive by all the time on the main street. That you can see if there's another one there as well. That a lot of folks go by on a daily basis.
We quickly want to recap before we return it to
ABC News.
The State Department has now been evacuated.
The White House has been evacuated.
The Capitol has been evacuated.
There was a credible threat to the mansion,
which I'm talking about the White House here,
and so the entire White House has now been evacuated.
Now we're looking back at the Pentagon again.
You can see the smoke billowing from there.
We have a...
No other information at this point about casualties or injuries, or exactly what it was that smashed into the Pentagon earlier today.
That happened,
what,
25 minutes ago,
20 minutes ago?
Something of that sort.
One of the other pictures we saw where she saw a...
What observers noted, and those they were in the airline industry, so we kind of take what they're saying for at the word 757 American Airlines. They could see the plane, they could see the markings crashed into the west side of the Pentagon, near the heliport.
This is a live picture we're just getting here.
This is the firefighters battling the blaze at the Pentagon.
Look.
So you can see the damage.
This is just going to be raw tape that Dave Stater and his crew are feeding in.
Just feeding in to us.
You can see this terrorist,
apparent terrorist attack,
a jet slammed into the Pentagon about 15 minutes ago.
15,
20 minutes ago,
the helipad side on 395.
We have no word yet on casualties.
Hillcombe,
K.
I'm Building 2,
93rd floor,
northwest corner.
Also in building
1, 93rd floor,
southwest corner,
K.
Hillcombe,
I also have 2 oil trees,
105 floor,
60 people.
Central.
And they said that they want the pinball.
Where am I at?
I'm on Green
Street and Church.
Ashley,
are you still in Manhattan?
I'm in Manhattan,
Chris,
and I'm just walking...
Looking southward towards the
World Trade Center,
it's just an incredible sight.
The streets of Manhattan are chock full of people who are stopped where they,
exactly where they were in the middle of their commute,
standing,
gaping,
and looking at this sight.
It is unbelievable.
I can see vehicles all throughout Manhattan,
not only Midtown,
but down near Chelsea. now,
where I am,
have been streaming by us at every couple of seconds,
an interval.
Ambulances are heading by me now.
A lot of the vehicles are also unmarked,
looking like FBI vehicles heading towards the World Trade Center as well.
Not only that,
but we stopped by one of the hospitals,
St.
Vincent,
which has been cordoned off.
I can only guess,
possibly waiting for victims to be caught.
Look,
you want to be careful here.
We don't want to get...
The BUSINESSES.
The businesses are not too far ahead of this. But obviously,
this has all the appearances of an extraordinarily
well coordinated and devastating
terrorist attack here in the United STATES.
Certainly nothing like it since Oklahoma City, and nothing like it here in New York
since the terrorist attack of the same
World Trade Center buildings in February
of
1993. Of whatever this operation is.
Has been, and look, look,
look, something just fell off.
military. In full fatigue.
Outside the White House.
Outside the White House,
fully loaded and ready to go for anything.
We expect that Banjuliani is going to be speaking shortly,
as you can imagine.
I'm sure there is a scene of much confusion now at downtown in Bowman,
outside the World Trade Center towers.
We have just been told that the Pentagon is being evacuated.
I'm not sure if it's working.
I think it's working.
I don't have a
TV at home.
I don't think it's working.
What?
I think it's working.
Hey,
zoom in,
there's still room inside.
Yeah.
It's a little too much.
Michael,
I'm on the grounds, right across from the Pentagon,
and what I can tell you is it is still on fire.
There is black smoke just billowing throughout the
Pentagon grounds.
There are several hundred employees on the ground.
They are crying,
hugging each other.
I see about 15 different pieces of fire apparatus.
I see ladders.
It's just a scene of utter chaos out here.
Traffic.
It's still getting by in front of the Pentagon,
but most of this roadway has been shut down.
They were going to land in the Gordia and ended up hitting one of the trade towers.
I don't know about the second place.
I guess the Pentagon is off the table.
So the other plane was hijacked.
I didn't hear that.
Yeah,
I mean...
See that fire?
Fire that just fell?
Yeah,
like molten metal.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I haven't seen something like that.
Drop it.
You can see it.
Thank you.
We were down in the subway, trying to at least take the subway to get downtown to the Wall Street area,
the World Trade Center area.
And the subway announcer came over the loudspeaker, saying due to a police investigation,
subway traffic will be stopped between a certain area.
So most of the people in the subway weren't able to get downtown either.
15-0-Z to 15.
The Pentagon has been evacuated,
as has the White House and the U.S.
Capitol building at Blair Mansion.
Before this happened at the Pentagon,
President Bush went on the air to talk about the response,
the U.S.
response,
in light of the World Trade Center.
But again,
this is what happened right after. He said we were going to hunt down the folks responsible for the apparent terrorist attack in New York City.
And shortly after that,
this is what happened at the Pentagon in Arlington.
We're just getting across the wires.
In Los Angeles.
Police departments there are on tactical alert,
but there have been no threats in Los Angeles that police are aware of.
But as you can imagine,
major American cities are on heightened alert.
And Los Angeles is saying we are on citywide tactical alert and have mobilized their anti-terrorist division.
The Federal Aviation Administration has actually gone even further than it did a few minutes ago.
It was forming all,
asking all planes not to take off.
Now, the FAA has ordered all aircraft currently in the air over the United States to land.
Land at the nearest airport.
Now you can imagine what may be happening, or what they think might be happening in some part of the country. That there is somebody else on some aircraft, coming from somewhere, or going somewhere with
with evil in there,
with evil intentions,
and so. All aircraft currently in the air over the United States have been ordered to land at the nearest airport.
Street in the church.
What are we seeing here?
Oh.
We have hours.
In the red.
Wow.
We're going to have all these people in the red in the city.
Well,
see.
Audrey,
let me interrupt you to explain what people are seeing, because I'm not sure if you...
You can see the picture.
We do have a picture now where we can see some people,
and we can also see the flames and the smoke that you're talking about. And some of the emergency equipment.
This is the first time we have seen that.
So please go on,
Audrey,
from your vantage point, with what you are seeing.
But we can now see flames.
We see emergency crews.
And just a moment ago,
we also did see some people there.
So,
Audrey,
go right ahead.
Audrey Barnes,
are you still with us?
We'll try to recode.
We've lost that in a moment.
If we can,
I'm not sure.
Do we control this camera?
If we can get them to pan back to the left here,
let's try to see what detail that we can.
Apparently we've lost that picture as well.
It's a camera that we don't control,
but it's showing you there are active flames at the Pentagon,
and you can see,
obviously,
some of the...
Workers there watching this incredible scene unfold there at the Pentagon.
We'll try to get you a number on exactly how many people do currently work in that building.
I'll hold that online on somebody.
Well,
nobody's going to be around there. ...
Into the World Trade Center,
A second crash into the second tunnel of the World Trade Center.
We're going to have a plane that's crashed into the Pentagon.
It has one activated on the first line of the Pentagon.
Look at that.
It's a fire sight.
United, 93, is 2-0 miles northwest of Johnstown.
2-0 miles northwest on primary?
Well,
that's a report from another aircraft.
Can you hear us,
Walter?
Here we are, about two blocks away from...
Okay,
two blocks away from where the whole thing happened,
And this entire area has been cordoned off,
and people that have been working in nearby buildings have been told to evacuate.
That's what this mass exodus is to my left-hand side.
To my right,
we have two witnesses,
and as we speak with you two,
we're going to pan up and show a shot of what we...
We see from this vantage POINT.
First, Marna, Ringle and Marna, you work across the STREET.
Tell me exactly what you saw on the street, and as you looked up, what you saw, because you said, you saw the second ONE,
am I CORRECT?
NO,
I didn't see the second ONE.
Actually was coming out of the building and there was maybe about 30 or 40 people.
People at the bottom of one world financial covered in blood.
I did not expect that at all. And I worked for Lehman in one right here, and a gentleman that I worked with was on the telephone.
He said,
What was that?
I said,
you know,
he thought it was thunder.
I looked over and screamed,
it was a bomb because I saw a piece of the building flow down. And I think I scared my entire floor because I can scream pretty loud and it was pretty bad.
The firefighters are putting them in the CAR.
They are not going to be able to get out of the CAR.
They are not going to be
Well,
Aaron,
there is a lot of confusion here at the Pentagon.
It appears that something hit the Pentagon on the outside of the 5th Corridor,
on the Army Corridor.
Several army officers I talked to reported hearing a big explosion.
Seeing shards of metal coming past their window.
The Pentagon has been evacuated.
Emergency services personnel were rushing to reports of several people trapped in the building.
Most of the building's 24,000 people are outside of the building or in the center courtyard as emergency teams try to sort out what has happened here.
There is,
of course,
thick black smoke billowing from the scene.
Both locations now.
35-01,
CFI's supposedly at Queens.
I think, if anything, it's people waving pieces of paper.
Yeah,
on the way,
yeah.
Yeah,
but I don't think they would be surviving.
I thought I could split it out.
Who knows?
You can focus it.
Yeah,
I know.
It may actually be the helicopter going on top.
Can you see the helicopter?
Yeah,
on the back.
On the North tower.
Oh,
above it,
yeah.
Let's go back to Dave Statter, with more from the site of the Pentagon.
Dave.
Can you hear me now?
We can.
All right,
I'm here with Michael Kelly,
who was a witness to this attack at the Pentagon.
I'm going to let him describe what he saw here,
I guess,
about 20 minutes ago with me,
Michael Kelly.
First of all,
let me...
Let me just first describe the scene.
This is the west side of the Pentagon,
the heliport side off of Washington Boulevard.
Were you driving or what?
Yes,
I was in the traffic on the 14th Street Bridge, right at the Pentagon, tied up, going into town.
And I heard this plane come over my head.
It was really slow.
What size plane?
It sounded like a small plane,
but it was very,
very slow.
Very low. And the next thing I know there was this tremendous explosion as it hit the Pentagon.
I looked right,
I looked over and those the smoke started coming up.
Pieces of the plane were and pieces of Pentagon were falling onto the 14th Street, onto the
Shirley Highway.
Very scary.
So I decided not to go across the 14th Street Bridge.
I came around,
and I wound up here,
stopped in the traffic right at the Pentagon.
I was trying to get back over to Memorial Bridge,
but no luck.
Had you known about the World Trade Center?
Oh,
yeah,
I was listening to WTOP Radio the whole time.
Then this thing came right over my head and it plowed.
It was clearly a similar situation to what happened in New York.
I've seen that ape come through the back side of the tower,
I guess that would be the south side of the tower,
and then the smoke and flame coming out the front side.
Um,
again,
that was about a half hour after the first attack was,
was it a pilot?
O-S-T-A-U.
A-R-U.
Right.
That's the office we're in.
There's three of us in here.
O-S-T-A-R-U.
Look at your name.
Hello?
Hello.
Look at your name.
We're looking at all.
We're looking at Financial center.
Two dreamers.
Two broken windows.
Oh,
God!
Oh!
Message number 100.
You mentioned that you saw people on the road outside of the building.
Explain that scene.
I saw,
there's maybe about 30 or 40 people covered with bandages and blood.
It looks like a lot of them were either on the floor of one of the exchanges.
There's actually,
oh my God!
Oh my
God!
I'm not sure exactly what happened,
but it was another explosion on the far side of one of the buildings from where we're standing.
The reverberation and another explosion on the right-hand side.
Oh, shit!
Oh
my god!
Hey!
Ah!
No way!
It's gone!
The bridge is in trouble!
Oh,
it's in trouble!
The ones down there are in trouble!
Yeah...
16 people...
Shit!
Oh my god.
Here goes the tower!
Fuck that shit!
It's gonna be awesome.
It's gonna last.
Take one,
take one and two,
one.
This is as close as we can get to the base of the World Trade Center.
You can see the two towers.
Debris continues to fall and to rain on the people below.
There are people hanging from the windows 90 stories up,
and a number of bodies have actually hit the pavement.
Take two.
Take two and two.
One.
This is as close as we can get to the base of the World Trade Center.
You can see the firemen assembled here,
the police officers,
FBI agents,
and you can see the two towers.
A huge explosion now,
raining debris on all of us.
We better get out of the way!
Think about it,
Joe.
We've got to get back down.
There's no way we can move.
Holy shit!
Oh my god!
The whole world just fell!
Oh!
I'm gonna call you back.
Oh my god!
It's all of them falling!
The other one's falling, too!
Is it?
Oh, shit!
Oh my god!
Get it off,
baby.
The whole thing just fell.
Oh my God.
Oh, shit!
Let's get out.
You ain't gonna get out now.
You can't get out on the street now.
Where you gonna go?
Look at that!
Don't go on the street.
Look,
I think we should get away from this window, first of all.
S-o-D-1 Central.
Okay.
S-o-D-1 for location.
S-O-D-1 Central,
S-O-D-1.
S-o-d-1 on air.
S-O-D-1,
C-Y Central,
S-O-D-1 on air.
Oh!
Oh,
my God.
Oh my God.
I told you I wasn't going to make it.
Oh, my Lord,
have mercy.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, God.
Yep.
Oh, Lord.
Well,
here's the deal.
The one out of Selfridge,
the two birds out of Selfridge,
they just did a quick turn.
They got no weapons.
They just went around strafing around up to the range.
They blew all their load.
I know,
but we got two.
They're loitering,
and we're going to send them down and do an investigation.
Two from Selfridge are airborne already.
I got two more from Toledo that special tracks over the,
what do you call it,
over the lake right now.
So,
what are we going to do with it if it isn't?
What are we gonna do?
I gotta get in my guy's direction.
There's a lot of confusion.
The Defense Protective Service,
which is the police force here in the Pentagon,
has been urging people to get out of the building and move away from the scene so they can handle the emergency situation.
Again,
it appears that an aircraft of some sort did hit the building.
Hit the side of the Pentagon,
the west front,
which faces sort of toward Arlington National Cemetery.
It's a corridor where a lot of army offices are located.
Wow.
And some people were...
Jamie,
I need you to stop for a second.
There has just been...
A huge explosion.
We can see a billowing smoke rising.
And I can't,
I'll tell you that I can't see that second tower,
But there was a cascade of sparks and fire.
And now this,
it looks almost like a mushroom cloud explosion,
this huge, billowing smoke in the second tower.
This was the second of the two towers hit.
And I,
you know,
I cannot see behind that smoke,
obviously,
the first time you see the
tower in front has not CHANGED.
And we see this extraordinarily and frightening scene behind us
of this second tower,
now just encased in SMOKE.
What is behind IT,
I cannot tell YOU.
But just look at THAT.
That is about as frightening a scene as you will ever see.
Have not made much of a dent in this fire.
I don't even know how much fire equipment they've been able to move up onto those upper floors.
Oh,
it's just coming down,
Pat.
It is just coming down.
Watch the right side.
It's exploding.
It's ripping apart.
It is billowing.
Pat,
the debris is flying.
I'm going to run.
Okay.
They're moving from the scene.
There's a lot of confusion.
The Defense Protective Service,
which is the police force here in the Pentagon,
has been urging people to get out of the building and move away from the scene so they can handle the emergency situation.
At the end,
it appears...
That an aircraft of some sort did hit the side of the Pentagon.
You know,
the left front,
which is sort of a third-party command,
the Sun's Pentagon,
it's a part of a lot of army offices that were there in the back.
And suddenly,
you see that?
And it's a huge explosion.
You can see a building smoke rising.
And I can't...
I'm afraid that I can't see that.
There are injured people here.
We can't tell you how many.
We've certainly seen
Arlington fire and rescue crews,
the paramedics working on somebody in front of us.
We have not heard the number of people injured.
This attack,
as you can see,
did not seem to really penetrate the building.
Holding a great distance, even though there is a great amount of fire on this side of the Pentagon,
which I believe,
as you can compare it to the World Trade Center,
I think the Pentagon has always been called the largest office building in the world.
So there certainly is a comparison there, besides its obviously strategic implications.
Arlington Fire here called in extra equipment.
They've called in the National Airport Foam unit.
Dave?
Dave,
we just want to break in because we want to go back to New York, where
Dan rather is anchoring our coverage. Where one of the towers at the World Trade Center has collapsed.
Please speak to Manhattan Urgent.
Okay,
okay.
One of the buildings is partially collapsed and it holds on to an area of cake.
Transmitting to Urgent,
identified.
Please wait,
I'm gonna make the call out to one of the followers.
Tower,
K.
Tower 2,
Tower 2.
The South Tower,
please record.
10-4.
Put it in the field,
com K.
I
I think one of your things...
Hang on a sec,
John.
I just want to check one thing. Because one of the very first people the president talked to was the director of the FBI,
And Pierre Thomas,
who covers the Justice Department and the FBI for us,
has been here.
They may think they prepare for this kind of...
Of thing here. But man, it must have been a shock, stunning shock. The FBI Special Operations Center is now in full alert, the FBI extremely concerned that there would be additional attacks. Normally, when you have a situation like this, they immediately get on the line with the C.I.A.
Various intelligence agencies, trying to get a sense of who might have been planning something. But right now, the first order of business is to protect against a second attack, third attack. The feeling is normally when you have this kind of situation, there will be more attacks almost immediately. Let's go,
thank you.
Okay.
Yes,
Zolar,
you're on the air.
Oh,
thank God you took my call,
Howard.
Now,
I'm looking at 7,
I'm looking at 5,
I'm looking at 2,
I'm looking at 4.
Let me tell you something,
Howard.
One word I'll do is...
Oh,
no.
Wait a second.
What happened?
Oh,
my God.
What just happened?
Oh,
my God.
What just happened?
Look at that.
Oh,
the whole World Trade Center just collapsed.
Yeah,
I'm looking at it on Channel 7.
Oh,
my God.
The whole thing just completely dropped.
Oh,
my goodness.
It actually collapsed.
That's it.
Oh my...
Anybody who had a chance of getting out of there?
It collapsed.
It's gone.
It doesn't have a chance now.
Are you watching the footage?
Yeah.
Oh,
it's horrific.
The whole thing just collapsed.
What?
Everything around there is in danger.
Let me put up the sound for a second so we can hear what's going on.
We'll call in microphone from Chopper 2 as he takes these pictures.
Jim?
Yes,
I am here,
Michael.
Jim,
tell us what's happening out there.
Oh,
my gosh.
We just witnessed some kind of secondary follow-up explosion on the World Trade Center number two.
Secondary.
On the south, that is difficult to make out through the debris and smoke. But it does appear that a portion, the top portion of the building has collapsed down to the streets below. Oh my gosh, unbelievable we have seen here. The debris and smoke is covering the entire portion
of Lower Manhattan. Oh my gosh,
the building is collapsing.
Oh my god.
Oh,
I think we're okay.
Thank you.
God.
Please,
downstairs,
downstairs building.
Spadalolus,
Building spadalus,
up.
Yo,
spadalus.
Down building.
Smoke,
there is smoke billowing and covering all of the...
I'm telling you,
it's a mess! ...
Lower skyscrapers.
This must have...
Stephen,
what's the latest information we have?
Well,
the latest information is that government buildings around the city,
around Washington,
D.C.,
Have been evacuated.
There is a fire going on at or around the Pentagon. It appears that a third plane crashed into or very nearby the Pentagon. In addition to the two planes that crashed into the World Trade Center, no reports of casualties here in Washington, but I think many casualties, certainly,
perhaps five more dead in the World Trade Center and many, many injured.
There's a building in the way.
They were going to land in Guardia and ended up in one of the wireless second planes.
I guess depending on something, they were in.
So the other plane was hijacked,
I didn't hear that.
Yeah,
I mean...
See that fire?
Oh shit.
It's like...
Fire that just fell?
Yeah,
like molten metal.
Yeah.
It was laying out at the bottom for me.
Yeah,
I have it.
I see something drop it and it fell.
You can see it just like...
Yeah,
that's what they said.
Whoa!
Oh my God!
Oh
Jesus! Oh my
God! Whoa!
Whoa!
Oh my God!
Oh,
God!
Jesus!
But it is a major complex there in Virginia.
And the two things that we have been reporting so far.
Is a radio reporter from the Associated Press saying he saw what he quoted as a large airliner diving directly for this building.
And also a report from The Associated Press,
which would be fortunate, if were the case,
that it may have hit.
The helicopter landing pad outside the building instead of going inside. This building, which is made up, as you know at one time, perhaps still is the world's largest office building by space.
Thank you.
That's the third.
Down it went.
The building just fell.
Do you know how many people are dead?
Banana Fieldcom Marine 6 to Banana Standby,
Banana Fieldcom Banana Fieldcom
Marine 6 to Manhattan,
urgent.
Marine 6.
Tower 2 has had a major explosion and what appears to be a complete collapse surrounding the entire area.
Marine 6,
10-4,
We were notified,
K.
Banana Field com K. Banana Field com
Oh,
Whoa!
Somebody walk the
floor.
Hello!
This way!
Come in!
Hello!
Jerry,
turn around.
Yes,
I am here,
Michael.
We just witnessed some kind of secondary follow-up explosion on the World Trade Center. Number two,
the one that is on the South, that is difficult to make out through the debris and smoke,
but it does appear that a portion,
the top portion of the building,
has collapsed down to the streets below.
Unbelievable what we have seen here,
the debris and smoke just covering the entire portion of Lower Manhattan.
The first video of the protest is here.
Go ahead.
Stay here.
Look out behind you,
look out behind you. .
Please,
look,
right.
Go on.
Over the right. .
Help. .
Help me,
Jesus. .
Help.
Help!
Come on!
Inside.
It's gone.
Oh my God,
it's gone.
Oh!
Going inside the rings itself.
We're going back now to New York City,
and it appears that something else has occurred.
We're not quite sure what,
but apparently the level of the smoke,
this is a different,
Is it a slightly different area from the World Trade Center?
Okay,
it is now the base of the World Trade Center.
There seems to be now a second area there of smoke,
so perhaps indicating that some sort of explosion or fire there.
Now,
of course,
what may have happened,
with the...
All these systems compromised in the building.
You may be getting an explosion from that.
We do not know what has happened,
but obviously something has happened there, near the base of the building,
setting off another round of major smoke and apparently a fire.
But we don't know whether,
again,
it's because the building,
because the earlier damage.
The tower is closed.
Two explosions,
two planes hitting the World Trade Center here in New York.
And what this second explosion was that took place above.
God,
we are so blessed.
Thank you,
God.
We're still alive,
guy.
Here is as if the World Trade Center has just fallen.
There was a cascade of sparks and fire,
and now this looks almost like a munching pile that just flows through these things.
Oh my God,
something else blew up.
This is the center of the three powers here.
You know,
I cannot see behind that smoke,
obviously,
the Z-band either.
The first tower in front has not changed.
And we see this extraordinary and frightening scene behind it.
Oh,
my God.
The second tower.
What is behind it?
I cannot tell you.
Oh!
What a,
what a...
How did it happen?
Did it go down or what happened?
Did it explode?
It exploded from the middle.
From the middle?
From where the crash was?
I guess so,
but...
Oh, no!
Oh, shit!
I don't think it's from the fire.
Big sand building blew up.
What?
No,
there it is.
Where is it?
I heard it on the radio,
it's just right now.
What?
How?
Right there.
The empire said that it takes like 30 seconds to go on the radio.
They can come with me if they want to.
This is Hunteris,
hey.
Yes.
We're at Delta 1989.
Cleveland talked to them,
they talked to the pilot,
he's not declaring emergency, but they're going ahead,
I mean, hijacked,
they're going to go ahead and land him at Cleveland for precautionary measures.
He's not a hijack?
No.
Sandy Center.
Hi,
Hunteris ID calling.
Wanted to give you a heads up on the Delta Airlines 1989 that was in Cleveland Center's AOR.
He was giving you the information that he was a hijacked aircraft.
He is not a hijacked aircraft.
He's taken precautionary measures,
and he's landing at Cleveland Center.
However,
we do have four fighters launched on that aircraft,
just to be sure.
We've got debris on the roof.
Oh my god,
the World Trade Center fell down.
Oh my god.
The side of the Pentagon,
the West front,
which faces sort of toward Arlington National Cemetery.
It's a corridor where a lot of army offices are located.
Wow.
And some people were...
Jamie,
I need you to stop for a second.
There has just been a huge...
Huge explosion.
We can see a billowing smoke rising. And I can't,
I'll tell you that I can't see that second tower,
but there was a cascade of sparks and fire. And now this,
it looks
almost like a mushroom cloud explosion,
this huge billowing smoke in the second tower.
This was the second of the two towers hit.
And,
you know,
I cannot see behind that smoke,
obviously,
as you can't either.
The first tower in front of me.
Front has not changed and the trade tower again. Because John, we now have a what do we have? We don't? It looks like a new plume, a new large plume of smoke.
Now it may be that something fell off the building.
It may be that something has fallen.
We don't know, to be perfectly honest.
But that is what you're looking at is the current.
That's the scene at this moment at the World Trade Center.
Stand.
There was another bomb, guys.
That was definitely another bomb.
Yeah,
but that's the- I told you,
my God,
Jesus.
My God.
That was definitely another bomb.
I told you,
my God,
it's gone.
It's gone.
They took it down,
man.
20 or 30 seconds? We're hoping that the people who are outside. That is a tremendous building, one of the largest in the world, and it's just apparently coming down.
We first noticed the first plane crash into the first tower.
And I can't say that I can't see that second tower.
But there was a cascade of sparks and fire.
And now it looks almost like a mushroom pile of explosions.
Huge,
huge smoke.
And the second tower,
this was the second the two towers hit.
And I,
you know,
I cannot see behind that spark.
I can't see it either.
The first tower.
We're not going any place.
Are you able to hear me?
Jim,
we know this is terribly difficult for everybody.
We're asking you to please stay with us.
Hold your shot.
Stay with us on audio.
We should tell people our crews have been running from that scene.
It's had everybody and the entire...
Oh my God.
.under. An evacuation for some time.
And just moments ago,
you saw it here live from Chopper 2.
A horrific scene as one of the towers there appears to have collapsed.
From what had happened earlier,
a quick chronology, as you can tell.
From American Airlines,
here is the first of those towers coming down.
Peter, from ABC's Good Morning America, is down in the general vicinity.
Dan,
can you tell us what has just happened?
Yes,
Peter.
It's Don Dealer down here.
I'm four blocks north of the World Trade Center.
The second building that was hit by the plane has just completely collapsed.
The entire building has just collapsed,
as if a demolition team set off when you see the old demolitions of these old buildings.
It pulled it down on itself,
and it is not there anymore.
That should be it.
Thanks very much.
It has fully collapsed.
The whole side has collapsed?
The whole building has collapsed.
The whole building has collapsed?
The building has collapsed.
That's the Southern Tower you're talking about.
Exactly.
The second building that we witnessed the airplane enter had been,
the top half had been fully involved in flame.
It just collapsed.
There is panic on the streets,
thousands of people running up Church Street,
which is what I'm looking out on,
trying to get away.
But the entire,
at least as far as I can see,
half of the building,
at least half of it,
I can't see below that,
half of it just started with a gigantic rumble,
folded in on itself,
and collapsed in a huge plume of smoke and dust.
We're talking about massive casualties here at the moment,
and we have...
That is extraordinary.
There is panic on the streets.
Please move it!
No!
I can't!
Move it!
I haven't said anything!
Please move it!
Move it!
Let's go,
Jerry!
Let's go!
Move back,
move back,
move back!
Let's go.
Go back,
go back,
go
No,
just come out!
Just come out!
I'm sick of this!
Keep going!
Fuck that,
I ain't looking back!
Look out,
look out,
look out!
Keep going,
keep going!
United, 93, was waving his wings as he went past the VFR aircraft.
They don't quite know what that means.
Rocking his wings.
People screaming and running from the site.
The gigantic plume of smoke has reached me,
and I'm probably a quarter of a mile north of there.
Peter.
Now, this is a...
This is what it looked like moments ago.
My God.
Joining us now is Greg Barrow in New York.
Greg,
what's the latest information from the World Trade Center?
Well,
the latest we have is that the whole area has been sealed off.
The police and security personnel are down there trying to clear members of the public away.
This was a very,
very busy time of the morning in New York,
just as everybody was going into their offices,
so it couldn't really have come at a worse time.
And I think...
The search is already beginning for those who may be to blame for this incident. That has really,
truly shocked people, not just here in New York, but also around the country.
And and you won't feel cupcake.
This is 249.
This is a major collapse in the tower.
The command center out here,
everybody has to see. It was a major collapse.
I'm in my wig right now.
We notified them that there is a major collapse in the area.
Can anybody in the area head to 1?
I don't know if you feel copiers available.
Can anybody hear me?
I'm a civilian.
I'm tripping on the foliage roots underneath.
The car is sick.
It's happening.
Stand by.
There's people close to you.
I can't breathe much longer.
Save me.
I'm in a case for your truck.
Hey,
person transmitting to Mayday.
Where are you,
Kate?
I just told you.
If you look at the World Trade Center,
there's a north pedestrian bridge.
I think it collapsed when that Porsche building just collapsed.
I was on the street.
I don't have much air.
Please help me.
I'm gonna go look for.
I'm in a field com urgent case.
Oh my God!
You better be so good!
Oh my God.
Holy shit!
Ice Gravers were hands on.
Oh my God.
I do.
I know a lot of people that work there.
Me also is jim Plant.
Jim,
you're also a witness of what happened.
Tell me exactly what you saw from your vantage point across the street.
I was just across Liberty and west here,
and I saw the second plane hit the tower.
It was a little bit of a FIREBALL.
It was
a little bit of a FIREBALL.
It looked like a 737.
It hit a glancing BLOW.
It didn't hit a DIRECT.
The FLOORS.
The floors are very close to.
As you can tell,
there's absolute pandemonium in this area because of what had just happened.
Exactly what,
I can't confirm,
but on the far side of the building,
there seemed to be another explosion.
And also on the right-hand side,
there was also another explosion.
We're not sure if that was extra reverberation from what happened at the World Trade Center, or if that was an added explosion.
At this point,
there's a lot of smoke,
massive plumes of smoke falling from the building across the street.
People that were running down the street or walking are now running away.
We don't have any information as far as what the most recent...
Reverberations WERE,
but from two blocks AWAY,
you can feel what HAPPENED.
We'll get more information and pass it along to YOU.
Come ON,
GO,
keep GOING,
let's GO,
get out of HERE.
Let's go,
you're in the way,
let's go!
There is smoke everywhere.
The building just came down.
This is clearly a four day attack.
Someone just told me that the Apache's coming down, too.
Loosen up those things to the left.
That's before I realized it was a plank.
I didn't see it.
Yeah,
so the thing is stretching and snapping.
It's quite quick.
It's pretty good.
Goal!
Oh!
We
have two explosions,
two planes hitting the World Trade Center here in New York.
And what this second explosion was that took place about...
A part of the south,
that would be the South tower,
has apparently collapsed.
We don't know if that was from the impact of this first plane that hit it or whether something else has happened there.
We'll work on that.
Sebastian,
let me get the walkie.
Your walkie?
Yeah.
Another one went in there?
Nah,
that's a bomb.
That was what?
Definitely a bomb.
Oh,
fuck this shit.
Ah,
guys.
One side of the twin tower went down.
Have it on tape.
And you're at the bottom of your screen, there, above the breaking news banner.
You can see people continuing to billow out of that area,
people leaving the area of the apparent attack.
NBC's Rick Sanchez is in Lower Manhattan covering the trade center attacks.
Rick,
what do you have?
Well,
the very latest,
Lester,
is a scene that's being described by some of the police officers who are scurrying about. Trying to get some sense of control in this area.
They are saying that people have now started to jump out of the buildings.
Yeah,
it's collapsed.
You know,
the world's,
uh,
the world today just collapsed,
copy?
Everybody just fall back down.
Hello?
Do you see anybody?
Fetch tape as possible.
Copy.
This is an unbelievable disaster.
I couldn't even get my toes up.
It appears that the South Tower has fallen,
creating a huge plume of dust,
extending all the way out to where we were not
15 minutes ago in North Cove.
I hope everybody there is okay.
We found Shane.
He's waiting for us at Chelsea.
From what I've heard on the news,
this was a terrorist act.
Somebody in Palestine,
Liberation Front,
something or other.
There's also been an explosion in the Pentagon,
near the Pentagon.
As yet unconfirmed.
All air traffic in the country has been shut down.
All paths in and out of this city have been shut down on a yacht.
Thank God.
My poor mom,
she must be just freaking out.
Mike, stop,
stop!
Please,
no more!
The
other side of the building is definitely going there.
Sir,
I'm going to lock the setback up.
Something came in.
It's a collapse.
I need some water.
Here,
here,
Paul.
Give me some water.
This guy right here.
Do you have any water?
We have no idea what caused this.
If you wish to bring. Anybody who's ever watched a building being demolished on purpose knows that. If you're going to do this,
you have to get at the under-infrastructure of a building and bring it down.
We don't know specifically,
as you've said,
what has taken place at the Pentagon,
but this is very serious,
striking at the heart of the national government,
and, as John King was explaining...
Frank,
it's Aaron.
I need to interrupt you for a second.
Again,
there has been a second explosion here in Manhattan, at the Trade Center.
We are getting reports that a part of the tower,
the second tower,
the one a bit further to the south of us,
has collapsed.
We are checking on that.
We are also told that the Sears Tower in Chicago has been evacuated.
And what I can't tell you on that is whether there was something specific that happened there,
whether there was an attack on that building yet.
We're checking that out.
This dust is just starting to settle after the Second World
Trade Center collapsed.
We saw it collapse and come towards us.
Marty,
I'm Megan.
I'm rolling,
I'm rolling.
We don't know what's happened inside.
What we know we have to do is just keep running the other way.
The firemen are going this way.
So are the police officers.
We don't know what's happening.
When we were talking to eyewitnesses earlier,
they said that the situation seemed to be out of control,
that the explosions were just running,
and it looks as if the tower,
one of the towers,
has fallen down.
Is that your understanding?
The whole building's gone.
It's gone and people are in there.
Oh,
my God.
Not anymore.
Hopefully they were out.
No,
no way.
No way they got out.
How could they have evacuated that entire building with fire going on and everything?
No way.
It's like, we keep looking at this,
and we think to ourselves,
how much worse can it get?
And every 10 minutes,
it gets worse.
It gets worse,
yeah.
Cabby.
Howard,
we were standing here,
and we were just discussing the things that were going on,
and the second building just crumbled right in front of us.
It did.
I know.
Do you think it was a red crack?
No,
no.
I think it was a building that was collapsed.
Yeah.
Oh my God!
Are we okay?
I think we're okay.
Oh my God!
Holy cow!
That was sick.
Close your eyes,
I got you!
Oh my God!
There are no confirmed fatalities.
Now in
Washington, the Pentagon has had a fire and explosions.
Much speculation of what would have caused the fires and explosions at the Pentagon in Washington.
But very few facts.
David Martin,
our Pentagon correspondent,
says that he has seen,
I believe, he said, five injured people at the Pentagon.
One eyewitness, and only one so far, is quoted as saying
he thinks,
I put that in quotation marks,
he thinks. A plane crashed into the Pentagon.
Try and shoot this.
Try and shoot this as we run,
Jared.
Try and shoot this.
It fell.
It just fell.
The second building just fell.
And it hit everything around it.
Oh my god.
Oh my god,
yeah,
you're right.
Martina,
where's your husband?
Rescue people.
It's a mess.
Get back.
She's not gonna hold that much time.
Don't blame me,
man.
Alright.
About 9.30 this morning.
Also confirmed from The Associated Press.
Look at that,
the whole middle of the building came down.
Unbelievable.
It's like an implosion,
right?
Yeah.
Let's go to Marcia Kramer now in the news.
There was first one plane that hit one of the twin Towers,
a second plane,
each about one.
Hour ago and now a third explosion. Ashley Banfield is in Manhattan, Ashley, did you see or hear anything just months ago?
Oh my god,
Chris.
This is incredible,
I'm looking right at it.
What are you seeing,
Ashley?
Well,
I saw the explosion for one.
Could you feel it?
Everybody,
I can smell it.
Everyone around screamed at the time that it happened.
It's just unbelievable.
I can't see that, it's another building.
It looks almost in the same position as the second bomb or the second explosion.
But it's unbelievable.
What the people on the scene don't seem to realize is that one of the twin towers has collapsed.
Back here,
okay.
We're going to get out of the area as quick as we can.
Again,
there has been a second explosion here in Manhattan, at the Trade Center.
We are getting reports that a part of the tower,
the second tower,
the one a bit further to the south of us,
has collapsed.
We are checking on that.
We are also told that the Sears Tower in Chicago has been evacuated.
How
many people on the ground or other buildings were affected by that?
Yeah,
the whole area.
It's a 110-story building.
This is our world,
that siren is our world.
This is a disgusting display. That is humanity right here.
Oh yeah.
What are you going to say here?
There's nothing to be said.
Um,
I don't know what we're good at doing,
what good it is to have us on the air right now.
I don't know,
uh...
They're not letting anybody into the city,
are they?
No.
Tom,
I don't think it does any good to have us on the air now,
does it?
The only thing I'd say about having you on the air,
it's a place for people to come.
Right.
Especially people in other cities.
It becomes a big encounter session.
If you want to continue that...
All right,
I'll stay on the air for a while.
We're looking at the very disturbing pictures from New York of the World Trade Center.
Only one tower is standing.
The other has collapsed.
Hi Pat,
we chose to stay in our hotel room because from our vantage point, we're in a corner suite of this hotel.
So we have actually two windows looking out on the corner of our building at the World Trade Center.
We could see the building number two was going to go and my husband and I were having a debate,
stay,
go.
And my husband said, If it collapses, we'll be killed below.
So we chose to stay in our room, which is where we still are on the
35th floor.
Building literally when it collapsed.
It came from the scene now.
There's obviously massive casualties.
Usually during these things,
there's a little bit of a high pitch,
but basic calm over the police radios among the emergency workers.
I can hear them screaming. Signal 1013,
which is the police code for help,
calling for help at the triage center,
where other people who were already injured have been injured. more.
Confirming that the building has collapsed,
dozens of officers,
more civilians are injured.
And we don't know,
although I'd have to suggest,
given the size of that building,
what progress the evacuation was in of the tower that collapsed.
I can barely breathe.
Please save somebody.
Okay,
the person calling for help,
listen to me.
You need to calm down and relax.
Stand by.
We do have somebody on the way.
You're amazing.
Maintain air.
Get off the air.
We do have somebody on the way over to you.
You remain calm.
10-4.
10-4,
I can't hear you.
we do have people on the way over there.
Manhattan to field,
com.
Urgent,
10-4,
3 to me.
Stand by.
Manhattan to field,
com.
Urgent.
3-3,
roger.
Manhattan to field,
com.
Go.
I'm ahead of Division 11.
Which way to go?
Stay put,
stay put.
You're in front of St.
Paul's Church on Fulton and Broadway.
Which way to go?
Stay right where you are.
Stay where you are,
man.
Chopper 5 on 3.
Stay where you are.
Oh my God.
The truck.
The station.
It's you and her.
Everyone is, like, covered in blood.
Thousands of people down.
Stay low!
In the last few minutes,
there have been two reports,
but not yet officially confirmed,
that a portion of at least one of the towers has collapsed.
But I caution that that's an unconfirmed report,
although it comes from two sources.
Stuff is going on in Washington.
Did you know that, too?
Pentagon,
yeah,
they got hit.
They're not as bad, though,
right?
The president's probably being skirted away somewhere,
huh?
They're evacuating the capital.
From what I heard,
the Pentagon was not hit itself,
but there was an explosion nearby.
You are looking at Lower Manhattan.
The entire
Lower Manhattan is covered with smoke and debris.
You're looking at an area of square miles that is completely obscured.
The exchange will not open today.
No,
they cannot do it now.
They cannot do anything now.
Everything okay?
Thank you.
You're looking at the scene there.
On the right-hand side,
there are some new developments in New York City.
We do believe that there was another blast after the two that rocked the
twin Towers,
the World Trade Center towers.
We are trying to determine now if this was a consequence of one of those two earlier attacks,
or perhaps this was a separate explosion.
Or it was a separate explosion.
Right.
We do believe...
That's what we're trying to sort out.
But it's beginning to appear that there was a separate explosion,
but again,
that cannot be sorted out at this moment.
You,
one of the two towers is gone.
The people on the scene are so engulfed in the smoke, it's understandable, and they're not looking at the larger scene that we are. But one of the World Trade Center towers, unless...
No, that's confirmed on the wires right now.
The South building has completely collapsed.
You see Raider?
Go ahead, Raider.
Wait a minute,
hold on.
I mean,
everyone there is gone.
Everybody in that building.
Everybody in that building?
Everybody in that building must be gone.
I mean,
there's probably a few in the bottom that made it,
but I mean,
you think about that building...
The elevator's probably jammed.
Oh,
I'm sure.
Well,
it went right through the middle of the building.
And you think about the top fell off,
so everybody up above where the plane hit must have got it.
Everybody on the bottom that was standing around trying to help probably got it.
Oh,
boy.
Look at the dust.
I mean,
it's just...
It's all up...
It's taken...
New York,
our Manhattan is completely done.
This is going to be a long time before this clears.
Yes,
Pierre Thomas.
One thing I might add is that in recent years,
the U.S.
Government has been preparing for massive attacks,
but it's been primarily focused on biological,
often bombing attacks.
One of the things I have not heard discussed at all...
In government circles is the notion that someone would hijack a plane and perhaps fly it into a building.
So one of the questions that I'm sure that will come out of this,
if this indeed is a terrorist attack,
is what kind of defenses did the U.S.
Have in place to deal with an event like this?
Did the power go out?
Did we lose power?
Yeah,
we lost power.
How are you?
What else?
I'm good.
Oh.
Come on,
come on,
come on.
I'm going to get you.
Okay,
then let me go quickly to someone named Don Wright,
who saw the plane crash into the Pentagon.
Don,
are you there in Washington?
Yes,
I am.
Can you tell us what happened?
Yes,
it was about 9.35,
and I was looking out our 12th floor windows at 1600 Wilson Boulevard in Roslyn,
Virginia,
and I watched this,
it looked like a computer plane,
two-engine,
come down from the south,
real low,
proceed right on and crashed right into the
Pentagon.
Went directly into the Pentagon?
That is correct.
Looked like a deliberate act?
A deliberate act,
sir.
And can you tell me what direction it came from,
Don?
It came from the south.
Came from the south,
up along the river,
across the land?
It came from the south.
Okay,
and did you happen to look at your watch?
We thought it was just a little bit before 10 o'clock.
Well,
I was watching ABC News,
watching the
Twin Tower,
and about...
I watched it come in very low over the trees and it just dipped down,
came down right over 395, right into the Pentagon.
And are you fairly sure that it was what we sometimes describe and recognize as a small commuter plane?
Yes,
it was.
Good,
Don.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate your help,
Don.
Seen an attack on the Pentagon or close to the Pentagon, the u.s.
Defense headquarters, the White House and the Capitol have been evacuated.
I was able to fortunately speak to my wife, who was dropping the kids not too far of the World Trade Center for school.
They are okay. But we can imagine folks watching these pictures that we've been seeing, wondering about their loved ones and having great difficulty getting phone calls in and out.
All I can tell you right now, as far as that is concerned, Lester, I talked to one police officer, police officer.
And they say what they're going to try and do is just evacuate the area,
get people out of this area as soon as they possibly can.
Their next step is to somehow try and cordon off or close the roads,
But they really haven't had a chance to do that because they're dealing with the buildings themselves at this point.
I am told that. Most of the schools and most of the buildings in this area,
even within like a
10-block radius,
have also been closed,
and people are being told essentially, to try and get out of the area as carefully as they possibly can.
I heard noises out there, now with sound.
Sounded like a megaphone.
I'm not confirming that that's what I hear,
but it sounds like police might be using some type of audio device to try and get people down here.
Rick,
I'm going to interrupt you for a second.
The whole fucking tower collapsed.
The whole tower collapsed.
No,
I do not.
I don't know how.
They were down by Park Lane.
I thought it was fucking inbound.
You won't be able to call it on your phone.
You can try.
Is it working?
Yeah.
Zolar,
go ahead and finish your thought.
Yeah,
oh my God.
There's no thought.
I would not tell you what.
At first second,
I hear on the news that it has anything to do with a cowl head or a dot head.
Bastard,
I'm gonna go out there and start going to those a-rap stores and start kicking, Nah,
you don't wanna do that,
you don't wanna do that, don't say that,
Zola. I implore all Americans to get your arms together,
baby, get out there on the streets and go to your local freakin'
deli with a man. Alright,
I got him
Where?
Let's go,
let's go,
come on,
back up,
back up.
George,
have them mobilize the army.
We need the army in Manhattan.
All units,
stand by.
Everybody try to calm down.
Manhattan to field,
com. K.
My menandah Division,
Menandah,
uh...
Menandah...
Menandah Car 9,
urgent.
My Menandah,
any units operating at the 5th and 1st on West Street and Liberty Street at tower number 2,
any units,
Jane?
Any unit operating in number two World Trade Center at the collapse,
contact Manhattan by radio,
fourth width.
3-3 Bravo,
Manhattan,
urgent.
Truck 15,
Manhattan.
All right,
Car 3-3. Bravo,
We understand there's a major collapse.
Can you give us some kind of report,
Jake?
All right,
thank you very much,
Walter.
Again,
one or two more explosions, again around the World Trade Center.
We don't know if it was in the same building or adjacent buildings.
Can we re-rack that video that we were looking at as Walter was interviewing those people?
Because perhaps that will give us some indication of what this was.
Obviously,
there are buildings nose-to-nose down there.
We have no idea if this was a third explosion or if it might have been.
Something from the debris raining down from one of the World Trade Center towers.
It appears to be to the south of those buildings,
but take a look at those pictures and that is quite an incredible sight.
No,
it's really war.
It's like a nuclear bomb hit the city.
Yeah,
it really is.
You know,
it's so beyond Pearl Harbor.
It's just so beyond.
It is beyond Pearl Harbor.
The entire city is covered with...
At least Pearl Harbor was...
And the Pentagon's on fire.
.a. Nuclear installation.
What went on at the Pentagon?
The plane crashed into the Pentagon?
Yes.
Oh.
And now they're saying there's one other plane on the radio they think is still up there.
Oh,
no.
Really?
And it's not down yet.
There must have been a third target in New York.
Come on,
come on.
Get it down.
Bring it back in.
Nice.
I'm gonna bring you to the command post.
Right upon the command post.
Marks 3 Where are you?
I'm not with a truck,
I'm by myself.
I have Keith Lyon and Jack Kelly here.
I'm going to go ahead and
get out.
Look, how much dust is in that Lower Manhattan.
It's covering the lower east Side.
I can't imagine what the other buildings nearby have been.
They've been destroyed.
Yesterday.
This is the kind of thing that you read theoretical things about.
Okay,
go.
At 855,
I came out of the battery tunnel.
I had to recross at the night.
You all, right?
Trying to get in.
What's the way?
Management over there.
Not anymore.
Management there.
I took,
I took the day off so I could get my bathroom ceiling fixed.
Would you have been in the building?
I would have been right where they landed.
I would have been on 86,
one world Trade.
Took your day off today.
Happened the first time, too.
When was the first time?
93.
What happened?
I walked out of the basement,
the walls came in.
All right,
sit down.
Sit down.
I got a hip.
Slow breath.
Take a couple slow breaths.
Clear out here.
Joe!
You need a worse than that.
What happened?
The building collapsed.
Part of the building collapsed.
At least that's what I think happened.
Everybody's running like...
They're going up.
4-4,
shelter!
Again,
this all started this morning at about 10 minutes to 9 o'clock.
We understand that a commercial airliner,
maybe a small commercial airliner,
was apparently hijacked, leaving the airport in Boston,
Logan Airport in Boston.
Out!
Everybody on the ground!
Just in the building!
Quit,
This is taped just in,
turned around from ground level of the Pentagon,
where apparently another plane has been driven into part of the Pentagon.
We have no casualty figures right now,
but you can see the steady stream of people leaving the Pentagon,
evacuating,
as you may well know,
the Pentagon is a series of rings,
inside rings,
a huge building and an enormous number of people to evacuate.
This attack occurring after 9 o'clock East Coast time,
so folks were clearly...
uh...
At their desk at work at the Pentagon when this occurred, uh...
Back to the situation in New York right now, we have a telephone with Will Feeney and you,
Well,
the latest I have for you is. The Associated Press news agency is saying that the plane that crashed here in Washington crashed into a helicopter launch pad near the Pentagon.
So it seems,
if that report is correct,
that the Pentagon itself has not been hit,
but there is a fire in the vicinity.
The White House and other government buildings, and,
of course,
the Pentagon, have been evacuated,
but certainly no reports of casualties here in Washington.
And I was about a block and a half,
two blocks away.
It started coming down.
I turned my camera on,
got the initial fall,
got the debris.
Turned my camera around like this and ran up to where we are now,
which must be 10,
12 blocks away from the scene.
I'm exhausted.
All right,
man.
Thanks.
All right.
It could have been done to that part of Manhattan,
And it's got to be beyond the control,
certainly,
of the emergency services and everyone else in the city of New York's ability to,
well.
I don't know anyone who could handle this,
David.
We must be looking at Washington right now.
Now we are looking at the Pentagon.
Yeah,
that's the Pentagon.
I recognize the facade of the building.
That was the subject of only one plane so far.
But again,
in New York,
the third attack came about 45 minutes after the first.
So there is no way to know at this point.
Fuck 15 to Milan!
All right,
ladder one flight,
go!
Fuck 15 to Milan!
This is a EMS,
Walker.
There's been a major collapse.
We need additional units forthwith.
We have multiple units on the way in.
Rada 1-5,
Can you ascertain if field comm is part of the collapse case?
Rada 1-5 to Manhattan,
be advised I'm not a 15
MLS, I'm an EMS MLS.
I don't want to talk to anybody.
Of that number, two World Trade Center.
This is the second tape.
Third explosion just occurred.
Can't even see the second tower of the World Trade Center anymore.
American Airlines has just confirmed that it was flight 11 from Logan Airport to LAX,
which was involved in one of the three
World Trade Center attacks.
I believe this is a 767, which has a maximum capacity of 300 passengers and crew,
I believe.
Just to give you,
can we go to a shot of the Pentagon quickly?
Because just to give you an idea of the sheer terror of what is involved here,
one
Associated Press radio reporter is quoted as saying,
I saw the tail of a large airliner,
it plowed right into the Pentagon.
There is billowing black smoke.
As of,
of course, we continue to look at the devastation of the world trade.
All right.
You didn't even try to get on the baseball truck.
It's Aladdin's house.
It's back.
Take it on the other side of the barrier!
On the other side of the barrier,
let's go!
Come on,
I'm fucking people's lives!
On the other side of the barrier!
The other side!
Hop up there!
On the other side,
up there!
Everybody up there!
And we're talking about a 767, which, for example, can hold a maximum of 300 people. And we are now talking about four separate attacks.
Four separate attacks.
One at the Pentagon,
three now at the World Trade Center,
the last of which has leveled the South Tower,
Mark?
The South Tower...
We can show you now what happened just a few moments ago at the Trade Center.
Watch the building to the left,
to the back of those two buildings.
This is just a few minutes ago.
We don't know if something happened,
another explosion,
or if the building was so weakened, it just collapsed.
Yeah,
we do have Audrey Barnes back now on the phone.
She has a view of the Pentagon.
So,
Audrey, try.
Yeah,
there she is now.
So tell us where you are and what you can see.
Okay,
if you look over my shoulder,
you can see the Pentagon is still on fire right now.
I'm right beside it.
You can see hundreds of Pentagon employees have been evacuated from that building,
and it is still burning right now.
Most of the fire,
you can see the flames shooting up behind that little guard shack there.
There are hundreds of people on the lawn,
and every five seconds,
another emergency.
Vehicle goes by to try to get this fire under control.
We have seen employees trying to console each other.
People are walking around in absolute shock and disbelief.
Now,
we were at the State Department.
Right when this happened,
we saw State Department police running out of the building, telling everybody,
get away.
And I look up and see this giant plume of smoke coming from the Pentagon.
So we got over here,
and this is what we found,
the Pentagon on fire there.
Still, quite a scene of devastation out here.
people.
People really don't even know which way to go.
They've gone away from the building.
Now people are running back towards the building.
Just a scene of utter chaos out here.
Don't fucking bastards.
All my coworkers are dead.
Yeah?
They have to be.
I just talked to a guy.
He was down in the basement.
So what do you think it was?
They flew planes into the building.
Planes?
More than one?
Yeah.
How many?
Well,
I understand two,
but I don't have all the details.
I only heard it on the news.
So it was a terrorist attack?
Absolutely.
Subways are closed.
Where's Casey going?
He has no family to go to.
Casey,
you have no family.
Get over here.
Get back here,
you.
He runs out with Jared.
And Howard,
Obviously, if you want to go,
we'll film.
I got nowhere to go.
Casey's going to OTB.
What about guys in a situation like me?
The horses aren't running.
We have to cab it out and take a train and...
Well,
good luck.
You're right.
Yeah,
I don't think you...
Vinnie,
I think you're here for good.
We better get a hotel room together then.
That means I can do the show again tomorrow,
Howard.
Oh, no,
it doesn't.
He's available!
Airplane man.
You back up from your fucking camera,
boy!
Make a hole for it!
Remains of a...
Airplane.
Crash over on
Lambertsville Road and probably had a terrorist bomb on board that blew up.
I don't know anything more than that.
That's what I heard on the scanner.
I just saw the smoke come up and the explosion shook the house clear over here.
And we are,
what,
15 miles from Lambertsville.
And it shook the heck out of the house.
Scenes on the street,
people on their cell phones trying to find out what's going on,
people calling loved ones trying to find out if they're okay.
As you walk into this building,
a lot of people out on the street not being permitted to go up and down through most of the elevators for security reasons.
Obviously,
as we think about the landmarks in Manhattan,
people are taking very serious security precautions just for that reason.
A lot of emotions I should share with you. Up in the newsroom,
too,
as we hear these just gut-wrenching eyewitness accounts of what these people must be going through,
especially in the Twin Towers right now.
Just amazing.
We have just been told that this,
what we thought was another explosion,
was indeed,
according to The Associated Press,
another building that has either been attacked or exploded.
So it appears to be separate from the two that we have already...
The
BUSINESSES.
Go ahead,
take it.
Thank you.
We've got some eyewitnesses as you...
Mike,
why don't you stay on,
show the pictures over here,
and I'll talk to the eyewitnesses.
You can look at what's going on,
the firefighting efforts.
We had a couple people who were in the Pentagon at the time.
Tell me what happened.
We were sitting at our desks having a meeting,
and there was a large shutter,
where there was a shutter of the building,
and the sound of a large thud.
Right,
you could hear the impact,
and there was a large concussion,
like an explosion would do,
the air would be a concussion.
We didn't know there was an explosion.
We just,
it was clear,
we looked at each other and knew that something catastrophic had happened,
but we had no idea what it was.
People began evacuating immediately and went outside.
It wasn't until we were outside we realized what had happened.
How far away from you in the building were you when it happened?
Well,
if you divide the building into fifths,
five pie slices,
which is the way the Pentagon renovation is scheduled,
This is in the first wedge,
the new wedge that just was finished,
and we were in the next one over.
Did you see any injured other than the ones who were out here that we saw?
I didn't see any injuries.
Did you see what size of plane it was when you got outside?
No,
just by walking up here now, along the road,
there are pieces of aircraft spread all the way up the road.
At least a third of a mile from the impact site.
What goes on?
Can you tell us what would be in those offices,
generally speaking?
I know you can't go into great detail.
Well,
we're looking at the e-ring of the Pentagon,
and that's where the more senior officials are.
That area,
I believe,
is where the
Army Deputy Chief of Staff for Operations and the Army Deputy Chief of Staff for Personnel's offices are.
We're looking here also,
I believe,
I don't have a monitor,
but I believe you're looking at. One of the injured being taken away by Arlington Fire and Rescue.
They've been on the scene since a few minutes after this happened.
And I mentioned before,
But the firefighters and police officers on the scene here have all been warned,
keep a close look at the skies,
watching for a possible second attack as what happened in New York.
Mike and Andrea.
George Shapiro of Goldman Sachs,
which is at one New York Plaza,
in the heart of this situation,
is on the line.
Howard,
Howard, Yes, Can you tell us what? One second, I can't hear you, one second. Okay, hello, they're closing your building, obviously. What can you see? What do you know? Okay, I'm at one New York,
one second,
I'm sorry.
Just go back.
All right,
you got to get out of there,
Howard.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to give you one minute here.
Yeah,
go ahead.
I'm on one New York Plaza, on the 46th floor,
so we're about,
you know,
five to seven blocks from the
World Trade Center. With obviously, a bird's eye view.
View of the building. We heard a large explosion for the first attack and we all ran to the window and we thought a boiler had exploded. We weren't certain what was happened. And then,
a few minutes later,
I saw a large commercial airline plow into the second building,
very clearly veering in towards the building.
And then now, five minutes ago or so,
or three minutes ago,
the building imploded.
All there is is a large plume of smoke all over Lower Manhattan, up to the 46th floor.
I literally see papers from people's offices, from...
The World Trade Center, floating in the sky, past me,
past the window.
Howard,
thank you very much,
and I think you better get out of the building.
I'm on my way.
Bye.
Thank you very much.
All right,
Manhattan,
any unit operating in number two World Trade Center urgent.
EMS,
Lionel 1-5.
Lionel
1-5, Manhattan.
I want you to go to the nearest chief,
Fire Department chief,
and have him come to the radio forthwith.
If you find anybody with a white hat,
get him to...
To the radio.
I need a report to find out what else I can send to him.
All units stand by,
Mr.
Sergeant.
Is there a staff chief or a battalion chief trying to call Manhattan?
Ladder 15 to Manhattan.
We're sending out the command post.
Speed it up.
The secret shelter in the building,
they're coming out now.
All units stand by.
Ladder 15 and ladder 15 only.
Go ahead with your message.
Ladder 15,
You have a message?
What other unit calling Manhattan?
Battalion 1,
Go ahead.
Agent
231, American World Trade Center,
Do you want me to relay a message?
Yes,
I want you to find the chief officer and have him come to this radio so I can find out what additional help I can send him.
You have three fifth alarm assignments and a second alarm assignment, either at the scene or responding.
Let me know who's in command there at this moment.
Station,
this is...
We thank the
honorable Warren and
we have one of our producers on the phone and I didn't get the name. So why don't we just go ahead.
Are you there?
Yeah,
this is Rose Arcee calling from New York.
Rose,
tell me what you know.
Just a few minutes ago, we saw there's a portion of the building...
Where the first plane struck, that seemed to be buckling inside itself,
almost as if the top of the building was going to fall.
Shortly after that,
two people,
it's hard to tell whether they were being pushed or they physically approached themselves,
the sort of river side of the building,
it would be the west side of the building,
and appeared to jump from the top floors,
just under where you're seeing the smoke and fire.
That is extraordinary.
The South Tower,
the World Trade Center,
has collapsed.
Again,
tell me,
how long ago was it that you saw this?
This must have been about five minutes ago,
and prior to that,
you could see heads popping out of windows right there.
Beneath where that big gaping hole is.
So there appeared to be people alive right below where the crash point was.
They were trying to find some way out of there.
And just as the thing started to buckle,
you saw them plummeting from that top floor.
Right.
And perhaps this is...
Stating the obvious, we apologize for that, but obviously people were for what, great, what? Yeah,
close the door.
Come on out.
Yeah,
keep the door closed.
Guys,
guys,
hit her out.
Hit her out.
Audrey,
With regard to the Pentagon,
the reports that we have received is that the plane may have impacted on that helicopter pad.
There's a small control tower there, set up on that side of the Pentagon, near where you're standing.
Can you see any of any of the wreckage?
Itself, can you confirm that? Or, or does it look like it actually impacted the building itself? It is not on top of the building. And your description of a helipad seems to be what I'm hearing from people out here and the fire crews are able to fight this fire from the ground. So it seems like most.
Most of the wreckage is on the ground, right beside the Pentagon, and the smoke is just billowing from that side of the building.
So that seems to fit with what you're saying about that helipad.
We also have heard reports that witnesses have seen the tail end of some kind of aircraft going into the Pentagon.
We are still trying to confirm that information.
The trade of the Sears Tower in Chicago has been evacuated and we continue to check on the circumstances.
The Pentagon,
the State Department,
and the White House have been evacuated in Washington as well.
The president has said...
John YANG,
CNN CORRESPONDENT,
CNN, our web partner.
Will,
can you tell me what you have seen and describe what's going on now?
Wolfie,
are you with us?
Yep,
can you hear me?
Yeah,
sure can.
Go ahead,
sir.
Okay,
great.
I started watching at the second explosion.
Let's see.
I'm about a few blocks south of the towers,
and my wife called to say that there...
Had been the first explosion.
So I ran out,
I looked out my window,
and the street was full of people all looking up and,
like,
pointing and just staring.
And,
let's see,
when the second one,
when the second plane came,
it was like a long...
Rumble like, I like, you could hear, like it sounded like thunder coming, coming, and then I heard the explosion. I look up, I saw the building across the street. For me, it's lights just sort of dipped and went out and came back up again. And I and I looked up at the tower and just saw this huge plume
of flame and smoke shoot out with like debris, like ticker tape, parade quantities of debris, like just the sky, filled with little pieces of bits, and it was coming down,
uh...
And and when I happen to be on the street, the street just turned in, or like, running, screaming, uh...
And uh...
uh...
Then slowly, and people start to come back, uh...
Request right about the uh...
The uh...
The people you the please give an audio. I just heard them go down my street as well, uh...
I couldn't quite make out what they're saying, probably for telling us to leave. Will have you seen any, any signs of casualties? As we and I want to let, folks, we're looking at a live picture now.
This is along the west side,
how with the west side of the trade towers there.
In fact,
Pat Dawson is doing a live report on the network side.
Let's listen to Pat now.
They could barely breathe as they came back.
The smoke and the dust,
as you can imagine,
from such a collapse was extraordinary.
Basically,
at this point,
what we can report to you is probably what you have heard.
And that is that the two world trade Centers,
each of these two towers here in New York City,
have been struck by aircraft.
It is,
according to the President of the United States,
an apparent act of terrorism.
Right down here,
we cannot tell you much more in terms of specific information other than to say that. There are probably at this stage,
I would say,
hundreds,
perhaps in the thousands of emergency workers who in the last hour and a half have managed to work their way down here to Lower Manhattan.
And basically try to get in
to this fray,
they are,
we are standing right here, about 10 to 12 blocks north of the World Trade Center.
These firemen that you can see,
firefighters,
firefighters are walking down towards the site now. And they literally have been arriving by the dozens over the past hour or so.
As we say,
probably in excess of a thousand or more.
Emergency workers from New York City and surrounding areas converging on this site. Now to try to make some sense of it.
As you can imagine,
at this point there is a certain level of chaos. Because they're just trying to sort out who's alive,
who's not.
We did speak to,
as I said before,
some of the emergency workers.
They are police officers from the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey.
That is the organization that has jurisdiction over those two buildings specifically,
as well as bridges and tunnels.
I spoke to two of them who were actually down there when that building collapsed.
They said that they speculate that the loss of life had to be horrific,
that there were not that many people down there on the streets at that point,
that most of them who had been evacuated,
that is civilians.
But on the other hand,
they said that there were literally hundreds of emergency workers who were down at that end.
They have no idea the level of loss of life at this point.
When I asked one of them why he was going back in,
as he suited up since he could barely breathe,
he said,
It's my job.
And they may be,
there may be some of my brother officers in there,
there may be other people in there.
You can walk to the broken bridge.
Yes,
yes.
Yes.
In and out, please.
Where's the outside?
All the way.
Shortly after that,
two people,
they hardly know whether they were being pushed,
They physically pushed themselves to sort of reverse side of the building,
moving to the west side of the building,
and appeared to jump.
Sally Falcon,
Mike Delta,
Echo Roger.
Radar service is terminated,
you're one zero mile southeast of the field.
And you can contact the tower,
they know you're coming.
Okay,
Mike Del
Picco and I guess the North Carolina.
The whole system is shutting down.
That's a great argument.
Okay,
Mike del Picco.
We're lucky that United is down.
We've got a report from a guy at 24 of a cloud of black smoke off his lap.
But we don't have confirmation.
I believe I'm talking 20 VF,
sending a 9000 at a 10.8.
Falcon, 20 VFD sir,
check for an ELT,
do you see any activity out there?
We're good,
97.
Probably on your right side,
smoke or anything like that?
Negative,
we're good.
Hold on, bud,
still there?
Yeah,
we do have a smoke puff now at about,
probably 2 o'clock.
Okay,
you're at 2 o'clock and I need to know how many miles.
Blue Ridge 227,
Contact Cleveland, 121.2,
21-2.
21-2,
Blue Ridge 227,
thanks.
Over in another attack,
this time against the U.S. government itself.
We've got pictures from the Pentagon.
Close by to the Pentagon,
another plane,
possibly also hijacked,
went into or near the Pentagon.
Smoke billowing from there,
the fires appear to be out of control.
You were in what building?
I was in one World Trade Center.
And what was it like in there?
Did they start evacuating?
Yeah,
cuz soon as the building,
soon as you got hit,
I was thrown to a window.
So I was very lucky to get out.
There's a lot of people that didn't get out there.
There's a lot of people coming down the stairs,
burnt up.
It's bad.
Were there other people that were hurt,
were lying there?
There was a lot of people hurt.
They were lying on the floors,
coming down the stairs.
A lot of people had asthma attacks while they were coming down.
It was bad.
It hit on the,
in one World Trade Center,
it hit somewhere on the 67th floor.
I was on the 56th.
And was it chaos trying to come down the stairs?
Yes.
What was it like in this private place?
Everybody was on top of each other, trying to come down and then somebody finally calmed the crowd down. To get them to come down the stairs in an orderly fashion and get them out of the building.
And what just happened now?
The building just came down.
One of them,
I don't know which one came down.
I don't know if it was one or two.
What did you start doing when that happened?
Running.
Like everybody else,
but trying to calm the people down while they were running because I told them, this is how people get hurt.
When they start trying to get out of the way.
It's just crazy.
I just thank God
I made it down from 56.
What's your name?
My name is Debbie.
Debbie,
your last name?
Troy.
Troy,
and where do you work?
I work at
C&P Press.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Debbie.
The original police that went into the
World Trade Centers were apparently themselves hijacked.
At least one of them was.
The latest news we've got is that. It was an American Airlines plane,
possibly with a number of passengers on it,
which went straight into the top of the World Trade Center.
You alright,
Sam?
Okay,
what's your name?
Yvonne Berger.
Oh,
keep your drift this way.
Yvonne Berger.
Berger?
Yeah,
I work at Lehman Brothers.
Tell me what you saw.
I saw the plane just collided into it,
into the middle,
and then I,
you know,
saw the people jumping out of the buildings.
It's just horrible.
All these people are just jumping because they're on fire.
So you saw people fall?
My coworker,
his wife is on the
82nd floor.
Do you know any of these people at all?
No,
but my coworker's wife is there,
and I feel so horrible.
I don't know if she made it out.
Where were you exactly?
I was outside when I was...
I was coming into the building because I came in a little late today and I just saw the whole plane go right into it.
Did you see both collisions?
I just saw one of them because I was on the side.
It's horrible.
Were you in the middle of the smoke?
What was going on around you?
They just started pushing everyone out of the way and then everybody just started running because you heard the explosion.
And what did you do?
I just ran and everyone just stayed on the sidelines watching all these people jumping out of the building and they're all on fire.
It's just horrible.
It's absolutely horrible.
Our heart goes out to the people.
Thank you.
It's horrible.
Damn.
I'm a couple blocks up on the west side of the island.
We're, like, way a block away.
Of course, you feel like crying.
This is absurd.
This is our country.
You knew this was coming.
What do we do that we're so wrong?
We did nothing.
We did nothing wrong.
You know when they did it,
Howard?
These are people who live in countries where they're enslaved.
They're going to say that we've participated in terrorist acts as well.
Who cares?
You know what?
Now is the time to stop their rhetoric.
You know,
that's their religion.
This is our religion.
Now you got,
for the first time,
you got the excuse to...
Really wipe out these animals.
Animal countries.
Don't target Osama bin Laden.
Do you realize how many people are probably,
you know,
dead or injured?
A thousand.
Fucking Habib.
So what makes you think it's immediately
Arabs? Yeah.
What do you think?
Well,
I don't know.
They're the ones that got us first,
bro.
Muslims,
Egyptians.
Egyptians and the others were Pakistani,
I'm not sure.
It's a mix.
See what appears to be a layer of white dust or ash on the street.
It's like snow.
I believe I was the one talking about that Delta 1989.
Go ahead.
Okay,
well,
disregard that.
Did you?
What we found out is that he was not a confirmed hijack.
Okay,
I don't want you to worry about that right now.
We got a United 93 out here.
Are you aware of that?
That has a bomb on board.
A bomb on board.
And this is confirmed.
Do you have a Mode 3,
sir?
No,
we lost this transponder.
What we want to know is,
did you scramble airplanes for that Delta 1989?
We did,
out of Selfridge and Toledo.
Did you?
Are they in the air?
Yes,
they are.
Is there any way we can get them to where this United is?
I cannot tell you where that happens.
That's either U.S.
Air force, or navy aircraft,
fighter aircraft,
now on patrol in what we've described as the no-fly zone over New York City today.
Be one more attempt.
John,
go ahead.
They've continued evacuations in the area now.
They're evacuating Battery Park City,
which is a large apartment complex taking up many blocks across the street from the World Trade Center.
Let's go!
Watch,
roll in all this mad sound.
People are just scared of it.
Watch.
All right,
we're going to go to Rick Armstrong.
He's one of our photojournalists.
He's down on the mall.
Rick?
Hi,
Buck.
What you got?
Not a whole lot other than the fact that the city is shut down.
I'm at the base of the Washington Monument.
A park police officer a few minutes ago told me They've shut down all the monuments.
They're evacuating all the buildings,
including the White House.
I can look across the river at the Pentagon,
and it's an incredible smoke plume.
Emergency vehicles going in every direction.
Looked like secret service vehicles,
fire vehicles,
police vehicles.
25 years here,
I've never seen anything like this.
Water on the unit calling.
Charlie
consolidated. Everybody's moving out to West.
Okay,
there is now on that United 93,
there is a report of black smoke in the last position I gave you.
15 miles south of Johnstown.
From the airplane or from the ground?
They're speculating it's from the aircraft.
Okay.
It hit the ground.
That's what they're speculating.
It's speculation only.
Okay.
Preliminary report that United 93 hit the ground about 15 miles south of Johnstown.
We were just coming around the corner when it blew.
And we just ran and we couldn't see anything.
For smoke.
What are you thinking now?
I don't know.
Get him out!
What we do not know is whether or not the vice president and the National Security team have stayed inside the White House situation Room.
We know that they were directing and monitoring operations from there as of just about 15 minutes,
15,
20 minutes ago.
They can't get the guys in the tower.
They can't get the guys that are in the tower.
I need you to operate a number two oil tracer. That's a collapse.
Contact my head and my radio,
fourth whip.
Number three,
five,
nine,
one,
pop,
Cleveland.
And
20VF, you about over that now?
We're coming up on it.
I'm getting ready to call you with some coordinates.
Do you want me to do that?
Yes,
please,
sir.
What's your name?
My name is Jason.
Jason,
what's your last name?
Jason Johnson.
Tell me what you saw.
Well,
I was working in the building,
D.C. 37,
working for the polls.
They evacuated the building.
When I came out,
all you saw was flames.
Next thing, you know,
people just dropping out the building.
I counted at least 33 people dropping from just this side of the building.
I could imagine what happened on the other side.
And I'm just glad that none of my family in there,
that's what I know.
And as we were standing outside the building,
we just seen the whole front side of the building just fall.
Boom,
boom,
that's all I heard.
Such a terror to actually beat.
Yo,
I done seen people get shot and stabbed,
but this,
I never seen this before.
Well,
as we know,
there was two planes that crashed into the world Trade.
That's what they said.
It was what happened to the Pentagon,
right?
No,
what happened?
There was a plane that crashed into the Pentagon,
too.
Well,
somebody had just told me when I was over there,
they said...
It had to be a terrorist because he was outside when the first plane crashed.
He heard the boom.
And when they evacuated his building,
he saw the second plane come.
The second plane circled around the building and then saw the building and just went straight into it.
He said the second plane knew what it was doing.
Smoke inhalation.
The victim's coming in.
That when this fell,
it hit a lot of other people.
When the tower fell,
a lot of other people got hurt.
But that it's terrorism.
They're looking for a third plane.
You'll be fine.
Don't worry.
Come here.
Where's your...
Over here.
We're gonna try to catch them.
We're trying to catch them,
everybody.
Don't worry.
Okay,
Victor, 20 Victor Foxtrot,
sir,
can you...
Can you give me a position on the activity there?
Yeah,
it's guesstimating, maybe 10 miles for 20VF and maybe 1,000 feet or so below it.
Okay,
1,000 feet below you, and it's in your 2 o'clock position, you say,
10 miles?
Affirmative.
It appears to be just a dark cloud, like a puff of black smoke.
Okay,
sir.
I don't want to put you in any kind of situation,
but if you...
Can you see anything over there,
sir?
Do you see any flames or anything?
Negative on the flames.
We don't see any flames.
Can't see that much of the ground from here.
Okay,
20VF,
you can descend at your discretion and maintain 5,000.
Sir,
do you have GPS on board?
Is there any way you can give me any kind of fix on this?
We do have GPS.
I don't know how we could give you an accurate picture without flying over the position over there.
Okay,
sir.
I don't want to put you in any kind of situation,
but if you can think you can fly over it,
you can have whatever altitude you want. And give us the exact GPs on that.
That would probably help us out.
Okay,
we'll head over in that direction,
and we're going to 5,000 to Jervik Departure.
To zero. VICTOR Fox,
let me know when you get there,
sir,
and we'll get a lat long from it.
Thank you.
We'll do zero, Victor Fox.
Yeah,
where you going?
Brooklyn.
Yeah,
great.
Thanks.
There is no fucking building.
What can you do?
All right,
hold on one sec,
go.
We have multiple units on the way in.
I can tell you is, as you can imagine, absolute chaos.
People were running panicking just when the- Man,
I saw that building collapse,
man,
I've been down.
People were trying to head down south, towards the World Trade Center,
when suddenly there was a large rumbling in the entire town.
Fell and collapsed to the ground.
People came running north because of the smoke.
It was billowing up Broadway.
There's a thick black cloud of smoke.
You can't even see down Broadway from the vantage point of City Hall.
I've now moved inside a building, but all the buildings along Broadway here at City Hall are being evacuated.
On my way up to this building, I ran into a woman who was in Tower 2 when the plane crashed into Tower 1.
What's the reaction of the people there?
Mostly tourists,
I'm sure,
and some working in the area.
To be honest with you,
I've talked to a lot of tourists,
and they're just,
what do you expect?
They're all shocked.
It's unbelievable.
It's hideous.
I know.
I can imagine what it's like down there.
We're sitting here,
every plane we keep an eye on.
I imagine everybody throughout the city,
you see a plane.
I've had no luck making any communication, except for I'm on a payphone.
The cell phones are down.
The TVs are down.
I don't know why.
I think we know why.
We decided to come to this location.
I'm with Frank Herzog.
We were on a sports story.
We decided to come.
To this location because this is a very likely spot for it for an act of terrorism.
Can't even see the second tower.
It looks like right now that the World Trade Center is only one building.
That's the way it appears from about 10 blocks north.
You can see that the existing tower is on fire for maybe the top 30 floors or so.
It's shooting out on the west side of the tower and behind him, to either side or just move.
Which almost looked like huge corrals at this point.
I don't even see a second tower.
It's like a creek.
Fire Marshal Squad, 282,
Manhattan,
City wide.
Squad 2A,
go ahead.
We're moving some people,
3 and 5,
more than some people,
to chase back a broadway.
We're setting up an ad hoc emergency post with EMS personnel,
K.
We could use more people because the place is filling up with engines.
All right,
10-4,
We have multiple units on the way in at this time,
K.
10-4.
Mark,
the best coordinated previous attack against the United States was nearly,
well,
I believe, in 1998,
though we're going to have to check on that.
You'll remember the two embassies in Kenya and Tanzania were attacked.
220-some people were killed,
including 12 Americans.
Early indications,
according to U.S.
Officials who tell
NBC's chief foreign Affairs correspondent, Andrea Mitchell,
Is that
Osama bin Laden is being indicated?
Because this note says he was the only terror leader with the capability of coordinating such an attack. This took enormous coordination.
This took a lot of money.
This took a lot of, a lot of, a lot of complete disregard for human life, this took insanity.
So those officers going in here,
as you can see,
all kinds of fire workers going in there,
literally in the thousands now converging on this site.
We cannot give you much of an organizational sense beyond telling you probably what you already know,
which is that. Two separate aircraft have struck the two towers of the World Trade Center.
If memory serves,
I think each of those towers stands 110 stories.
Some of the dust,
as you can probably see now,
is blowing in our faces.
It really depends on which way the wind blows, as to whether or not we're enveloped in some of the dust and the smoke.
Just your back.
Please don't.
Just your side.
As you can see from these pictures,
the amount of dust from the fire that's still burning,
flames and ash,
is extraordinary at this point.
And at least a few emergency workers have said that they really aren't so sure that other tower won't stay up now.
They really didn't think the first one was capable of coming down,
but it did.
And so they're basically saying, keep back as far as you can.
On the other hand,
facing that danger,
as we have been telling you,
many,
many hundreds of these workers are heading over those lines,
down towards that burning building,
to try to rescue those people who are in there,
be they emergency workers,
be they civilians.
Were you able to get any information?
Did it happen?
I was in a building.
Oh my God,
you were in the building?
I was on the 92nd floor of Number 2.
And I didn't see the first plane crash,
but I was on the lower floor when the second plane crashed into number 2.
And my brother's a photojournalist, and he's down there now.
I hope he's okay.
How did you get out?
I walked down 92 floors and I stopped on...
On the 70 something floor because they said everything was okay in the second plane crash into the second building right here. Of course, at this point, everyone's concerned. It's just getting north, getting away from the World Trade Center, as well as finding out where their families are. There are lines around the block to use pay phones. Everyone is scrambling, trying to figure out what is happening here. We will bring you more as soon as we know it. Eileen LaPalmer Live 1527 Mode 3. We got a track number 1527, Mode 3. We got a track number.
Okay,
we got a Mode 3 on this
United 93.
How close are you?
3951 North.
07846 West.
Got it.
Toledo was...
Look for him.
Okay,
I need a track number.
Okay.
Okay,
Ian.
Weapons?
Two...
Apparently we've got a United 9 and a 9-3 bomb on board 20 minutes. ...
Will be airborne in less than 20 minutes.
Mode 3,
15-27.
Any weapons?
We don't know.
We'll press with that.
We have anybody committed on the...
We're getting to it.
We don't know where it is.
We're getting...
Just pass that to weapons.
Yeah.
Okay.
Got it.
You're at 9-3.
Mode
3, 15-27.
Negative.
Negative clearance to shoot.
Jamie.
1-5-2-7,
Brian.
Good.
Damn it.
Foxy,
fuck the code words.
That's perishable information.
Negative clearance to fire.
ID Type tail.
Hey,
let your guys know also.
Fucking nuts are going in there,
bro.
Get out!
What you are looking at now is a close-up of the enormous hole.
In the side of that building.
That is exactly what happens when a plane hits the side of the World Trade Center.
Let's go to Lauren Ashburn now,
USA Today.
She's,
uh,
Lauren?
Frank?
This is Andrea and Buck.
Hi,
Andrea.
Buck.
I am on the
22nd floor of the USA Today
Tower 1 building,
overlooking this immense plume of smoke,
the e-ring of the Pentagon.
You can't even see it from this distance.
Is a helicopter hovering over the site,
taking pictures and taking a look at what's happening inside.
I'm looking down on traffic,
which is completely gridlocked on route 50,
heading out of the city,
heading into the city on route 395.
You can see traffic is moving along quite quickly,
and we have heard several...
It was a little difficult at first.
Welcome to Ireland!
You've got another?
It's a strange dog!
Let's go back to New York City for a second.
The latest reports now from the Associated Press does say that one of those towers,
this is World Tower Center 1,
the second tower hit,
has collapsed.
Now that's the second tower,
and we believe that was the one hit higher up.
We do not control this camera.
It is from New York City.
But the Associated Press is reporting that the second tower has collapsed.
We don't know if that's a complete collapse,
a partial collapse,
or whatever.
We hope to see it soon.
Once again,
you're looking at...
.a.t. Tower 2. And this was the first one hit just after 9 o'clock this morning.
How do you fight a fire like this?
You let it burn.
The only time that we really have any kind of comparative experience as to how to do this,
rather how to compare it to,
I suppose,
is. In 1945,
a B-25,
an
Army B-25,
just at the end of World War II,
crashed into the Empire State Building,
and that caused,
obviously,
a great deal of damage,
but it happened at night,
so the loss of life was not that bad.
And center 20,
Victor Foster coming up on that.
Our coordinates are 4002.2,
785,
4.7.
And it looks like dark smoke on the ground, on the edge of a field,
bordered by a street area or forest area at the end of a road.
Okay,
sir.
Are you seeing any kind of flames or anything?
No flames,
black smoke,
and it's the end of a dirt road near a wooded area.
We're circling now.
Yes.
We're standing at direct-in traffic on Morris Street and the West Side Highway.
All of a sudden,
a loud noise.
Building came tumbling down,
creating a lot of smoke and ash and gray and fire.
Couldn't see a thing.
Could not see a thing.
I ran for...
Of my life ran through the tunnel. It got so cloudy in there and foggy and choky with smoke. I couldn't breathe. Somebody came back and gave me a lift out of the tunnel. It's scary, really scary. Directly below the building, right? I couldn't see that far.
Everything came crashing down, everybody ran.
I'll direct in traffic, there's people up there already. Yes, down below. Yeah, I was. I was two blocks away, two blocks away, and it was messed up, messed up. As you can see, it's still coming down, now, still coming down. It is scary. one scary thing. Can't,
can't, it's hard to see.
I just found out from one of the guys that a plane hit the Pentagon too, so I don't know what's going on. There's a terrorist attack now. Also. Mike Lito, thank you.
I know.
It's hard.
L-E-T-O,
from truck enforcement.
L-E-T-O.
Can I have a number to reach you?
We just,
you know.
Yeah,
I couldn't believe that building crashing.
Oh man,
I saw it.
I saw it when I was over here.
It just came down.
They should have took those buildings down since the first bombing.
Since the first bombing,
the structure,
I believe the structure was not sturdy enough.
That's why it came down.
Well,
you know,
this is the kind of a thing that has fallen more into Tom Clancy novels than into actual response planning.
Having said that,
we've been anticipating for a long time,
we've wondered why it's been so relatively quiet.
The suggestions of Osama Bin Laden's involvement,
what has he been doing since? coal,
other groups out there with a real or imagined grudge against the United States.
He's dead,
here's the thing.
They got officers trapped in the subway station on Chamber Street.
You hear that?
What?
They got a door online,
they're standing off the track,
they're requesting assistance.
Yeah,
The officers trapped in the Chamber Street station.
They're probably evacuating the people.
Uh-huh,
okay.
Let's go back to Dave, who is at the Pentagon site.
Stater A,
I just heard another explosion of some sort.
Now it could be a secondary explosion here from something happening.
We just heard a loud puff, just as you were coming to me.
It seemed to be on the east...
Of here,
I can't tell what it is.
It might be something that's secondary to this because we had a number of small explosions after the fire occurred.
Dave,
we understood there was construction.
The area that was struck by the plane and what's on fire,
was that the area under construction?
So maybe there weren't a lot of people in that area?
There is,
yeah,
there's toward the south end of this area, there are construction trailers,
I can say that,
but I don't,
can't tell you for sure. If this area was,
would be sparsely populated.
Would you ever predict the Pentagon?
Never.
I mean,
who knows?
They thought there was a third one here.
What's that noise?
That's one of the military jets that's circling over the tip of Manhattan and the tip of Brooklyn.
Howard,
this ability has got to be shot.
This has become one of those movies.
They must be trying to find that other plane that they're circling like that.
How many people do you think...
Think we're in that world trade center at the time of this attack.
The two world trade centers together got to be over 75,000 or 100,000 people.
They said 50,000 people work in the two buildings.
Between 50,000 and 70,000 work in the two world Trades.
Are you okay?
President,
you know,
I've been in this business almost
40 years,
and quite frankly,
I couldn't have written a scenario like this.
If I would have come forward with something like,
possibly like this,
they would have laughed.
This has all of the worst case scenarios put together into one.
This is monumental.
This will be something that,
you know,
you get Gary Condit in the news,
you have O.J.
This is something that we're going to be...
Looking at for the next couple of years,
unfortunately,
and not just from a media perspective,
but from the people who've witnessed this.
I mean,
when you think of the psychological trauma that this is going to cause to New Yorkers and to Americans,
it's monumental.
It's off the map.
We have two explosions,
two planes hitting the World Trade Center here in New York,
and what this second explosion was that took place above.
God,
we are so blessed.
Thank you,
God.
We're so alive,
Bureau here in New York joins us on the phone.
Alan,
where are you?
My colleague Jennifer Westhoven also just arrived.
She was closer to the building.
I'm just south of Canal Street,
about 10 blocks north of World Trade Center.
Just before 10 o'clock,
parts of the building began peeling away.
People started screaming.
Jennifer tells me,
because she was a little closer to the building,
that the police began yelling,
run,
And thousands of people started running away from the buildings as they were falling.
That was,
of course,
followed by an onrush of ambulances and special police vehicles.
Some people have told us,
although I can't confirm this,
that dozens of stories of the building have fallen away,
maybe down as low as the 30th floor.
Michael,
if you can hear me,
we just heard another explosion down at the Pentagon building.
We just heard another loud explosion down at the Pentagon building just seconds ago.
That's our Audrey Barnes,
who is standing nearby the Pentagon,
saying they heard a second explosion.
Audrey,
did you see anything since these other attacks have been aerial?
Did you see anything flying overhead just before this explosion?
We can't see exactly where the source of the explosion was,
but you could hear it very clearly with a loud boom.
And
I'm looking for another plume of smoke.
I don't see anything right now.
It might be still in that same general area where the fire is burning right now.
But you could clearly hear another loud explosion.
I was sitting next to it, right beside it.
Tell me what you saw.
Well,
I was at my desk and I saw the building.
I felt the building rumble.
After that,
I looked outside.
I saw papers everywhere.
Then I looked.
I saw a big hole in the water.
center,
then we all evacuated our building.
And when I went outside,
Unbelievable.
It's the markings of a leased.
Well,
often in the Middle East, when there's a bombing,
a s****** bombing or a car bombing,
you'll find a second bomb going off when the emergency response crews respond.
Right.
Which just happened.
They are so sweet,
those people.
This is our worst case scenario.
This is something.
A fourth plane has just crashed into...
I'm not sure where.
This is something that has...
Let me see,
someone's on the phone saying that
Palestine and that Bensama bin Laden guy is claiming responsibility,
whatever his name is.
Oh,
the second plane was in Jersey,
huh?
Both from an investigative standpoint.
Hold on,
I'll get to that guy.
From a response standpoint,
is going to be...
Another explosion hits Lower Manhattan.
Oh my God.
Clearly, you can only do so much...
Hold on,
let me see what this guy's saying.
The nature of the event is shocking.
The fact that it's happened is not.
Thank you very much,
Carl.
Really appreciate it.
Carl Olson.
One quick thing.
The suggestions that are floating around out there right now,
there's apparently this claim from the Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine.
Right.
Very interesting to note,
if this is legitimate,
if this claim stands up,
this appears to be the first time this group has targeted Americans.
This group has primarily steered away from the more extreme end of the violence scale.
They focus on the violence.
Less on s****** bombings,
more on gun attacks and that sort of thing in the territories against Israelis.
If this holds up,
this is a very different tactic.
Well,
if it is true,
of course,
The Democratic Front for Liberation of Palestine was very much involved in attacking aircraft in the
1970s.
We're actually being asked to move back by Virginia State police a little bit.
We're going to try to keep this location as much as possible.
The reason they asked us to move back is because,
of course,
they're concerned about any secondary explosions.
I can tell you from my experience as a firefighter,
there's still a great deal of fire inside the Pentagon by the smoke that's coming out of there.
I'm sure firefighters are inside, making sure first that they can get everybody out that they can, and then trying to attack the fire inside.
They've also had fire,
of course,
on the outside, that probably involved some sort of airplane fuel.
That's why it burned so well.
It's still burning,
in fact,
on the side.
South end, on the outside, near those construction trailers.
Again,
I can't tell you much more other than a loud pop. Just a few minutes ago. That seemed a little bit different,
a little bit different than the ones we heard earlier, which were on the outside here. That could have been tires or something else.
We're just watching also as they're taking another man to the hospital.
Looks like it's going to be a medevac.
And what I can tell,
it looks like he's burned.
There seems to be a burn sheet on top of him.
Medics are taking him to the U.S.
Park Police
Eagle helicopter.
This is a vehicle,
and we have seen ambulance issues.
As you see the scope of this and the mythology of this,
radical way in which it appears to have been planned and happened.
And again,
we don't know what truly occurred,
but there's talk of aircraft being hijacked,
of second explosions,
of et cetera,
et cetera.
What if there are signals...
And again,
just because we lost a little bit at the beginning,
where are you physically now?
I'm just south of the Holland Tunnel in downtown Manhattan,
perhaps
10 to 15 blocks north of the World Trade Center.
Got it.
And the pictures that our viewers are looking at,
this was that collapse of the South Tower just a few minutes ago here in New York.
The President of the United States,
President Trump,
and President Obama have been in the same position for more than a decade.
The President of the United
States, President Trump,
and President Obama have been in the same position for more than a decade.
The President of the United States,
President Trump,
and President Obama
take all that.
I'm the last one.
There's nobody up on 23?
No.
They evacuated everybody down.
Alright,
they're probably going to the bus.
Thanks.
Yeah.
I think we'll try to get a shot of that.
We're going to show you over here on Washington Boulevard.
The Eagle helicopter from Park Police is landing,
taking this man to the hospital.
From my vantage point,
it looks like he has burns.
We also,
besides Arlington Fire and Rescue,
see some doctors,
what appear to be...
Be doctors on the scene, not sure if they're military or not, they seem to be helping with the injured. This dust is just starting to settle. After the Second World Trade Center collapsed, we saw it collapsed and come towards us. I'm
doing, uh, well, as good as can be expected. I've got guys that will be launching in about 15 minutes. Appreciate it. Are they loaded?
We've got hot guns.
That's all I've got.
Well,
that's good enough for me for the time being.
Only words I've got,
I've got another possible aircraft with a bomb on board.
It's in
Pennsylvania, York,
approximately area.
Yeah,
that's south.
south of us.
And there's also the possibility of another one that's possibly at Cleveland area.
Okay.
Do we have vectors on those?
Not yet.
It's like one over Cleveland turned around.
Looks like he's heading back.
The guy down at York,
Pennsylvania,
he's heading north,
northwest.
Okay.
We might be able to get those,
too.
Yeah.
And the call sign for the guy in York is United. 93,
Mode 3 of
1527. Okay.
It doesn't help us.
We can't interrogate.
Okay.
And I got this other guy out west.
He's American.
Where's that guy?
The track is fading over Cleveland.
Okay,
I got one who dissipated over. Cleveland,
Delta
8-9er,
Mode 3.
I know it's not going to help you,
but if you're talking to FAA,
they might be able to help you.
13-04.
Okay,
when we get our guys airborne,
they're going to contact you on 260.9.
I've got two jets right now.
Do you need more than two?
Can you bring up two more?
Get four to them.
Yep,
yep.
Okay,
thank you,
sir.
And if you want to talk to Colonel Marr,
he's up at
6403, sir.
Thank you.
So you're a journalist as well?
I make videos and my sister called me right when it happened, and
I just knew I had to go.
I actually got on tape of the crashing down of the building.
Right at the Pentagon.
Audrey,
from where we're standing,
from where we're watching,
rather,
it appears now we can start to see the shell of something there.
Can you have any better vantage point on what may have,
on the type of,
on an aircraft,
see any wreckage at all?
All now.
It seems like the smoke is dissipating to a certain extent.
From what witnesses have said,
they saw the tail of some type of aircraft go into the Pentagon building.
I'm still trying to confirm that from somebody who's on the scene,
but there's a couple of people who are coming from the Pentagon building. That I'd like to see if I can get some information about that.
Can we do that with Johnstown through tower when he goes over to tower?
Okay,
yeah,
go ahead.
This is imperial go for
06. If I can,
I'm going to take him down towards that report of smoke area.
I just got it, Bill,
I have it.
I have the.
I see a guy right over it right now.
You can do what you want,
but I have a guy down there at 5,000 feet over through it.
We got the lat-longs and everything.
And a report.
That was the United.
He sees smoke and he doesn't see flames.
He sees smoke and,
yeah.
Okay,
I got it.
That's a positive idea.
All right.
Bye.
Okay,
sir,
can you see any kind of wreckage or anything out there?
As we get around this side of it,
the smoke is blowing away from us.
We do see flames.
It's on the edge,
like I say,
of a wooded area.
And a very, fairly clean field.
But I don't see wreckage.
I do see flames now and dark smoke.
Okay,
2-0, Victor, Fox,
Roger.
Roy,
I'm going to keep you there for just one more second in case we need a little more information,
if that's alright with you,
sir.
Yeah,
everything appears to be okay for us.
Okay,
we think it was a United Jet,
sir,
that was bombed.
Bob.
Bob,
are you there?
Bob?
Okay,
hold it a second.
Wait.
Bob?
Hello?
Yeah,
you there?
Howard,
I'm here.
Alright,
what's this fourth plane?
Well,
it's just being broadcast now,
Howard,
that a fourth plane,
the two that hit the World Trade Center,
then there was one at the Pentagon,
And now a fourth plane has crashed into the South Tower and actually made the tower fall.
Is that right?
Oh,
my God.
And they're also saying that the Palestinians and Osama bin Laden...
Are claiming responsibility for this.
They've come out and said that they are the ones doing this.
Well,
let's...
They're not done yet.
Then let Israel loose.
Let Israel loose.
Let
Israel loose?
We have to do this.
Let the U.S.
loose.
Let me tell you something.
We have to go to war with the countries we have to go to.
It could be taken care of in an hour.
We could wipe them off the face of the earth.
We don't want governments who would allow this to happen again to stand.
An hour is too long,
Howard.
In an hour from now,
they could have six more planes crash into the city.
Where is the fourth plane head,
Alex?
The fourth plane crashed where?
Into the World Trade Center.
Into the South Tower.
Hi,
Pat.
We chose to stay in our hotel room because from our vantage point,
we're in a corner suite of this hotel.
So we have actually two windows looking out on the corner of our building at the World Trade Center.
We could see the building number two was going to go,
and my husband and I were having a debate,
stay,
go.
And my husband said, If it collapses,
we'll be killed below.
So we chose to stay in our room,
which is where we still are on the
35th floor.
And the building literally wouldn't collapse.
Where were you, guys?
We were working on the 50th floor of the laundry room.
Oh, yeah?
On the 50th floor?
Yeah,
like a horse pick.
And the building shook?
Yeah.
But it hit above you,
right?
Yeah.
So...
We did not fall.
So were you able to get down in an elevator?
No,
we had to walk.
You had to walk?
Yeah.
Was there total panic in the building?
No.
You were in front of that other black...
Just tell me,
what did you see?
What did it look like?
It just looked like a lot of smoke on the upper floors.
It collapsed.
It looked like the entire building collapsed down on top of itself and spreading debris all over.
I mean,
it's a horrific scene.
I just wish we knew who we were at war with.
I think it's terrible.
You don't know whether it's an enemy from within or it's an enemy without.
It's horrible.
There's no words for it.
There are no words,
are there?
No.
This is time when Americans come together.
Joseph Fichera.
Spell the last name,
Joe.
F-I-C-H-E-R-A.
Terrific.
And?
Paul Sutherland.
S-O-U-F-U-T-H-E-R-L-A-N-D.
It's terrible.
My legs started shaking.
I couldn't do anything after that.
You just saw them jumping?
I saw them jumping.
I could see them clearly.
They had their ties flying,
their blue shirts.
It was,
and I've seen everything happen through everything,
and this one tops it all. In terms of the temerity,
in terms of the planning,
in terms of what the aftermath is going to be,
the shock to the American psyche,
to the American public.
I mean,
think about this.
We try to calm people down by telling them,
you know,
the chances of you being involved in a terrorist act is very,
very small.
What do we tell people now when they walk around New York City and look up and see the tree towers on fire?
We see other buildings exploding.
We see people crying in the streets.
I mean,
this is a horrific event,
and it's a very,
very sad day.
Mark,
I want to remind you that the wire is saying that the South Tower there collapsed following this morning's plane crash.
There is not yet confirmation of a fourth plane.
We want to remind you, the first plane hit.
Hit the North tower of the World Trade Center,
which you see there still standing.
Second plane hit the South Tower,
which later collapsed.
We're not sure if another plane was involved.
A third plane hit the Pentagon.
Okay,
first of all,
tell us what you saw.
You're talking with Fox 5.
What did you see?
I was in the remote delivery facility,
which is the area where they process incoming deliveries and so forth.
We heard.
Explosion And then about
10 minutes later, something came over the the announcement saying Evacuate the building, so all we heard was an explosion. Nothing, nothing dropped in the ceiling or anything in the RDF, which is this building right here,
I understand a plane has hit the building so
Well,
the scene gets worse.
We just saw about six people jump out of the
North building from the top.
Oh my God.
What?
Jumping out of the building.
Jumping?
To escape,
I guess,
what seems to be an unbelievable fire and smoke inhalation.
There had to be five or six bodies.
Paired for this kind of devastating attack,
the Air Force was not in place.
Questions, though why are these huge planes flying out of airports hijacked and nobody knows anything FBI knew about one of them? No, but there's control towers that these planes are leaving their flight here. It is third blast, brought down tower, third blast now.
Maybe not from a plane, because the building could have blown up just because of the fire alone, because that looked like a bomb. I think what you're hearing in our background is Cabbie is out in Brooklyn. And you can hear the.
You can hear military planes going over,
you can hear emergency...
Um...
Mayor Giuliani established early on an office of emergency management to coordinate all the government agencies involved.
So you have coordinated leadership of police,
fire,
health,
all the city agencies.
Responding to that emergency.
They've planned for this kind of event.
Unfortunately,
this is not a unique occurrence in the life of New York City or our country.
Tragedies like this may not be a unique occurrence,
but it is a very rare and extraordinary one.
It is extraordinary and therefore,
therefore, in New York City, we have coordinated response and they're responding.
What happened?
Did the size of the building come down?
Something fell.
What did you see?
Ah,
it was pretty clear at one point. And then there's a whole bunch of smoke and glass.
And I think we're just about the last ones in this building right now.
I think you should leave.
Everybody else is gone.
Okay.
I'll just make sure that there's nobody else coming downstairs.
What do you think happened?
I hear the top of the building fell down.
Fell over on us.
I don't know.
I haven't even seen outside yet.
Have you,
ah...
How many were you here?
How many?
After the planes landed?
As a matter of fact,
we're standing right underneath
sixth World trade. When a building, actually,
the plane, hit it the first time.
Describe it.
We heard a plane,
the engine screaming,
and then just an explosion.
Glass,
then everybody was running around, trying to get away.
Tell me your name and spell it.
Bennett,
B-E-N-N-E-T-T-E.
Sergeant?
No,
secret Service.
Secret Service?
How do you want your title?
OST.
OST?
Thank you.
All right.
Now,
at the time,
we had MSNBC's feed up.
Right.
And we could clearly hear people...
Saying in the background,
My God,
another plane.
Really?
Okay.
And then the South Tower disappears.
Now,
you said you were inside the building when this happened?
Yes,
the remote delivery facility,
which is the wing of the new Pentagon.
So there's parts of debris of airplane and stuff scattered along the road here.
So,
and then I just heard another explosion.
Up there,
so someone told me an airliner hit the building.
Anybody describe the plane to you?
How large was the plane that hit the Pentagon?
It was a commercial-sized airliner.
I'm not sure how big it was.
Gentleman just said he was sitting on 95.
The plane flew very low over his car and hit the building and blew his windows out of his vehicle.
And he was on Interstate 395.
Looks like everybody's in shock.
It's unbelievable.
It's a dark day,
very dark day.
And I just heard an explosion back over that way.
I'm not sure what that was either.
So
I'm just trying to get home to my family. And try to let people do what they need to do here. And try to get people out of the way and let the emergency people do what they gotta do.
Oh, man.
And everyone here is just,
I mean,
it's a sight that doesn't,
you can't even describe.
I'm doing a terrible job telling you what I'm seeing,
but it defies words.
It is the most horrible.
I can now see some blue sky where the second building was,
the South building.
It's not there.
Nice and orderly,
nice and orderly,
no need to run.
Nice and orderly,
The one that just collapsed,
the reason for that devastating collapse was not an implosion.
He's saying it was a fourth plane.
That's what's on the news.
How could a fourth plane possibly get through?
I'll tell you how.
Because they have hostages on there.
Whatever the confusion is in this moment,
we are not prepared for this kind of devastating attack.
The Air Force was not in place.
Dr.
Kushner,
I don't know if you're watching television,
but we are now showing...
Our very first pictures of some of the victims of this today,
and we can see some horrific,
what appears to be burns,
some serious injuries.
Again,
this is video that we have just gotten in.
Yes.
I'm watching it.
I can see it.
Two planes going straight into the World Trade Center and you can see the picture there.
Smoke still billowing.
The fire is completely out of control.
It's making the job of the rescue services extremely difficult.
We've seen a few helicopters trying to get to the scene,
but visibility must be extremely difficult for them.
I have your attention, please.
I have
Four.
Three.
That area was completely evacuated.
You know,
if I might just interject this,
I was involved in a civil litigation against the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey because
I was representing with a team of attorneys who represented two clubs.
Clients were at the B2 level.
And the Trade Towers was warned many years in advance that there's a possibility of having a bomb placed in the bottom of the building.
And my report showed that the construction of that building was in such,
beyond the code,
that even such a powerful bomb couldn't do the damage.
But now, looking at these pictures as we speak,
it just,
I'm choked up looking at it,
thinking that this type of risk assessment.
Wasn't there and we didn't have. But how do you guard against something like this? So, um, while officials may not have confirmed it, it seems fairly clear, plus, the tower would not have collapsed absent some tremendous trauma. Absolutely, and that that seems to to make sense. And that was my next question. Second explosion at Pentagon building reported, according to Dow Jones. That is literally just crossing, a second explosion, a second explosion. Could we get up? the Pentagon shot reported at the Pentagon
.of. A plane crashing at the Pentagon,
the Pentagon being evacuated,
fire on the mall in Washington,
the State Department evacuated,
and we...
We have all flights shut down across the country as officials sort out what's happening here.
Randy,
back to you for a second.
How much of the,
well,
if I recall this correctly,
there is a,
what was called a bunker,
the mayor's bunker for these sorts of events in the trade Center,
correct?
There is an emergency management center.
The scene is covered with extra equipment right here.
My question is,
was the first building,
the one that's still up,
the second one was where the big plane went into the collapse,
right?
Yep.
And they're saying a possible third plane.
I also want to give you a heads up,
Washington.
Go ahead.
United 9-3,
have you got information on that yet?
Yeah,
he's down.
He's down?
Yes.
When did he land?
He did not land.
Oh,
he's down?
Yeah,
somewhere up northeast of Camp, David.
Northeast of St.
David.
That's the last report.
They don't know exactly where.
You can see now the thick pool of smoke that's enveloping the scene.
One of the other problems there,
of course,
is that these fumes will be extremely toxic.
That'll mean that only people with proper breathing apparatus will be able to get anywhere near the rescue work.
I think that's probably going to be restricting work as well.
There's nothing you can do now.
Let's go to Frank Herzog,
who is near one of the most visible monuments in the city,
the Washington Monument.
Frank,
what do you see?
What do you hear?
I'm on the west grounds of the Washington Monument.
The area has been completely evacuated by park police,
and I think I could answer Dave Statter's question about that secondary explosion.
It wasn't an explosion.
That was the sonic boom of jet fire.
Fighters that were scrambled out of Andrews Air Force Base,
we believe.
They just circled the Washington area,
flying from the east out to the west,
and they were in a hurry and they were high up in the air.
Maria
Bartiromo,
What can you tell us?
Thanks, Mark.
You know, now I'm standing on the floor of the exchange,
but I just came back from outside and I am covered with soot.
Basically,
I was outside when that third explosion occurred,
and everyone ran for their lives,
basically.
I went under a building.
There was a little stairwell that I could go under with about 20 people,
and we just stayed there.
The whole area turned pitch black when that third explosion happened.
At this point,
people are in the New York Stock Exchange.
People feel that this is the safest place to be right now, because when everyone was outside,
there was...
explosion.
There were three explosions.
So now the exchange is keeping everyone inside.
I'm on the floor with about,
I don't know,
100,
200 people right here,
and we're just waiting.
That's all I can tell you.
It's pitch black outside.
There's soot falling from the sky.
I don't know if you could see my jacket and my shoes,
but I'm completely covered in white smoke. From the explosion,
from that third explosion.
Maria,
do you know what that explosion was?
That was about,
I'd say,
15 minutes ago.
But do you know what caused it?
No,
I don't.
So jet fighters,
at least one,
possibly two,
were scrambled,
probably as a precautionary measure.
Needless to say,
downtown Washington,
D.C.,
Except for the vehicular traffic,
which is bumper to bumper,
the rest of the city has been shut down.
It looks like a Sunday morning here.
The mall is absolutely empty.
Park police came through about ten minutes ago,
evacuated the entire area.
And told tourists to go somewhere else.
But I can tell you right now that at least one,
if not two,
jet fighters have been scrambled.
They are patrolling the skies over Washington.
Frank Herzog,
Thank you very much.
No,
that wasn't a third.
It looked like the World Trade Center was almost...
Tipping at one point.
Yeah,
it did.
I think it was probably like that.
The World Trade Center just doesn't exist anymore.
No,
I think the one that's still up looks like it's almost buckling.
I think that's the one that got hit originally.
Charlie!
Let me just read you the lead,
the Associated Press lead,
just came out of New York.
First of all,
let's check in with Dave Stattert at The Pentagon.
Dave.
Oh,
it collapsed right now,
as you can see.
I assume you're taking our picture.
I do not have a monitor,
But right now. We just had a middle section here of the e-ring of the Pentagon. Collapse from the amount of fire and destruction from this.
So obviously there was a great deal of damage here.
It just collapsed.
We don't know who was inside or how many people were inside.
You hurt somebody.
One of the people who was inside the building talked to us a short time ago and said,
this e-ring of the Pentagon has a great many senior officials,
so if somebody was planning something,
this might have been the place if they wanted to get senior officials.
Again,
most of the fire on the outside of the building has been extinguished.
There's still some spot fires on the outside of the building,
and still,
from what I can see,
a great deal of fire inside.
So now you have a gaping hole on the west side of the Pentagon, here at Washington Boulevard,
and this collapse just happened.
It was not an explosion,
a secondary explosion.
This apparently the damage from the great deal of fire and the structural damage from the plane crash.
Any word yet,
Dave,
on casualties?
Bel Air,
Blue Ridge Ad line.
Bel Air.
Yeah,
I got him holding a ticket on a Med-X 411.
Did you guys divert him somewhere?
We put everybody on the ground.
All right.
The only plane I got in the air right now is a military plane.
All right,
you get to me.
TJ.
Bye.
I mean,
you don't just hijack an airplane.
It's not the easiest thing to do.
Yeah,
I mean,
and to do it simultaneously?
Right,
three or four airplanes.
Look at how long Japan planned to do
Pearl Harbor.
They did as much.
They did as much work as that.
This is a huge undertaking.
This is a war.
The problem is, we've been talking about Osama Bin Laden planning some new major attack on the United States for about a year.
We've been waiting for this.
You know,
we'll never know until this whole thing is over.
But for all we know,
their plans failed miserably.
And this is a third of what they were planning.
The world thought they were going to do on New Year's Eve in 1999.
And they were smart and they waited.
They waited until a random day in the middle of the week, in the middle of September.
Say was responsible for it and who's since been charged in it.
In this case,
I think this ratchets up.
Excuse me.
This is the Pentagon we're looking at now, according to my monitor.
And again,
it is hard to grasp what part of the building,
we do not know if they're in the courtyard or outside,
But you can see that a fairly considerable amount of damage has been done.
We do not know whether these are offices or storage areas.
Areas the Pentagon is full of many thousands of people every day. That
Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld has been saying only yesterday and today. If he wants to reduce the bloatedness. As he put it, as he alluded to it in the military.
And the bureaucracy,
but this is the great home of the military.
But this is the great home of the military bureaucratic establishment.
Can
you tell me your name,
please?
Yes.
Yes,
my name is Lisa Fleischer.
I live down in Gateway Plaza,
which is right across from the World Trade Center.
Where were you when this happened?
I was standing on the street,
and I heard the first explosion,
and I ran,
and
I didn't see what happened.
But then
I saw the second explosion happen.
It looked like a plane rammed into the second building,
and then that exploded as well.
What happened at that moment of impact?
It was just a huge fireball and pieces flying out,
papers flying.
Debris flying.
Heat coming off from the explosion.
What did you think it was?
Well,
we knew at the second hit that it was obviously a terrorist attack.
The first time, we just,
the first explosion.
Yeah,
yeah,
there was debris raining all over the place on the street.
What about bodies lying,
tell me,
like, what happened?
No,
it's,
well,
people were jumping.
People were,
we saw people jumping,
yes,
but I mean,
I'd rather not say in front of my daughter,
But our first thought was we had to go to the school and get my daughter and make sure that she was safe.
We just started running toward the school.
Thank God you're okay.
We did have people we heard in the background.
Something ignited there.
Maybe they had,
that was an incredible.
That was an incredible explosion.
And that does not cause from a.
I agree with you.
I think it was the third plane.
But again.
It could have been something that was planted.
Or a bomb planted in the building.
Yeah.
Let's bring ourselves up to date on the situation in Washington.
.these? Planes crashing in to the World Trade Center.
Sir,
can you tell me your name?
John,
can you hear me?
Yes,
I can.
John,
tell me what you saw.
This morning, we were at
midtown Manhattan in the 31st floor of a building facing south.
We saw a 767 flying low down the center of Manhattan Island.
Heading towards downtown Manhattan.
At about maybe
20 blocks north of the World Trade Center,
we saw the plane veer to the left and fly directly into the north side of the South Tower.
So this was the second plane that hit the tower,
correct?
No,
this was the first plane.
Got it.
This is the 767.
John,
hang on.
Other than seeing the two people we saw medevaced, who had serious burns,
I have not,
I can't confirm any others.
They've been working on people,
but we don't know what's inside that building, to be honest with you.
So,
Dave?
Certainly, anybody in those windows, or in those offices by those windows,
you have to be very,
very concerned about right now.
Hi,
Dave Stetter, reporting from the Pentagon.
Here you can see.
Most scared I've ever been in my whole life.
What happened,
sweetie?
What did you hear?
It started when I was in my classroom and we saw,
we heard the explosion.
The whole classroom,
it felt like the whole classroom jumped.
You heard both of them?
Yeah.
You heard both things?
Yes.
And then what did you do?
Well,
we had to run into the gym because they said,
please stay away from the south side of the building.
What's your name?
Lily.
Lily?
Thank you,
Lily.
Thank you.
Kate Snow is on Capitol Hill.
Kate,
what can you tell us about the events there?
Well,
I'm a couple of blocks away from the Capitol right now.
I can tell you that about a half hour ago,
the Capitol building itself was evacuated.
It was a little bit chaotic.
Everyone was running out of the building.
People ran a couple of blocks away.
We have now been pushed back by security.
We're within two blocks of the Capitol.
I did see myself a plane about a half hour ago circling over the Capitol.
Now, whether that may have been an air Force,
a U.S.
plane,
it's unclear.
But that seemed to be the reason,
according to security guards that I talked with,
for the evacuation of the Capitol.
They had seen something or heard something suspicious.
Rolling.
Yeah.
You were in the lobby of the main tower?
All right.
Tell me,
when the first explosion,
what time was it roughly?
I really don't remember.
That 845.
Tell me what it was like.
I just heard a big blast.
That was it.
And,
uh,
oh,
wait a second.
And
I started to,
I heard that noise once before,
and took off.
The lobby was flooded with water,
you know,
putting out the fires.
And then I went back to see how my friends were,
and the blast just happened now,
and I got caught across the street.
A couple of guys helped me get into the building across the street.
That's about it.
That's all I know.
Oh,
God.
It's amazing.
What are you thinking?
I really can't even think.
I'm just like...
I'm just out of breath.
I just hope my friends are okay.
You have friends inside there?
Yeah,
they were on the 88th floor of one World Trade Center.
So,
I can't talk.
I really can't talk.
I understand.
What's your first and last name?
Joseph Napolitano.
Joseph Napolitano?
Napolitano,
yeah.
Alright.
Yeah,
you gotta sit down.
Let's get up.
You saw the tower come down?
Yep.
It's not standing.
Press agents and everybody else that went the other way,
everybody else went this way.
When you saw this collapse taking place,
could you see if there were a lot of people on the ground near the building as it was happening?
No,
I was further north than you were,
but I was dead looking at 6th Avenue.
The view you see at Ball Towers is you come down 6th Avenue.
Right.
So.
We have a phone pilot who witnessed these planes crashing into the World Trade Center.
Sir,
can you tell me your name?
Hampton?
Yes.
Hampton Pearson?
You're looking at pictures right now,
taped earlier,
from the scene outside the Pentagon.
Outside the Pentagon.
That's what you're looking at right now.
We had one report...
The dust cloud has dissipated.
All units can respond into West Street and Albany Street for the second alarm for box 5-0.
The dust cloud has decided to the Brooklyn Battery Tunnel.
The BBC's Steven Sveich is there.
Does it look as if there have been two attacks on the Pentagon,
Steven?
So far, I think we're talking about one.
Now that may change,
but at the moment, it seems to have been just the one aircraft.
I mean,
I'm saying just one aircraft.
it is an extraordinary event for an aircraft to crash,
it seems,
next to the Pentagon.
It appears the building itself was not hit.
The reports we're getting is that there was a huge explosion which threw people off their feet inside the Pentagon.
That's according to U.S.
officials.
Hey,
come on guys,
let's go.
Come on.
Hey,
I got a painting.
Let's go.
From
Dave's camera shot,
several people being escorted out of the Pentagon.
The Pentagon is being evacuated,
as is the White House.
U.S.
Capitol.
Most monuments,
museums,
the city, basically,
as you've heard from Frank Herzog and from photojournalist Rick Armstrong near the Washington Monument,
closed down.
Almost everything is closed down.
To locate where the mayor is obviously, uh, usually in the winter is crisis situations. He would be down at the Office of Emergency Management, which is down at the World Trade Center, we cannot find him right now. The city Hall is also evacuated and locked down, obviously for security reasons. We will let you know as soon as we know when the mayor will speak, speak
with us.
This unfolding story here in Washington is number one,
an explosion,
sources saying a plane hitting a portion of the Pentagon.
As you mentioned earlier,
it is the world's largest office building on any given day.
At least 30,000 people work inside that five-sided structure.
Also here in Washington,
the White House,
the Capitol,
the Treasury Department,
and all of the national monuments,
in fact,
have been evacuated.
The FAA has basically ordered all air traffic nationwide shut down.
The president is en route back to
Washington, D.C. from Florida.
You heard his earlier comments.
Also,
we have just gotten word, too, that over at the IMF and World Bank buildings here in Washington, DC,
People there have been told they can leave the buildings,
but they are not required to leave.
.directly. Into the north side of the South Tower.
This is the second plane to get to the tower.
This is the first plane.
Got it.
John,
hang on.
Get in the snow like that.
We'll go.
Okay.
And eyewitnesses.
And they're talking about an airliner.
So we're talking about a large vehicle,
a large plane,
crashing near the Pentagon,
it seems,
just by a helicopter launch pad.
And one reporter who happened to be inside the building at the time,
she's been quoted as saying that she was thrown to the ground.
By the course of the blast.
We've got an eyewitness just coming up now.
There's one thing,
of course,
they've got multiple...
Banana field,
cop,
check.
We had a second alarm.
Oh,
second alarm.
Hold on,
one, five,
one, one, two.
They had different locations.
They had one building,
you know.
I can also...
Go ahead.
Kate,
I'm sorry,
and if you said this,
I apologize.
And I apologize to viewers, too.
Was there,
to your knowledge,
an explosion at the Capitol?
No,
sir,
there was not.
I cannot,
I can see the Capitol from here.
Everything looks to be fine.
There was,
however,
Aaron,
a...
Sound about five minutes ago, that sounded like some sort of explosion.
Everything is in close proximity here in Washington.
It could be that that may have been something that happened at the Pentagon.
We're not very clear on that.
Okay.
As to all how all this happened,
uh,
it's becoming.
It's becoming increasingly apparent that this was a terrorist attack.
President Bush,
as much as said so. About an hour ago,
what with two planes in very short order crashing into the
World Trade Center,
Both towers and the second south tower has now collapsed.
In addition,
a plane has apparently crashed near the Pentagon.
There have been threats.
Obviously,
all of these threats are incredible today.
The White House was evacuated to the Treasury,
the Capitol.
And now we have a report that there's...
There has been an explosion near the U.S. Supreme Court in Washington,
that, according to
Fox News.
As you can see,
a portion of the Pentagon has collapsed.
This happened after a jet.
Apparently deliberately plowed into the Pentagon.
We have Daniel McAdams on the phone.
He is an eyewitness.
Daniel,
Good morning.
What did you see and where are you?
I'm here in Arlington, just off of Columbia Pike,
probably about two,
two and a half miles from the Pentagon.
And we were sitting in our living room having coffee,
and it sounded like a military jet flyover that they do sometimes,
you know,
a very,
very low altitude flyover.
And then, just a couple of seconds later, we heard a massive,
massive boom.
All of our doors and windows shook.
We went outside,
looked out the window,
and then saw a plume of smoke.
All right,
Daniel,
thank you very much.
We are now getting more information about what may have happened,
may have led up to these incidents,
these attacks.
General Richard Myers,
who's the vice chairman of the U.S.
Joint Chiefs of Staff,
has been reported by one of the news agencies,
Associated Press,
as saying that. One hijacked plane was seen,
was known about by officials heading from the New York area to Washington.
Of course,
they wouldn't have had time if that was the aircraft that hit close to the Pentagon.
They obviously didn't have time to give out an alert.
The other two aircraft,
it's possible we have one unnamed U.S. official saying that one was hijacked after takeoff from Boston, and a third was hijacked from
Newark, New Jersey.
I don't want to.
Can you take the stairs before I get up there?
You can take the stairs down here.
All right.
I got this.
Go slow.
The dust is.
Just tell him to go slow.
I want to work right now on the climate.
I'm going back to the field.
All right.
You're going to stay with him?
Work with him.
Stay with me.
Okay,
I'll come back.
Let's go back to Dave Stapp.
Dave,
what do you have?
I know.
Stat,
hey,
they're evacuating us now.
They believe another plane.
This could be a rumor,
but they're evacuating everybody.
Possibility of another plane coming in this direction.
Certainly,
but this is a major evacuation at the moment.
Again,
it could all be a rumor,
but FBI is evacuating everybody out of this area.
These are earlier pictures you can see.
This,
by the way,
is a portion of the Pentagon that had basically been reopened.
There's been a major renovation underway for the last several years.
Ironically,
had this incident happened even as recently as...
Two weeks ago,
that portion of the building where there was an explosion inside the Pentagon basically would have had very few civilian or military personnel at their desk and on duty today.
No,
I can't imagine how I would make it.
To Manhattan today,
but I have to tell you,
you know,
on one island,
it's so far removed,
It's a peaceful,
sunny day,
and yet people are absolutely gripped by this.
I just came over the Atlantic Beach Bridge,
which is right on the Neff Hotel.
But we did hear a sound.
We heard something that sounded like a loud boom about five minutes ago.
And Kate,
you were...
I'm sorry,
could you just let me go?
We're on a street.
Just keep going.
Leave your phone.
Thank you very much.
You too,
please.
We had a report of a fireman trapped over here on the...
Northwest corner. So, uh, we'll make sure that, uh, we got people over to help dig him out. Now. Did you get the report that somebody said the last plane crashed the base of the building? There was a third plane that actually set off that second explosion that caused what we thought was an implosion. At first, it was
maybe one second.
No work?
Oh,
the Northwest Tower is
we gotta be over here or over this way.
I'm gonna head out and move out to the other end.
Alright.
It's difficult to tell how you even respond to something like this.
What do you do?
It's gonna be massive.
A tower.
What floor were you on?
B1.
What floor?
First one.
What happened?
Tell me.
A big explosion happened.
Some guy came out.
His skin was all off.
I helped him out.
This is him all over.
There's people jumping out of windows.
I seen at least four people.
14 people jumping out of windows.
It's horrific.
I can't believe this is happening.
Anything else that you saw?
Were you there for the second hit by the plane?
Yeah,
About 10 minutes later,
the second building went off.
Did you see it?
Yes,
I saw it.
It just blew up.
Up a big explosion, people started running. It was just chaos everywhere, people jumping out. People just kept jumping and jumping and jumping. And you could still see they were alive because they were flailing around. The FBI has already stepped in to investigate. It could be possibly a terrorist strike. Great could be. It could, because it was the first one went off and then ten minutes later, this just blew up out of nowhere. Or to think that that would just be accidental? No, I don't think it would be accidental. Back it up,
folks.
Back it up.
Kenny,
Jahanami.
J-O-H-A-N-N.
E-M-A-N-N.
Eyewitnesses telling what he saw a huge...
.Washington. Bridge.
If you are a New York City firefighter,
you are requested to report to your station immediately.
We need all possible help at this time.
You're listening to 1010 Winds,
continuing live coverage.
Tommy,
see him over there?
What did you see?
Well,
I just saw it actually when it just blew up.
It was a big explosion and just fell down pretty much.
Did it fall forward, or fall together, or fall in pieces?
No,
fall in pieces,
just like that.
On the left side,
you see,
over there at the tower?
On that side,
actually,
it falls,
just like that.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
What's your name?
Alex.
Alex,
right.
All of a sudden we saw the other explosion.
I saw a couple of people jumping out of the other building.
I seen two or three people jump out of the building.
The first,
I don't know if that's the number one tower or number two tower.
It's unreal.
The second tower is gonna go.
But the plane's inside there.
I see the plane there.
Right there.
I mean,
we were about a block away and all of a sudden,
everyone just started running all over the place.
And the building fell, and it's such a smoke just engulfed the whole area.
It was absolutely unbelievable.
Pretty terrifying.
That's all the brilliant that I have to say.
We're out of here.
Hello.
Give me a shot over here so we can see if this building's listing.
They're clearly being sent as far away as possible.
.scenes. Of fear and pandemonium in New York.
As you can see,
the twin Towers,
one is already down,
the other is billowing with smoke.
The fire is still out of control.
We're going to go back now to Audrey Barnes,
who has another eyewitness to the Pentagon attack.
Audrey.
Michael,
I have a witness who was...
Inside the building when the Pentagon died.
Tell me what your name is,
sir,
and where were you when this happened?
My name is Lieutenant Colonel Battle,
Terry Battle.
I was in a meeting inside the Pentagon when we heard a loud boom.
It was basically all you could say.
Were in the middle of a briefing,
loud noise went off,
everybody started clearing out of the building.
What at that point,
what did you think had happened, or what have you heard happen?
I'm not really sure.
We've been through these kind of drills before on evacuation of the building, so initially just thought it was an evacuation. But then once we got outside, clearly, as you can see the black smoke rising, we recognized that it was something very serious.
That first tower came down.
Quick!
Okay,
when he said,
okay,
take it for me from the beginning,
Kathleen,
what did you see?
What did you hear?
I heard a plane low and I looked out the window and then I saw something. Push bill.
Building in. And then I saw the tail, and then
I saw flames engulf the whole upper portion, and then I saw the smoke and the whole trailer rocked.
The trailer was almost lifted off the ground.
And then I just started screaming because I could feel,
I could feel what was going on with the people.
What could you feel?
No pain.
The Command post,
from Humble Command Center to Manhattan,
K.
Hi,
Humble Command Center,
Manhattan,
can you contact Hillcum?
Humble Command Center,
at this time, we are unable to make contact,
K.
Alright,
10-4,
Manhattan,
I'll get back to you.
Alright,
10-4.
The people should be as close as this is perhaps rather worrying.
It happened off Russia,
and you can see that the police are trying to...
Clear the streets and get people as far away from the building as possible.
Perhaps they're worried that the second twin tower might collapse.
We saw the first come down with a terrible bang.
I can see the fire still raging.
.of. This disaster that's unfolding this morning in New York City.
Let's go to 1010 Winds reporter Lori Madden with an update on the New York City tunnels.
Lori?
We just got an update from Shadow Traficly that all of the tunnels into and out of the city,
we know about the port Authority.
Tunnels, but on the East River as well closed, that would be the Battery Tunnel, the Midtown tunnel. We would assume those would be shut down. We've got the confirmation they are shut down. All of the bridges, the East River Bridge is also coming into the city.
There were two planes.
How does all of you know?
We were here by the 25th,
124th Street.
That's where we were.
Across the street?
We were just green flying.
So we had to get a look at that.
Thank you.
Alright,
engine 228X,
is it possible you can get over to the
Two World Trade Center.
Firefighter trapped.
I don't think we can proceed with the raid.
We'll go as far as we can.
Marriott World Trade Center.
Where are they trapped,
K?
What do you call the urgent?
Supported to be in a fell area.
Unicorn urgent.
We're in that two world trade center.
We have some of the individuals in the front.
We're waiting to evacuate them,
K.
10-4,
also be advised,
in a fell area at the Marriott Hotel.
Receiving reports of firefighters trapped and down.
Yeah,
I'll go back.
What
are you looking at?
10-4. I think it was my family to make sure they knew I was okay because they know that I work here.
It just tore me up, like it tore up the building.
And I just can't believe anyone could do that,
regardless of what your political views are.
Is closed down.
Let's go back to Lauren Ashburn,
who's in the USA today. Building in Roslyn.
Lauren?
Yes,
good morning,
Buck and Andrea.
I am taking a look right now at the Pentagon.
There are one,
two,
three,
four helicopters I can see from the vista here.
The USA Today Tower 1 building that overlooks all of Washington from Arlington,
Virginia.
I can see one helicopter is on its way,
it looks like to me,
to the Washington Hospital Center.
It's attempting a landing right now.
I'm sure.
Sure, there are two others following in that direction at this point.
I'm looking down at traffic.
Traffic is at a standstill leaving the city.
Can I ask you a real quick question?
Just what are they telling you?
Like, what are you supposed to do?
What's the plan?
What's that?
I mean, just not even in terms of what happened, but I'm just trying to figure out what they're talking about.
I'm standing outside St.
Vincent's hospital right now, where the scene is absolutely unbelievable.
When I arrived here,
it was just as the second building explosion happened.
And there is what I could describe as chaos in the streets here.
There are hundreds of people just in shock,
police officers telling people to go home,
obviously worried about crowd control.
But at the hospital,
there has not been much activity in terms of ambulances arriving here,
though you might expect there would.
Be after that last explosion, some hospital, some ambulances took off and headed down
Seventh Avenue, which is otherwise closed to traffic, but st.
Vincent is obviously preparing for the possibility of many, many people arriving at their emergency room. They have what looks like a trauma center set up on the street, on the sidewalk of Seventh Avenue.
Well,
Erin,
I'm in our bureau,
but I have on the telephone with me
Barbara, who is the wife of a friend of mine. And who is an eyewitness to exactly what happened at the Pentagon.
Barbara,
can you hear me all, right?
Yes,
I can hear you.
Well,
what exactly did you see?
Let's look at the Pentagon now, as you describe what exactly happened at the Pentagon this morning.
As we were driving into town on 395,
there was an exit.
We were trying to get off the exit for the Memorial Bridge.
Off to the left-hand side was a commercial plane that came in and was coming too fast and too low.
And the next thing we saw was it go down below the side of the road,
and we just saw the fire.
That came up after that.
How large was the explosion?
It was large.
Was there sound as well?
That I can't verify because windows were up in the vehicle.
Was it clear to you what had happened?
Yes,
definitely.
So you believe it was a commercial airliner that was hitting the Pentagon?
Yes,
and I'm not sure exactly where the Pentagon was in relationship to where the plane went down.
But they are relatively close to one another.
Whether it hit any part of that Pentagon,
I'm not sure.
How low was the plane?
When it was coming down?
Yeah.
It was coming down on less than a
45-degree angle and coming down to the side of the 395.
And when it came down,
it just missed the 395 and went down below it,
and then you saw the fire come up from it.
Were you able to see what kind of plane or what airline it belonged to?
No,
I did not see what kind of an airline.
I just assumed because we were so close to the airport, it was coming into land.
But it seemed awfully low to you?
Yes,
and fast.
How big was the fireball?
I was spatially challenged at times and it was pretty big.
What did you think was happening?
I know that that hit the ground and exploded.
Were you frightened yourself?
Yes,
yes,
everybody stopped the cars and we all got out of it and so forth.
Right,
well,
thank you very much.
Thank you.
Appreciate your talking to us.
Erin,
back to you.
David,
Thank you.
What we're looking at,
spin around,
we can see the picture from,
this is from where we're standing.
We're a good 20 blocks or more from the World Trade Center as we're standing here.
And you can see the flames,
you see where the hole is.
And you can see how the hole,
the original hole is,
which is in the middle of the building.
And if you look at it,
you can see how the hole has grown.
Also, the flames below,
maybe 10 floors below now,
those flames have spread from the original fire.
We've seen with binoculars,
there have been people out here with binoculars.
They've seen people in the buildings.
There are still people in that tower.
Screaming through the air.
Anybody could do that to innocent people.
I remember looking at the clock that it was 9 o'clock.
And I said,
here's people sitting at their desks with families.
And then they weren't anymore.
Then there was a second plane.
Then I was on the phone with my mother,
looking out my window in my office,
and she said,
Oh my god,
Another plane hit,
and then I saw the burst of flames,
and the smoke,
and I just started screaming.
Because then I felt it all over again.
I just felt it all over again.
Um,
John,
before I come back to you,
Dennis Cross is on the phone.
Dennis,
do you hear me?
Dennis Cross,
Do you hear me?
Yes,
I can,
Peter.
Dennis,
I understand that you were in the World Trade Center when either this or these attacks occurred.
Am I correct?
Yeah,
that's correct.
It was,
uh,
I guess it was slightly before 9 o'clock,
and,
uh,
I work on the 36th floor in one World Trade Center.
I work for in the insurance industry,
probably hundreds of people in my industry in both of these two buildings.
And what happened?
As I was...
Dennis,
just let me stop for a second.
Somebody is trying another telephone on this line.
Could they please not do that while we listen to Mr.
Cross?
Thanks.
Go ahead,
Mr.
Cross.
Go ahead,
Dennis.
Essentially,
I was at my desk working,
general office activity,
and felt an enormous...
It almost felt like an earthquake.
I could literally feel and see things in the office moving and the floor moving.
Immediately after it was some sort of explosion or something,
there was an enormous volume of debris and paper.
It almost looked like a dirty parade.
All of this material just falling down.
I was looking out the south side of the
One World Trade, and everybody in the office was kind of screaming,
kind of gathering in the middle. And I went to the window and
I immediately saw one woman, who appeared to be a woman.
Appeared to be motionless,
laying on the roof of a lower building next to me.
At that point,
everybody started to gather their things.
They were trying to evacuate people down the stairwell.
Did the electricity go out in the building?
The tower was a little bit closer to the TOWER.
I thought it was a TOWER.
The lights flickered a couple of times and then it was WEIRD.
It was kind of like there was
one sort of rush,
and then
surely after that there was another ONE.
I don't know if it was
maybe the other tower, or if there were
elevators in the inside of IT,
you KNOW,
sort of just dropping to the FLOOR.
Are you aware that
one of the twin tray towers has now collapsed on ITSELF?
Looked at it on the screen.
Screen here, Dennis. We could see the smoke from this collapse. Just sweep the billow forward through the lower blocks of Manhattan. Did you have a sense of that completely? I was at that point. I'm a little bit northwest, it's certainly north, maybe to the west side of
Tower one, and I was trying to get to Broadway. My wife works on the other side of downtown, here, I'm still trying to get there. But the smoke literally
I couldn't see. It was a wall of smoke and if you were in it, you couldn't see. If you were
were out of it, you could just see the wall of smoke.
I'm sorry for interrupting.
How difficult was the evacuation?
I'm sorry, say that again, Peter?
How difficult was was it to evacuate the building from? At least from the 30,
there were 110 stories in the building.
I would say that it wasn't. It wasn't extremely difficult, it was just slow going down a somewhat narrow stairwell.
If there was any sort of, you know, people who weren't able to move quickly, then it literally please slow down or.
Stopped everybody.
I was on 36, so it wasn't too terrible when I got down to, you know, the 15th or 12th floor or so.
There was water coming in from the doors, you know, kind of at our feet level, and then it just was a waterfall. Down all of it, continually down all of the stairs. Probably, you know, in some cases, three, four inches deep.
It's up, sirens and alarms are going off, and then people started to get a little frantic there.
Dennis, Thank you very much.
Okay.
I, I really appreciate you calling in.
Dr.
Krause,
who works...
I
was in the first building that was hit.
It seemed like a plane hit.
We thought it was an earthquake.
We were on the 10th floor.
The whole thing was shaking,
swaying, like you wouldn't believe.
Then we all went into the hallways.
We ran down the stairs.
A lot of people fell,
were getting hurt.
Then when we got out.
Outside the building,
the second plane went crashing into the other building.
And then the whole top of the building just collapsed. now,
that's what I'm hearing.
Unbelievable.
Tony Ciarnella.
C-I-A-R-N-E-L-L-A.
How do you do that,
though?
I work for Bank of America.
Can you tell us exactly how you do it?
That's a good question.
I really don't know.
Too far ahead.
I know we have a contingency site.
We're probably going to end up there.
What do you think is the reason you guys are doing this?
I think that there's some really crazy...
People in this world.
This is just not,
too many innocent people.
People are jumping off the building,
body parts all over the place.
I mean,
this is just,
I feel like I was in a movie.
And
I'm just so happy I'm alive and I wish my wife could hear me because I know she's trying to page me.
I'm alright,
I'm a little hurt,
but I'm okay.
Now, Andrea,
I can see the sky.
I know you had talked about possibly another plane from somewhere coming.
I have a vista almost 180 degrees here across the horizon and I can see not one single solitary plane.
The only thing I can see are those helicopters I talked to you about.
The one helicopter has landed,
it looks like, to me,
at Washington Hospital Center.
I'll drop you off on the subway.
Yeah,
you can go.
to 10 Duralama Street,
take the train right there.
Uh,
you mean,
or are you gonna pass,
uh,
like,
Bam?
Oh,
man,
that fight's getting worse.
This building's gonna burn down,
because I-I got a bit afraid to,
uh,
get near it,
and not expose you,
you know?
I want a military package,
photos,
no VO.
Oh,
by the way,
camera's in front of me.
Explosion there as well.
And Michael,
I've been told by our guest here,
Michael Hirschman,
who's the president of an international security and counterterrorism firm,
that there's an unidentified aircraft approaching an airport in northern Virginia,
possibly Dulles or Washington National Airport.
Authorities there are scrambling to find out about that aircraft,
an unidentified aircraft circling,
approaching an airport in northern Virginia.
We're not sure which airport that is.
You have Dulles there,
you have Reagan International,
and
George, actually, those are the two airports there,
scrambling to find out the nature of that aircraft.
I was standing in the corner of Park Row and I believe it was Fulton Street when we heard this massive explosion. And the top of number two World Trade Center came down.
I'm not entirely sure what happened.
Are you serious?
Are these cameras right now?
They're aware I'm just notifying the rest of the department.
We don't know where it's going.
Say it,
I've got something to say.
We're back to the islands,
man.
The impact was unbelievable and the flames and the smoke lapsed. And as we warned you, the whole business of responsibility, claiming of and naming responsibility would be complicated. And now we've from from the middle,
Middle East,
A senior official from the Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine has denied any involvement,
any connection to a double plane crash on the World Trade Center.
It was in fact, earlier on an anonymous caller who...
Had called Abu Dhabi television to say that the DFLP was responsible.
So for today, we'll put aside as best we can the,
I'm trying to understand who did it, just knowing somebody who did it.
In the United States, you can see just how upset and shocked people are.
It happened at one of the busiest times.
And then we saw smoke coming out and everybody started running out and we saw the plane on the other side of the building.
And there was smoke everywhere and people are jumping out the windows.
Over there,
they're jumping out the windows,
I guess,
because they're trying to save themselves.
I don't know.
And
Everybody just doesn't know where to go.
They won't let,
everything is blocked off.
You can't even,
they're telling us to get out,
but there's nowhere to go.
And then I heard that another plane hit.
And if you go over by there,
you can see the people jumping out the window.
They're jumping out the window right now.
Oh,
my God.
All right,
ma'am,
thank you.
And let's go.
What part of the plane you saw?
The tail.
I saw a silver flash and the flames, and I saw a pointy tail.
That's how I knew it was a plane.
We have on the phone now Daryl Jenkins.
Mr.
Jenkins,
you're an airline security expert, with what organization?
Washington University Aviation Institute.
All right,
sir.
You've seen what's happened this morning.
Give me your read.
Well,
our lives will never be the same again.
This will change everything we do in this city and everywhere else around here.
This is the day that we will all remember until we die now.
Hello,
BPM.
B-B-N,
yeah?
B-i-b-i-a-n
a-y-o-n-o-t-e ayanote,
ayanote,
B-B-N, ayanote.
Like, um,
I was just sitting down and they told me that
a plane crashed into Waterloo Centre, and I was like,
how is that possible?
Then we went to look,
because I work in Goldman Sachs and overlooking Waterloo Centre,
we went to the other conference room. And as we were looking,
the other plane,
the second plane just flew into the building!
Right,
and then you just saw the whole thing just exploding.
The top one regard of the trade center was just inflamed,
because I was right over there.
And then bodies started just falling out of the building over there.
And then on the ground,
people started to panic and trample other people.
There was blood on the road out there because people got hurt,
people got trampled.
It's a nightmare.
It's really a nightmare.
Thank you.
I'm not going to be able to
rose Harris.
Rose Harris.
At Goldman Sachs.
New York Plaza.
So it's taken a long walk.
And as we were leaving,
there was another explosion down there.
That's when we saw it.
Wow!
And as we were leaving,
there was another explosion down there.
That's when we saw it.
She said an announcement was made, stopping many trains from going into Manhattan.
And no one was going to work today.
Okay.
10-10 wins in
Brooklyn. Well,
actually,
WCVS,
no,
get a fed from WCVs over there.
Okay.
Okay?
Yep.
Bo White.
Where you at?
I was on the 81st floor.
Tell me what you saw in her.
It was just,
I had 40 people in there.
Just explosion.
There's a light flash out my window.
My whole doorway to the entrance of my office blew open.
My office was freaking out.
And I just told them to calm down and get to the center of the office.
Everybody was fine on my floor and we just started heading down the stairs.
I heard people were trapped in the bathroom.
I ran to the bathroom.
It was just blown out.
I asked if anybody was in there.
People weren't in there.
So I started going down.
I heard people shouting.
I stopped at like 68 and there was a woman in a wheelchair.
And
I got her in the strapped wheelchair and just carried her down the steps and carried her down 68th floor.
And then we got lost on the fifth floor.
It was chaos.
What do you work for?
Network Plus Communications Company out of Randolph,
Massachusetts.
Steve,
I can tell you anybody's calling.
Mike,
Benfonte,
B-E-N-F-A-N-T-E.
Thank you,
Mike.
It was chaos,
man.
But here you see an enormous explosion about midway up in the South Tower, and the entire structure collapses.
It just disappears.
CNN's David Ensor in Washington.
CNN's Brian Palmer joins us on the phone from here in Manhattan.
Brian,
why don't you begin by telling me where you are?
We are in front of the criminal courthouse after being pushed north slightly.
We watched one of the towns...
Of the World Trade Center, disappear from the skyline.
It basically folded into itself in a plume of gray smoke.
A crowd of thousands of people dashed up Broadway,
followed by emergency services personnel.
Hey,
watch your back.
She was flying low,
I asked my little buddy,
I said,
What'd you think?
You know what it did?
It came from over the bay.
And I asked my buddy,
what's happening?
I explained, flying so low.
He tilted his wing like that and right into the bay.
I said,
I need the bay.
I seen it.
I have a.
The
Pentagon. You can see the billowing up from the building, huge clouds of smoke.
Take zoom.
Oh, shit!
It's gonna go.
It's leaning and buckled.
Leaning and buckled?
Yep.
Watch out.
Hi,
my name is Greg Cherry, and yes,
okay,
I work on the 20th floor in the World Trade Center.
I'm just traumatized right now.
World Trade One.
And
I was working at my desk on the 20th floor. And all of a sudden the impact,
I thought it was a bomb,
just lifted everybody off our seats and it was screaming.
But
I was proud of my co-workers, everybody was calm. We took the stairways, there was a little panic, We took the stairways with them. When we got to the bottom. The elevators, they were, they all cracked, they were coming down, more debris was coming down. Yes,
no, that they popped the cable, popped the elevator. It just cramp tumbling down. So when we got to the exit, another plane
came in and more degree, they wouldn't let us out the building. I thought that was it. But um, I just want to let you know my wife Barbara, I'm safe and my mother.
I'm just happy I got out and hope my coworkers and everyone are safe.
9-David,
go ahead.
As soon as you get...
Are you at the scene?
They have us right now down opposite the downtown Athletic Club on West Street.
Get me a status report on Car 9 and all the other units that were in that area.
And get them back to me on the telephone,
please.
10-4-9,
David.
As soon as possible.
10-4-9.
Peter,
big concern now from the scene that the Northwest Tower,
the one remaining standing,
is leaning and buckling in the northwest corner.
They're moving back the mobilization areas and they're cordoning off the area in a much wider zone now. Because obviously they are now concerned about the possibility of a second collapse.
Members of the uniformed division of the Secret Service ran out to intersections and started diverting traffic.
There are emergencies.
On almost
every block around the White House.
It seems that a large aircraft is being described as an airliner.
.crashed? Into just near the Pentagon,
near the west side of the Pentagon,
around near a helicopter launch pad,
or on a helicopter launch pad.
Well,
Andrea,
it is,
I hate to use the cliche,
but it is truly a scene out of a movie here.
The dark,
acrid smoke wafting over from the Pentagon has shrouded the terminal area here at National Airport lightly.
Not a dense fog here at the AIRPORT,
but a late fog, NONETHELESS.
You're hearing some sirens behind ME.
Those are some additional police vehicles heading down 7th Avenue right NOW.
MELISSA,
if I can interrupt you for a SECOND.
There's an urgent on the wire that something has happened at the State DEPARTMENT.
A source SAYS,
We don't know YET,
we hear it might have been a PLANE.
And so there's a possibility now.
That a plane may have slammed into the State Department in the nation's capital.
That,
of course.
Come on,
girl,
I got you.
Now,
that's interesting from a forensic point of view.
The explosion that leveled the South Tower came,
it seemed,
roughly halfway up,
and yet it took the entire tower out.
I'm still desperately confused,
John,
about what may have caused the building to collapse.
As you watch the videotape,
it appeared to buckle from the middle,
from the point of impact and collapse,
which,
you know,
with no background in architecture,
I don't know about the structural vulnerability,
But as you see,
debris starts to fall,
then it cracks,
and then it just goes straight down.
And now they say that the other tower is leaning.
If you look at some of the pictures,
it appears to be on a slight angle to the right.
News with Judy DeAngelis.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you,
James.
We are just getting word now that...
Good luck.
.The. Airspace lock from below ground is also being closed.
You were in that area today.
Yes, I was.
I was on 299 Broadway when I felt a huge vibration.
I thought it was an earthquake,
didn't know what it was.
People were running across the street barefooted,
some crying on the floor,
almost like a stampede was occurring.
Everybody just ran.
This is where I'm at now.
I don't know how many blocks I ran.
I almost caught asthma by the time I stopped.
I lost my cell phone.
I can't even call my family right now.
That's it.
My past came before me,
but
I thought maybe this was some type of earthquake.
I ran to the window like some fool, to see if it was an earthquake.
I didn't see other buildings tumbling,
so the first thing that came to my mind was that it was a bomb.
So,
um,
no,
I was still inside when we got to the bottom.
We were ready to leave the building.
They told us not to get.
That's when the other plane hit and everything was falling.
They told us to stay inside the building and it was just chaos.
I saw bodies flying everywhere.
It was something I never experienced.
I'm getting bumped off because they're doing live shots.
So JFK shut down medical supplies into LaGuardia.
146 10-4,
10-5.
At this time, reporting a floor collapse on the 22nd floor.
We're going to have a one-on-one response into the box at this time.
146,
acting 10-4.
9 and ladder 5-6,
K.
Ladder 5-6.
Check the A's,
we can check out the A's.
They can send it not too far away from here.
Did you want a car 3?
This one, now or not?
Number three,
hey,
man.
Stuyvesant went to the bank that day.
I asked you about the number 14 of mine.
If the building could collapse,
it's gonna fall on top of Stuyvesant High School,
okay?
I have to tell them to get out.
Did you hear that?
Yeah,
tell them to get out,
it's gonna fall.
They said if the building collapses,
it will fall on Stuyvesant High School.
Really,
he was right.
New York City,
this is the city,
right,
go.
Fallen Stuyvesant High School,
because it's failing the South.
I'm
18, 18,
5-0 here.
Okay.
ABC's John McQuethy now confirms for us,
we've had from an eyewitness,
or he adds to our eyewitness,
saying that. A small plane heading north,
which is exactly what our eyewitness a little earlier told us,
exploded at the base of the Pentagon,
at the base of one wing of the Pentagon.
They evacuated everyone inside.
My name is Rich.
I was working at the Ritz, Carlton,
Villava,
Spell it,
V-I-L-L-A-L-V-A.
And you work at the Ritz Carlton?
We were doing construction at the Ritz Carlton and it came on the Bay side,
came right past our window.
And the plane started angling like this.
Was it a big plane?
From what I saw,
it was so fast,
went by so fast,
it looked like a commercial,
like a United,
I think,
plane.
And he angled like he was going to take out more floors,
it looked like,
you know.
And it just hit,
and we evacuated the building.
I don't even know where we're walking to now.
Get the heck out.
Yeah.
You don't think I could walk to Jersey,
do you?
No.
But the mass transit will start working as soon as you get out of here.
There might be mass transit available,
port Authority,
that kind of thing?
Okay.
But you're all right.
And you saw what happened?
I don't know.
So what happened?
God.
I'm going to have to go check her out.
Everybody out of this way.
Let's go.
Everybody in the back.
Get all the tickets out of the way from the building.
What's the matter?
Let's go.
We're good.
Watch this.
Go.
That time, I learned my lesson.
Me too.
Sadly,
I heard Howard stirring on the radio,
and I was thinking about him joking there when I passed somebody's car.
What?
When I passed somebody's car and I heard Howard stirring on the radio,
I was just having a laugh fest.
That this happened?
Yeah.
No worries.
There's no confirmation that she was there,
but it's a mystery.
Statter?
Yeah,
I'm here.
You hear anything about the State Department?
No,
I know there was concern here.
Let me describe what happened when we had to rush off a little while ago.
Yes.
There was concern,
and we don't like to put rumors on the air,
and I'm not sure that you can call this a rumor,
but FBI...
On the scene at the Pentagon,
told everybody to leave the area because there was concern of a hijacked plane that might be coming in this direction.
Hold on.
Hey,
Dave?
Yes?
We just got this bulletin from the Associated Press.
A car bomb explodes outside the State Department.
Being attributed to senior law enforcement officials,
again,
a car bomb has just exploded.
Let's go to
Frank Herzog,
who is outside the State Department.
Frank,
what have you seen?
Talk to someone who is in the building,
had just gone into one of the world's...
Trade towers. When it all happened, he said from where he was in the lobby, there was a flush of debris and a flush of fire down one of the elevator shafts. He actually was singed, and he was in the lobby. This gentleman here,
three planes.
What do you want?
Two aircrafts at one time.
There was concern that another plane might be inbound towards the Pentagon.
And by grounding everything,
of course,
by ordering everything to be grounded on all radio channels to all aircraft that are flying in the area.
I'd rather not have a bad day.
Thank you.
Do you know where everybody's going?
No,
I don't.
We don't know.
Thank you.
We may never know the answer to this question,
but again,
you know,
you have to wonder,
a jetliner captain, with a gun to his head,
told to crash into a building,
what would he probably do?
I would imagine he would probably say no.
So we have to wonder who flew the planes.
They just
come out walking.
Do you know the people are falling out the other side?
Shit.
I'll go closer and then up.
Okay,
good,
thanks.
I'm thinking, you're gonna have a,
uh...
Explosion on Capitol Hill,
possible bomb at the State Department.
Department, D.C.
Chopper 4,
Local desk.
Out of Boston, bound for L.A.,
Crashed into the world.
You see the picture right there.
That's the second explosion when this American Airlines jet, apparently hijacked,
plowed into the World Trade Center.
Then, about an hour ago,
there was an explosion at the Pentagon.
A plane plowed into the Pentagon near the heliport.
Look at this.
And one of the towers we have reported that one had collapsed. Here is proof that...
Frank Herzog,
where are you?
I don't know what you gotta do,
but I want all the rescue firefighters available from home to report,
10-4,
we have been broadcasting that,
K.
Any order of help we can get?
10-4,
We have multiple units on the way in now.
4.
People are jumping.
Let's go to Walter Perez.
Walter is downtown in Lower Manhattan.
Okay,
now, as you can imagine,
Ralph,
as you can imagine,
it is a pretty frenzied scene out here.
Just a few moments ago,
I'd say about 20 minutes ago,
we're not sure exactly what it was.
We have not confirmed it.
Something either exploded or fell off the side of the one building that was attacked and caused a massive plume of SMOKE.
As we turn LEFT,
you can see as the trucks go by that they are spitting off SMOKE.
These were the emergency trucks and ambulances that were near the building at the time that that had happened.
At that POINT,
it wasn't so much of a frenzied scenario because people were walking away from the BUILDING.
This entire region has been cordoned OFF,
and people who were working in nearby buildings were told to leave and evacuate the area. For obvious REASONS,
for safety CONCERNS.
When that second plume of smoke came up from the ground AREA,
people started RUNNING.
People were covered in SOOT.
There were people with blood on their SHIRTS,
ripps in their SHIRTS.
And at this point,
looking up at the top of the building,
at a rate of about one every five minutes,
you see people that are jumping from the top.
Of the building.
I was on Liberty Street.
It's terrible.
Oh my God.
Were you in the building originally?
No.
So I was on the way to work and the dust come down and cover us.
We had to feel our way out from the dust.
It's just bad.
All I need now is to get to Brooklyn.
Home.
Home is Brooklyn.
Yeah.
Why are you running?
You know why?
Why?
Where are you coming from?
I was in the Century 21 building.
So you were downtown, too?
Right.
Our office points right at the buildings.
And we're so accustomed to seeing people of all walks of life down in the lobby and everything,
and every day,
and then all of a sudden, this happens at 9 in the morning.
And fire came out from all sides of the building.
And to us,
we thought bombs went off or something,
but apparently planes went.
But it's a sad,
very sad time for America.
What we're going to do is we're going to...
Why don't you go out without lenses?
Lesh,
Charlie,
do you know how to get voicemail on these things?
No.
I'm going to go back and see if we can put it at the barrier.
Hello.
We had a big tragedy and this guy, what happened? And he said he's not gonna tell anybody.
It's a cow.
We're gonna,
to this scale,
you know,
find out who did this.
Hey guys,
excuse me.
The president of the United
States, Donald
Trump, has been in the White House for a long time.
He,
nothing has happened there now.
It looks all quiet.
But I am getting reports from Park police that another plane was hijacked out of Pittsburgh.
That's the word they're getting.
Another plane was hijacked out of Pittsburgh.
As we gather more information and we're sure we're settled where we're supposed to stop,
we'll get back to you. Because at this point, police are still not sure where we should be.
And as you can see,
a lot of police activity.
They're trying to move the media to a safe area so we can do proper reporting and let everybody know exactly what's going on.
For now,
back to you.
We'll throw you back to the studio now.
We won't speculate on that,
but Lisa Stark,
who covers aviation for us,
confirms that it was American Flight 11 to Los Angeles.
There were 90 passengers and crew on board,
and there was a second plane.
Help me understand this,
not...
This was just a few minutes after there'd been another explosion near the top of the North Tower.
Eyewitnesses said this tower appeared to be struck by a plane that came in low and then hit the building at a slight angle.
Again,
within seconds,
the upper floors were consumed by flames and smoke.
Is this a visit tower?
Corporation.
I don't think it has one.
Call 1 on the air,
Call 1.
I mean, the whole thing,
you know,
like,
you can see individual windows.
Call 1,
state of mind.
The whole thing is just...
No,
it's outside.
It's outside.
What happened?
A car bomb exploded.
Where's that tape?
The tape we shot.
Pop it out.
We'll feed it.
Stay on the tight shot.
Okay,
just give me the tape and we'll feed it.
Yeah,
yeah.
Thank you.
Coming in to the Pentagon this morning,
identify yourself and tell us what you saw.
My name is Ed Hudson.
I was coming to work at the Navy Annex.
I was passing by Fort Myer and I saw...
I saw a large airliner-sized plane,
roughly a
767-sized airliner,
very deep descent,
approaching the Pentagon.
I didn't actually see the impact,
but I did hear the blast and saw the smoke rising from the crash later.
And if you go over by that,
you can see the people jumping out the window.
They're jumping out the window right now.
I tell nothing.
Are you here on backup?
I'm here on backup.
Are all your guys okay?
We're trying to find them right now.
Trying to find out if emergency personnel are okay?
I'm with the fire marshals.
We're doing the fire investigations.
We're just trying to find out if they're okay.
Now they're okay?
I'm with the fire marshals.
We're doing the fire investigations.
Trying to get together.
Pretty crazy.
Right,
thanks.
And
CIA Director George Tenet has been holding meetings in his office in Langley,
Virginia.
And as we reported earlier,
key FBI team members from their rescue efforts and anti-terror coordinating team were stranded in Monterey,
California,
where they were on a secret military exercise against exactly this kind of event.
Andrew.
Thanks for the queue.
Got any water in here?
No.
Thanks,
hold on one second.
It's me,
front line,
leader, front line.
Is there any way you could put a phone, or is there any way we can get ISB into Pat's ear for a talk back and forth?
I beg your pardon.
The second plane was not hijacked from Boston,
but from
American, from Dulles Airport,
we're being told,
which, of course, is outside Washington.
And we do not know if that was the...
The State Department voted.
Yeah.
Russia voted.
And Capitol Hill.
The
Pentagon's been hit.
Capitol Hill.
Operation GO.
They say that,
uh...
CY,
attention to call one.
Call one.
Empty space.
Completely done.
Call one.
Where?
Is this in the World Trade Center?
Yeah.
Yeah,
we signed up.
Caller four,
then...
Call one,
I want him.
The phone from St.
Mary's Hospital in Hoboken,
New Jersey.
Doctor,
I know it's extremely busy.
What can you tell us about any casualties you're receiving there?
We're receiving some minor burns now.
We have three emergency rooms in our hospital system,
one here at St.
Mary's,
one at St.
Francis,
and one at Christ Hospital in Jersey City.
And we're open and functioning to receive any casualties that we may get.
Wait,
the other one.
We are continuous,
continually trying.
Okay,
that's great.
Also,
would you make everyone aware that we're going to be seeing some pain?
Holy shit.
Jesus!
Oh, no!
The second one,
the second one's gone.
It's going right now.
Oh my god!
It's falling.
It's gone.
The twin trade towers are fucking gone.
Oh my god!
Well, of course, there's fucking people in there.
We just,
we simply do not know who has been hurt and what casualties might have occurred,
which is the information that we are,
I want you to take a look at what's happening right now.
That is a live picture.
That's a live picture.
That's World Trade Center 2.
That's World Trade Center 2 has just collapsed.
That's the second of the towers to collapse.
We are now looking at the collapse of the second of the
World Trade Center towers.
Again,
this is something that we never dreamed we would witness in our lifetime.
Let us tell you that to come into this city right now,
you will not be able to.
The bridges,
the tunnels,
shut.
That is one of the witnesses to this extraordinary,
these extraordinary events this morning here in New York.
Again,
and I know that for many of you,
you've heard this a lot,
But I think it's important as people join us, as they do in moments like this.
They are coming in all the time that there have been attacks in two American cities,
New York and in Washington.
The trade centers here in New York.
New York have been hit by airplanes.
In Washington, there is a large fire at the Pentagon.
The Pentagon has been evacuated.
And there,
as you can see,
perhaps the second tower,
the front tower,
the top portion of which is collapsing.
Good Lord.
There are no words.
You can see large pieces of the building falling.
You can see the smoke rising.
You can see a portion of the side of the building now just being covered on the right side as I look at it,
covered in smoke.
This is just a horrific scene and a horrific moment.
Looks like there was never a building there.
When it went down,
I could see like it was paddled.
Yeah,
it seemed like it just sort of...
Oh my God!
There's a north cow coming through.
Go this way.
Coming up.
Small piece of the base is still not going down.
Look at the steel.
Oh my god.
You can hear it.
Ha!
Be advised the tower is down.
Be advised the North Tower is down.
All personnel be advised the North Tower is down.
Oh,
that's fine, too.
A lot of mercy.
Be advised the whole North Tower is down.
There it goes.
Oh my God!
Holy shit!
That smoke is bad.
Let's go.
Holy
shit!
God!
Ah!
Mother of God.
Carlo,
those people running on the left,
on the left,
where the smoke is.
I.
We have Swiss Re,
which is the second largest reinsurer in the world,
down 14%
right now.
Munich re down 9%
and Allianz down 8%.
We are also waiting for a statement out of the European Union.
We had been told that EU would be issuing a statement shortly,
and we will get back to you when we have that.
Back to you,
Mark.
We have an enormous explosion now in the remaining world trade Towers.
Center in the second.
I believe the North Tower is now gone as well.
Oh,
shoot!
Which way is the right?
The left side.
Oh,
it's collapsed!
it's gone!
I didn't see it.
It's scary.
Shit.
The sky is so...
It's so...
What is it?
Oh my god,
it's lying on the side.
Oh,
that's amazing.
Oh my god.
Give me the camera.
There
it goes,
it's going.
It's going down now,
it's going down now.
There it collapses.
Oh.
Boop!
It just collapsed.
Oh, those poor people.
Oh, god.
The second tower is gone.
You are directly across the river from
midtown Manhattan.
Have you ever, in your experience, gotten any of these types of casualties from New York?
What kind of emergency plan is in place that would include New Jersey hospitals?
I don't know what kind of emergency plan they have in place.
We have our external disaster plan in place.
We've sent triage teams to the Path Station
Hoboken terminal.
And as I said,
we have our three emergency rooms open and running.
Thank you.
Dr.
Angelo Caprio,
thank you very much.
You're quite welcome.
From around the New York City metropolitan region,
help is pouring in after the attack on the Twin Towers.
And we believe now the second tower of the World Trade Center,
that would be tower number two,
has collapsed.
This is a terrible,
terrible tragedy.
The first one collapsed just a short time ago.
This now appears to be...
The second of the twin towers,
having been struck,
each of them,
by a plane,
has collapsed.
Let's look.
There was another big,
big explosion in the other tower.
Flames coming out and this billowing gray smoke.
People still not panicking.
People not quite understanding what was going on.
Then somebody said that they saw an airliner.
Going to one of those towers.
Then,
I don't know,
an hour later than that,
we had that big explosion from much,
much lower.
I don't know what on earth caused that.
The thing that strikes me is,
one,
the terribleness of the incident.
Whatever the cause,
and we don't go into politics,
but whatever the cause,
the terribleness,
the hugeness of what's happened.
So huge,
in fact,
that most of the people around simply can't understand what happened.
People were just standing around,
talking to each other,
nodding their heads.
Not just in U.S. history,
but probably in modern times.
Unprecedented.
And every time you say that,
I'm going to go immediately to Washington,
but every time you say that,
I keep thinking of how. We are told time and time and time again by the Pentagon and by the State Department that they know something's going on in the world today.
Stand by.
They seem to have a problem at the North Tower,
Peter.
Let's look at the North Tower quickly.
The North Tower seems to be coming down.
Oh my God.
The second tower.
It's hard to put it into words, and maybe one doesn't need to.
Why are they pulling us out of here?
The North Tower is the heat of North Lake.
Again,
we are looking at two pictures.
The one on the left of your screen is the Pentagon,
where a section of that building has collapsed,
struck by an aircraft.
This is New York City,
where one of the...
Twin Towers collapsed after it was struck by aircraft one of the 110 story towers.
Emilio Delano He's a terrorism expert over at American University. Sir, are you with us here,
Emilio?
I think we just, I think we lost of the phones in this area, everybody's on his cell, trying to get out. This was live of the second tower, we believe the second tower
of the World Trade Center just collapsed.
That's what you were looking at live.
Thank you.
Oh my god.
Jimmy,
the second tower just went.
At this point,
quite certain, he pledges...
The government's full support, as would be obvious, victims and their families, as well as a full-scale investigation to hunt down those responsible. Let's go back to Cindy Shoe in the newsroom is joining us now with another update on the way that can be the best live picture, live picture. We're see
seeing the second
World Trade Center Tower number one, has just collapsed,
ladies and gentlemen.
You see it live in our picture.
One World Trade Center has just collapsed.
That means both World Trade Center buildings have collapsed.
The New York Stock Exchange.
Just a moment ago,
the entire top of the building collapsed.
You can see a massive plume of smoke.
People are running away from the area.
There are firefighters and there are police trying to evacuate the area as quickly as possible.
People who are near the area are in an absolute frenzied situation.
The entire top of the building just collapsed.
You can see the plume of smoke is coming in our direction.
Let's get out of here,
Ralph.
We're going to leave because the smoke is coming right at us.
Obviously, this is a devastating moment in our history.
They're gone.
The World Trade Center is no more.
We simply do not know who has been hurt and what casualties might have occurred,
which is the information that we are...
I want you to take a look at what's happening right now.
That is a live picture.
That's World Trade Center 2.
It's just collapsed.
That's the second tower to collapse.
We are now looking at the collapse of the second of the world.
Trade Sowers,
World Trade Center towers.
Yes, I am Michael.
We just saw that as well.
The second tower,
the only one that was standing,
tower number one.
Just we saw some kind of explosion,
a lot of smoke come out of the top of the tower.
This way, Pat.
You can see the chaos.
We can see the top of the building from here.
Oh yeah.
Oh, there it goes,
there it goes,
there it goes.
Oh,
when it comes downward.
Alright,
we do need to put it down now.
I think we need to put it down now.
Here we go.
Ten minutes or so,
they started a second evacuation of the Pentagon area.
We're told that there's another aircraft that's been hijacked,
and it's 20 minutes outside Washington,
D.C.
Emergency vehicle crews with bullhorns have been coming through this area,
telling everybody to get back.
Is that what your understanding is, as well?
Yes,
exactly.
Okay,
now what about employees?
Have you guys been given any information about what you should do?
They just told us to go home.
This is shocking and devastating for everybody.
It is.
I think it's time that the American public realize that...
We are vulnerable.
We're not in a situation such as World War II, where we had two oceans to protect us.
Thank you very much.
Mr.
Ed Hudson was an eyewitness to that plane coming in this morning.
He said...
A friend of mine works for the FBI.
He's,
you know,
out in the field.
He's an agent.
And he tells me all the time that he's on surveillance outside people's houses who are known terrorists or possible terrorists.
And they're constantly watching these people.
So so what I'm asking again is...
How did this slip by?
I mean, we can say, you know, 2020 hindsight, but this was obviously a synchronized, planned attack on two states.
But are they watching the people in this country or the people in other countries?
Oh, my goodness,
look at the screen.
Oh my god.
Oh.
Both towers down.
Oh my god.
10-4 on your urgent,
shut off.
289 asking.
Marine 3 to Manhattan,
K.
Connecting to Manhattan.
Urgent,
289 to Manhattan,
urgent.
The world's trade center's collapsed.
Building 2 has collapsed.
K.
Urgent,
urgent!
Unicorn urgent,
K-4.
Everybody get out,
we had a collapse of the second tower.
Everybody's running from the...
Hey,
here he comes,
get in,
hold on.
All right,
10-4.
Attention, all units,
we're receiving reports of number one and number two World Trade Center collapse.
All units at the scene,
receiving reports of number one and number two World Trade Center collapse.
Thank you.
Just come out of Tower One,
we're walking towards Broadway.
They're saying,
move along,
move along.
I looked up as soon as we got across the street.
I looked up,
I saw the building start,
the tower start to buckle.
I just turned and ran,
ducked down,
put a jacket over my head.
Three or four of us huddled together and...
And it was just black everywhere.
Were you covered?
Were you hit with debris?
No,
no,
no.
But I mean,
I was ducked behind a subway cover,
so I put the jacket over,
The three of us,
all of us huddled together.
There was dust and whatnot everywhere,
but it was...
We got knocked down.
The second building has just come down.
The second,
everyone is being asked to get down.
Come down.
The people are now panicking again.
The second tower has just fallen.
Apparently hit. And now. The Pentagon officials are evacuating everyone from the area there, according to The Associated Press, because they fear another plane could be en route to the Pentagon.
Senior law enforcement officials
say a car bomb has exploded outside the State Department.
That from the AP, we're just getting.
It was already among buildings here in the nation's capital that had been evacuated,
so people had been asked to leave.
They were leaving.
We have just heard that the second tower has collapsed in New York City.
The second World Trade Center tower has just collapsed in New York.
We're looking at a live picture.
Holy shit!
God!
.to. Be at risk,
So that's why so many precautions have been taken.
The planes are shut down nationwide by the FAA.
New Jersey State Police...
Oh,
two world Trade...
There it goes.
The other World Trade Center tower is collapsing.
Watch your screen there.
10-28 now.
The second
World Trade Center...
Oh,
that's...
.Two. World trade centers is disintegrating.
Now, the second tower has collapsed.
The first collapsing...
This is one world trade center now collapsing.
That's correct.
Two World Trade Center collapsed at about 9.55.
It's open.
It's not going out.
It's not going to everybody to go out.
One of the concerns,
of course,
was that the Emergency Command Center was at 7. World Trade Center,
which is across the street from
Tower 1. And what was Tower 2,
unfortunately,
and that the Port Authority was based at the World Trade Center.
It was Tower 2.
President Bush did comment earlier.
He called it an apparent terrorist attack,
but then updated that to...
Call it, seemingly, at this point, quite certainly, pledges the government's full support, as would be obvious for the victims and their families, as well as a full-scale investigation. To hunt down, uh, those who are down back to Cindy Shu in the newsroom, wait a minute, wait a minute, what's the matter? That's
the other power is gone. Hold it a second, let's hear this World Trade Power Center. If Jim Smith is with us, still in Chopper two, Jimmy there, Michael,
we just saw that as well.
The second tower,
the only one that was standing,
tower number one.
We saw some kind of explosion,
a lot of smoke come out of the top of the tower,
and then it collapsed down onto the streets below,
much like we saw the first tower just about a half hour ago.
Gosh,
this is an unbelievable,
it's incredible.
Yes,
go ahead,
Jim.
As you basically informed some people what happened,
assuming some people had no idea what was happening,
what kinds of reactions are you getting from people?
Oh,
look at this.
You're going to the second tower.
You're looking at this live right now.
Both towers now completely destroyed of the World Trade Center.
You have no idea how many people may have been in those buildings.
We have no idea.
This is a major communication center for this city,
for this country.
Many government offices in those towers.
Amazing video as you're watching it now.
It's not video,
it's live.
It's right before your very eyes.
The World Trade Center is gone,
ladies and gentlemen.
shit!
Terrible!
Well done!
Saddest thing ever.
Thank you.
Everything that's going on around the world, Miguel,
vamonos!
Mobile Command Center to Manhattan,
K.
Mobile Command Center.
I'll be advised,
Mobile Command Center is set up in front of PRA.
I have engine 209 with me.
Also,
Dr.
Prezant.
And Supervisor...
Fire Marshal Burns,
okay?
I have no radio contact with anybody else at this time.
As soon as I get something,
I'll let you know,
okay?
10-4,
Mobile Command,
sir.
Speed 3 to Manhattan Urgent.
The other tower just collapsed.
We need to collapse.
That's it.
Where's everybody?
It's like snow.
AHHHHH!
.been. Hit by airplanes in Washington.
There is a large fire in the Pentagon.
Oh, baby,
hold the leash.
Come on,
let's go to the other room.
Yeah.
Is this dangerous?
I think it just smoked.
Is the air conditioner turned off in the room?
And the windows closed in the bedroom?
People near the area are in an absolute frenzy situation.
The entire top of the building just collapsed.
John Miller,
very briefly,
you said to us just a few minutes ago that this was their concern,
that they thought, after the first tower went, that the second one was vulnerable.
The entire building just collapsed.
The building just collapsed.
We're going to leave because the smoke is coming right at us.
This is a devastating development.
They're gone.
The World Trade
Center is no more.
We do not know at this point the extent of injuries or casualties,
how many people were in these buildings.
Evaluation And what else you're able to see from your vantage point?
Michael,
we have seen the entire lower half of Manhattan just completely covered in smoke,
debris,
dust,
everything. Well, south of Canal Street is just completely covered in this smoke and dust at this time.
There is not anything recognizable of what were the two trade towers,
nothing standing out from those clouds of dust.
At this time.
We understand the school.
We believe now that we can say that both,
that portions of both towers of the World Trade Center have collapsed.
I saw the second one!
Everybody come back!
There was constant intelligence that terrorist organizations, and specifically that financed by Osama.
Bin Laden was trying to mount another series of attacks against the United States. Of course, they thought of the symbolic targets, the most symbolic was the World Trade Center, because it had been attacked yet not brought down and
.in.
8 seconds,
as it was all falling...
.looks. Like steel...
We do not know at this point...
What has happened in Lower Manhattan,
almost unfathomable.
An apparent terrorist attack.
Two planes deliberately crashed,
we believe,
into the twin towers of the World Trade Center.
Now these are pictures from just moments ago.
Earlier, one
World Trade Center collapsed.
Now you can see the collapse of the second tower.
It is almost incomprehensible to believe that these
these two
110-story towers,
there you see it,
just collapsing into the ground,
are no longer part of the skyline of Manhattan.
I'll help you.
Left on.
Come on.
Right,
what's it doing,
gang?
It's okay,
it's okay.
Rose Arcee,
one of our CNN producers,
is on the phone.
Rose,
what do you got?
I'm about a block away and there was...
People that were hanging out the windows right below where the plane crashed,
when suddenly you saw the top of the building start to shake,
and people began leaping from the windows in the north side of the building.
You saw two people at first plummet,
and then a third one,
and then the entire top of the...
Building just blew up and splinters of debris are falling on the street.
Where I'm right now. There's a thick plume of smoke and you can see crowds of people, including emergency service workers and police officers, running from the scene, screaming. And there's a school nearby.
By where there were kids in the schoolyard, that has been emptied out and they're running up the street. Now to minutes ago,
within the last minute,
actually, the second twin tower collapsed.
Just to recap,
if you're just joining us. Around 842 Eastern time this morning here in New York City,
a plane crashed into the one twin tower of the World Trade Center.
It seems that those concerns. That even caused the World Trade Center to hire a senior FBI counterterrorism official just weeks ago to try and beef up security, have
come home to roost.
It's also interesting to say that there is no type of security.
Security, which would have prevented against this today. Well, that's that, may not, that's, I'm gonna say. That may not be able to be true because security operates in waves and contentious circles out around the world. Now we've lost the picture from there, so now, trying to get out.
We've seen some people are running away. They're running away. What are they gonna do? You guys gotta run away.
Look at the plume.
I think it's going to be gone away.
No,
no,
the plume is being blown away.
It's horrific,
incredible,
not to give away.
Tuesday morning,
we're looking at...
.in. The area...
Reporting that the children were there.
At last report,
at last report,
the children were safe.
They're saying that the parents,
if you can get there,
and in this,
frankly,
it would be quite difficult.
The schools are under lockdown.
The children are not allowed to leave unless the parents come to get them.
But we have heard word that the children are okay.
The casualties here are far.
We don't even want to speculate.
We do have reporters at St.
Vincent.
A yes,
it is gone.
Both towers of the World Trade Center. Now you have been destroyed.
Audrey,
we need to interrupt you right now because of pressing developments taking place in New York, where things have gone to gotten even worse.
And there you see the twin Towers.
Both towers now have apparently collapsed.
All these people running away.
Brigitte,
this happens every day,
right?
In the Middle East.
You think to yourself,
how lucky we are,
we've never had this horrible thing happen before.
So true.
You're right.
I just imagine living in Masaki,
went through all of this during the war.
All his houses,
you know,
bombed and...
Oh,
really?
Get in,
here comes the cloud!
The cloud is coming!
Keep going!
Go,
go,
go!
Get inside!
It's gonna jump right over this building!
It's gonna jump over the building!
Here it comes!
It's gonna jump right over this building!
Get in here!
Get in here,
Marty!
I lost network I have been.
When suddenly you saw the top of the building in Arctic shape, and people began leaping through the windows in the north side of the building. You saw two people at first on it, and then a third one, and then the entire top of the building, just...
Shit!
Yeah,
I think I heard it.
Shit!
Shhh!
There you have pictures in downtown
New York.
In the area,
I think,
from what I can see,
near the World Trade Center,
one of the towers has collapsed.
Both towers have now collapsed.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Come on,
guys.
Back where you are.
We're trying to get out.
Everybody get out of the way.
Rescue workers,
there you see,
I don't understand. And
I would be very anxious to hear in the future some,
the forensics of this situation,
But both towers,
this is an unbelievable day,
both towers of the World Trade Center are now gone.
I just wanted to give you guys a kid's perspective.
I got a nine-year-old sister that just called me and asked me, Why do people hate the Americans?
Well, because we have everything, and we have a way of life that's organized and free, and they're jealous.
I mean, it's an easy question to answer.
Yeah.
We have it all.
Honey, I'm sorry you have to list stuff like this.
Because these other countries live in fear of their leaders.
It's unbelievable.
They're raised to hate.
And we have to now recognize...
And we're...
They make us responsible for all of their misery.
You know,
it's no different than when you were a kid growing up and you were beaten.
I mean,
it's,
uh,
you either take out those that beat you, or you accept it and you...
And the behavior continues.
Right.
Reaver!
Let's go,
I'm an Adan asking any division or any staff chief at the scene of any of the World Trade Center,
okay?
Any division chief or any staff chief at the scene of any of the World Trade Center,
I'm an Adan,
mobile command Center,
okay?
Mobile Command Center to Manhattan,
K.
This is 36RK at the Command Post of Manhattan,
Mobile Command Center to Manhattan,
K.
Mobile
Command Center,
What chief do you have at your Mobile Command
Center, K?
Negative on anything,
K.
Right now, we're all alone.
The second building is down.
So we have no contact with anybody at this time,
K.
10-4.
I'm in the pizza shop!
You know, this is the documentarian in me that feels like I need to record this.
Look at all the ashes.
It looks like it's snowing.
There's people getting onto the west side now, onto the walkway.
Yeah,
that's the guy.
These are the emergency workers who are coming back.
It was just about 10 minutes ago that we described to you the possibility of that North Tower collapsing.
About five minutes after we went off the air,
it did collapse.
Once again,
we have no idea at this point, the loss of life.
I can only tell you there were hundreds of emergency workers down there,
about five or six blocks.
It took probably about,
I would say,
no more than 50 or 60 seconds for that dust, cloud,
dust and smoke.
To literally make it the five or six blocks up here and begin to envelop us. At which point we started to move out of the way, there were literally dozens and dozens of firemen who were trying to run past us. In fact, our cameraman even put one of the captains in his car and drove him down to a command post.
Teterboro?
Teterboro,
I just forgot what you said.
Refueling.
I mean,
I came up here five minutes ago, getting ready to talk about which markets may be closing around the world,
but now this is just becoming irrelevant.
No,
they're irrelevant.
This is...
Oh my goodness.
There you see the building imploding.
Do you see what's happening?
Yes.
Now,
what would cause that?
I don't know.
Well,
you have...
I mean...
All right,
CSU2,
can't wait to have you on.
Hey,
you're the one that's gonna check these radios.
Climb to base.
All servicemen.
Is that a policeman?
Fire.
10.
Climb to ambulance and land off the course.
10,
Can you hold this?
Just a few moments ago,
as we said,
and perhaps 20 minutes after the first tower collapsed,
we turned around and saw what looked like sparks falling.
And then the top part of tower number one.
Collapsed.
Somebody better close the door.
We're going to have nothing but dust in here.
We need a sledge or something,
guys.
Why don't we open up keys to these fucking doors?
Get inside,
away from the dust.
Everybody get out.
Open the door for us.
John Zito is an MSNBC producer.
He lives in Lower Manhattan.
He's on the phone with us now.
John,
where are you and what can you see?
I can't see much.
I can't see more of about...
Three feet in front of my face.
All the debris and soot from the second tower is just showering down.
There's paper and just black soot.
I'm outside a bank and a bunch of people are inside in the lobby, taking cover.
Where exactly are you in relation to where the twin towers stood,
John?
I'm about,
I'd say,
15 to 20 blocks away.
I'm at the Bowling Green subway station.
I know that doesn't mean much to people who aren't from New York,
but it's in the downtown area.
It's a very popular place where a lot of commuters come in and out.
Well,
you know,
as Robin pointed out,
for a year now,
they've all been saying,
Well,
Ben Laden is preparing a big attack on the United States.
I don't know if it's Ben Laden on this particular thing,
but once I hear he's preparing an attack,
level the country he lives in.
They're protecting him.
Why do we care?
We're a country that has it all.
Now's the time to level.
There's too many people in the world anyway.
Level them out.
Do
I force the heat from in the building,
or is that a bomb?
That's the second big sprint.
Everybody in one room,
now!
I was in this before,
I know what it's like.
When the first one collapsed,
the dust followed us like a firebomb.
And you can see now whether that was an explosion or exactly what happened that caused that second tower to collapse.
We cannot tell you.
And at this point,
I can't imagine we're getting any word anytime soon.
I don't think,
I think we're safe.
Here, I think I'm on safe ground,
Bill.
I don't think.
This was clearly the way the structure is collapsing.
This was the result of something that was planned.
This is not. It's not accidental that the first tower just happened to collapse.
And then the second hour just happened to collapse in exactly the same way.
How they accomplished this,
we don't know.
But clearly,
this is what they wanted to accomplish.
Out of the World Trade Center building.
People,
the body parts.
Oh,
God.
Guys,
how you doing?
Oh,
my God.
I'm just so sad.
I know.
Now,
obviously,
listen,
The most important thing is that you stay safe,
John,
and that you get to an area where you feel that you may be most secure.
Were you able to feel the collapse?
Of that second tower?
The second tower,
no.
But the first tower that went down,
I was very close.
I'd say about five blocks away.
And CNBC's Ron and Ana and I were trying to hook up with the truck or find any NBC contact down there.
And we were very close when that tower came down.
And the debris came showering down.
And Ron and I both ran for cover.
I managed to get inside an alcove of a building and all the scaffolding around collapsed in front of me and broke the window next to me. And I climbed inside that and stayed in there for about 10 minutes.
I couldn't get out of there.
It was pitch black outside and I haven't pulled up.
I'm all right.
What you see?
Everything.
That's what chaos is.
It's just chaos out here.
It really is.
So the twin towers fall.
It's amazing.
It's crazy.
I can't believe this shit is happening.
I really can't.
It's a nightmare.
It's armageddon right here.
What's your name and how do you spell it?
Peter Rodriguez.
R-o-d-r-i-g-u-e-z Where do you work?
Embassy,
the hotel,
the Embassy Suite.
How's the hotel?
Oh man,
I can't even see it right now.
Hopefully,
it looks like we're going to have a lot of work to do.
A lot of work and hopefully all those families are alright.
My god,
this is crazy.
I can't,
I'm distraught right now,
sorry.
I can't talk,
this is crazy.
Oh,
you're insane.
This is a deal.
This is a huge deal for the city.
It's not just the city,
this is our country,
man.
Yeah,
this is our country.
The World Health and Care Center and the Pentagon, and everything else.
This is scary.
That is un-fucking-real.
Wow.
You need to read this.
Region commander has declared that we can shoot down tracks that do not respond to our direction.
Okay.
I'll pass out the weapons.
The region commander has declared that we can shoot down aircraft that do not respond to our direction.
Copy that?
Copy that,
sir.
So if you're trying to divert somebody and he won't divert...
Po's saying no.
No?
He came over to the chest.
Fox,
you got a conflict on that?
You got a conflict on that direction?
Right now.
Okay,
okay,
you read that from the vice president,
right?
Vice president has cleared.
Vice president has cleared us to intercept track.
Shoot them down if they do not respond first on RCC.
Let's go!
Tell me what you heard,
what you saw.
Well,
excuse me,
I was over there, just meeting with some of my customers.
I'm a defense contractor,
and we were standing around watching the CNN report on the World Trade Center incident. When we felt a jolt,
something along the lines,
I would suspect,
of a minor tremor.
And then a strong gust of air went through the hallways.
Immediately after that,
someone in the hallway started yelling,
Get out of the building now.
Panic inside there?
Excuse me?
Was there?
Was there panic inside there?
Yeah,
it got fairly chaotic quickly, as everyone was trying to run down the narrow corridors there on the D-ring to get to an exit.
Mobile command to, uh...
This is Italian. 4 Alpha,
I have dozens and dozens of firemen,
we're at the bulkhead on the Hudson River side of the World Trade Center.
We have medical emergencies,
we have EMS on the team,
three possible heart attacks.
We're in the process of hitting some kind of a roll call.
We're going to try to keep the units together here,
Kay.
10-4.
Mobile Command,
sir.
Stand by,
Manhattan.
10-4.
The people you see here are pretty much all emergency workers.
Many of them that I have seen in the last two to three minutes,
quite frankly,
are coming out of here. And remember this,
these are professionals.
They're coming out of there looking literally stunned,
in shock, many of them,
struggling for breath,
obviously in serious distress.
Breathing problems are the biggest problem for those who manage to make it safely out of that.
Area down below us.
You can't see much more than a block south of me right now.
And the World Trade Center probably stands about 10 blocks south of where I am at this moment.
And as you can see now,
the dust is beginning to pick up here.
It really depends on which way the wind blows, as to whether or not we get heavy dust or not.
But at this point,
I can tell you that in the first few minutes,
emergency workers were trying just basically to get out of there,
to survive.
You could see that written in their faces.
The situation was so desperate,
they just wanted to get out of there.
I just find the winters,
like, especially in California,
it's like,
that's a summer thing.
Yeah.
Just a few houses,
maybe two houses.
I don't have to part with you.
I'm gonna make Afghanistan and...
Palestine.
.a. Parking lot.
Big bombs are going to fall.
I mean, this is just...
See,
the thing is,
if it's a terrorist organization,
there's no central base,
you know?
They're just going to have to...
I saw a lot of the bombs.
They can't retaliate, then,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
they can,
but it's...
I mean,
who do you...
But it wasn't the country itself that was a terrorist.
Yeah,
it was a terrorist group.
I think it's gonna end up in some sort of a political coup.
Do you believe this,
Mr.
Garrett?
It's certainly of great concern,
I guess.
Yeah,
it's putting it mildly,
I guess.
God.
Oh,
my God.
On the beach,
did you see that movie?
No.
What was it?
Can you play a little more?
Oh God,
I'm glad I didn't.
You're okay,
John?
I'm okay.
Actually,
I'm being ushered out of here right now.
They're sending me inside the building.
And who is doing that?
Are police on the scene?
Hello?
John,
are police on the scene?
Who is moving you?
It was a New York
City police officer and he just sort of gone on his way and left me now.
But I'm the only one on the street at the moment.
You're the only one on the street.
Well,
John,
obviously get to a safe place.
Place. But tell us, as the smoke starting to clear, are you able to see anything more at this point? And literally the streets are deserted?
I'm standing across the street and I'm staring at a walk don't walk blinking sign. And so the street couldn't be more than what 10 yards across. I can barely make out the blinking don't walk sign.
John, hold on right there, thank you.
Let's go to WNBC.
NBCN.
Alright,
let's find out what's going on,
man.
I'm gonna take a look at it.
I realize,
we're not,
we're just one of, like a million.
I know,
yeah.
Now,
many of them are beginning to regroup.
A couple of them asked me where they're coming from.
Commander might be.
They're trying to get together and go back in there and try to take care of the people who obviously are in serious trouble.
There's no other way to describe it.
The language here,
at times,
if I slip into language which seems a little melodramatic,
forgive me.
Me. But this is a circumstance which is very, very difficult to describe in many ways, without sounding melodramatic.
4-.Alpha to Manhattan,
K.
4-Alpha?
We have a medical emergency,
possible heart attack. fireman.
We're on the bulkhead requesting oxygen for the fireman,
K.
Any unit hear me?
Come to the bulkhead on the
Hudson River side of the World Trade Center.
All right.
Copy that.
We are going to Teterboro.
They want us to land.
Yeah,
they want us to land,
land.
They want everybody out of here,
apparently.
I told them we're going to Teterboro.
Howard.
Yeah.
I'm on,
I'm on actually on the jersey side.
Looking into New York City from
Weehawken Boulevard East.
Yeah.
Literally,
it looks like a volcano.
It does.
That's what I'm seeing.
It's a volcano all over Manhattan.
It's Hiroshima.
It looks like,
yeah,
something from a natural disaster.
Exactly.
An earthquake,
a volcano,
something.
Just my lunch.
It's okay.
You can use mine.
If you want to go back,
you can.
Downtown Bruce,
can you hear us?
Yes, Andrea,
it's kind of quiet chaos here.
Many,
many of the buildings have been evacuated in downtown, and there are thousands of people out on the street trying to figure out how to get home.
There are long lines next to the parking garages as people try and get their cars and get out of downtown.
Around the executive mansion,
people evacuated from the White House grounds, and they're setting up a rather wide perimeter.
Around there,
at least down as far as
15th Street, on one side there.
The
uniformed Secret Service officers have been putting out yellow tape and refusing to let anybody get near the White House Treasury Department complex in that area.
And a lot of people who were working on the White House grounds and in the surrounding office buildings, kind of walking around with shocked looks on their faces.
A lot of rumors flying around here.
So far,
no specific incidents downtown.
But...
Many emergency crews running around and heading in various directions trying to deal with anything that might crop up.
I actually saw two paramedic units from Walter Reed
Hospital coming all the way down here downtown to kind of station themselves and prepare for whatever might happen.
Advice for people who are watching and might have business downtown,
don't.
Do not come down here.
It is absolute gridlock down here,
and they're doing their best to keep...
Everybody out in the streets cleared. And it is a very difficult proposition.
Bruce LaChanne,
Thank you.
Please stay in touch.
NBC News got me.
Oh yeah,
they did?
The network's talking about two locked down.
I see.
Is that it?
Skip Brandon,
former FBI special Agent,
stand by.
We're going to go back to our Audrey Barnes,
who is on the scene there near the Pentagon.
Audrey,
give us an update.
The update is police are here, right in front of the Pentagon,
not letting people get any further than this point.
They're saying that another plane has been hijacked.
And at this point,
it is now
10 minutes outside Washington,
D.C.
And police are telling me reports are that plane may be headed to the district.
And they're speculating that it may actually be headed back here to the Pentagon.
Honey Mund.
I'll give you an update on downtown.
My daughter-in-law works at 25 Broadway,
which is like five blocks from there.
They're all sitting in the offices with gas masks on.
Oh,
my goodness.
She can't get out?
No.
Where are they getting gas masks from?
I guess they have them in the city office.
I guess they have them on hand.
So you spoke to her inside the building?
No,
my mother did.
And she's sitting there with a gas mask on?
Yeah,
she's sitting with a gas mask on.
That's amazing.
This is nothing compared to what they could have done to us,
and we gotta go.
And we're sitting around, twiddling our thumbs.
We gotta,
well,
we're gonna kick some serious ass.
It's gotta be.
I think your city lacks in security because it's unbelievable that these planes were able to get through.
Yeah,
well,
how do you protect it?
How do you stop it?
You know how you stop it?
You regularly go out.
As soon as you hear of terrorism going on,
you blow up the whole goddamn country.
Why should we risk our way of life?
Exactly.
Let's teach these clowns a lesson.
Well,
you know,
to remind you one more time,
these terrorist attacks kept happening during,
I think it was the Reagan administration,
and he finally just sent bombs over to Libya.
That's it.
He bombed the country.
Right.
That's what you got to do.
That's enough.
It's very simple.
You want to keep these terrorists around.
We're going to bomb you.
Until you get rid of him.
Somebody's paying a price,
and he said,
you're going to pay the price.
And all of a sudden,
it stopped.
Right.
Because it wasn't worth the price that he exactly.
Oh,
I'd blow up
Iran, those clowns,
the Palestinians,
all of them.
All these nudniks.
Afghanistan.
All of them.
Afghanistan is a big area.
Supposedly,
that's where Bin Laden is.
They've been keeping him company.
It's a big joke.
They keep these guys,
and these guys pay them off.
Blow them all up,
and be done with them.
And you know what?
You won't miss a night's sleep.
You won't.
Exactly.
And you know,
it's really as simple as they're children over there,
and they're spoiled,
and they've gotten comfortable.
All Pentagon employees have been evacuated from the area.
Hundreds and hundreds of people have been ushered across the bridge and out of harm's way.
As you can see,
there are perhaps 50 different emergency vehicles still on the scene here.
The fire is not out.
Eyewitnesses tell us it looked like a 767 commercial aircraft that crashed into the Pentagon building this morning.
There are bits of debris of that plane scattered across
27, across the lawn of the Pentagon, into the woods.
A couple of joggers said they even saw debris in the area.
Audrey,
let me break in.
Let's focus for a second on this developing situation.
Help us sort out.
Certainly, in more than 20 years of covering horrific events,
this is something that I've never seen before.
As we say,
the emergency workers now beginning to try to gather themselves.
Over there, you can see a police emergency service unit.
They are trying basically now to reestablish some kind of a safe perimeter.
And many of the...
Emergency workers basically just happy to be alive.
Certainly, that picture tells it all.
Many of them just happy to be alive at this point,
having survived what is an extraordinary event,
the collapse of two towers.
As we said earlier in our report,
110 stories each.
I will tell you that what fell,
what I saw fall,
had to be at least 40,
50 stories of that building at first.
The skeleton was left at about,
I would say,
the 50th or
60th floor after the shell,
after the
the structure of the building fell down.
The skeleton,
the steel skeleton,
was literally sheathed off, and it took probably about another 30 seconds before the skeleton collapsed into the street.
That was the last we saw of the World Trade Center.
And that was maybe 10 minutes ago when that final skeleton,
the metal skeleton,
steel skeleton,
collapsed into the street.
That was NBC's Pat Dawson, again.
The Pentagon,
if we do hear from them,
we'll simply interrupt and let them get on talking.
Yeah,
Rebecca,
do you hear me?
Yes,
Peter,
I hear you.
I'm in the basement of 815 Connecticut Avenue.
It's a building across the block from the White House,
across the park.
You know where that is next to the...
The Chamber of COMMERCE.
I had to come down here BECAUSE,
as you SAID,
none of the cell phones are WORKING.
I'm in the engineer's office and they've given us
their phones to USE.
There's a real dichotomy here at the White HOUSE,
PETER.
Tourists who still are not fully aware of what's happening across the nation are
the White HOUSE.
They are standing there, watching with CURIOSITY.
They keep getting moved BACK.
But those of us who are inside the White House realize
the SITUATION.
I was inside the White House this morning trying to gather information for you.
When we were told by a very nervous
White House security staff
that they feared a plane was headed to the White HOUSE.
And we heard planes, indeed, OVERHEAD.
And they quickly evacuated all of us out of the White HOUSE.
NOW,
I just got off the phone with my own
crying mother, who I'm a little bit of a crying MOTHER.
I'm a little bit of a crying MOTHER.
I'm a little bit of my own
White HOUSE.
I'm not sure if you're ready for THAT.
I'm not sure if you're ready
for THAT.
I'm not sure if you're ready for THAT.
I'm
not sure if you're ready for THAT.
I'm not sure if you're ready for THAT.
The President's OFFICE.
I think it's important that
days ago was preparing a lovely state dinner for President Fox of Mexico.
I saw him and I tried to speak to him.
And, frankly,
Peter,
he was too rattled.
He said he couldn't speak and he was with his staff. And they were all very anxious and very worried. because,
of course,
they did know what's going on in the country today.
Many thanks,
Rebecca.
They want us to land.
They just want us.
They're evacuating 30 Rock,
so they just want us to land.
You want to go back and get your phone and stuff?
It's just smoke.
We saw the whole building shiver.
Our cameraman even put one of the captains in his car and drove him down to a command post.
The people that you see here are pretty much all emergency workers.
Many of them I have seen in the last two to three minutes.
Now we are...
We are getting reports from
Dow Jones across the wires just about 60 seconds ago.
Reports of a hijacked plane heading toward Washington.
We should note that President Bush is not in Washington right now.
President Bush is not in Washington.
He is en route to Washington right now on Air Force One from...
Sarasota,
Florida.
He cut short a trip there.
But to Bill,
I'm sorry,
I did not mean to interrupt you.
No,
that's fine.
I'm not logged in.
Let me do that now so I can be up to date along with you.
It's just me and Rafe standing by to where else you want us to go.
We have some good people.
Copy,
stand by.
Hey,
you got a 100-feel horn,
man.
Get people shots,
too.
I did,
I got a few right here.
Excellent.
Man,
you don't need to tell me how to shoot.
You can do it yourself.
Thank you.
Come on guys,
anybody coming?
Get your ass over here,
now!
Now!
Everything south of the Brooklyn Bridge is in a dust cloud.
There's no visibility.
People all over the street.
Travel is near impossible.
10-4, Division 1,
clear to land.
Who is saying what?
Who is saying that another plane has been hijacked?
Just sort that out.
Here,
there's a...
Take your time.
Excuse me,
officer.
Can we talk to you for a second?
That officer is trying to...
The car just tried to sneak by here and is headed to the
Pentagon building.
And they're telling everybody...
Let's see if I can get him to update us on exactly what the situation is here.
Officer?
We want to just find out what the situation is.
We're told another aircraft is coming towards the Pentagon.
We have another threat,
ma'am.
.breathing. Problems are the biggest problem for those who manage to make it safely out of the...
Oh my god,
there's no more World Trade Centers.
.You. Can't see much more than a block south of the...
.trade. Center probably stands about ten blocks south of where I am at this moment.
Dave Statter is at the Pentagon.
Dave,
can you hear me?
I hear you,
Mike.
The fire continues to burn out of control at the Pentagon.
It looked like they were making some headway.
We don't know if they had to pull back because of the threat that came in here,
but right now, there's still a great deal of fire in...
Inside the Pentagon at the moment.
Firefighting operations may have ceased for a little bit because of the threat.
The threat,
again,
which you've been talking about,
is that there's some other plane that may have been hijacked.
FBI agents on the scene here moved everybody they could away from the plane.
From the Pentagon,
including us.
There was a brief bit of panic as people ran,
and they forced us out of the area.
We're now a little bit further away,
looking at the west side of the Pentagon,
near the heliport,
the E-ring.
50th floor of the Millennium, Hilton,
And I was getting ready to call my wife.
I heard the whine of a jet.
An American Airlines jet hit the tower.
I know about planes.
It was either a 737 or a 757.
I don't know if they fly the Airbus,
but the air...
Engine configuration looked like it was a 737.
It had the nose down.
It was hauling ass.
I looked up and I thought,
what is this plane doing, coming so fast?
And it just slammed right into the first tower.
Wham.
Unbelievable.
I think it was just from the heat of the fire.
That's my guess.
And when that happened,
then they told us to get the hell out of the hotel.
What's your name?
My name's Doug Eisler.
What's your last name?
E-I-S-L-E-R.
From Philadelphia.
Have you ever seen anything like this?
Absolutely not.
I've seen at least 10 people fall to their death and just splat like a ripe tomato.
It's awful.
But it's,
I don't know who was at the controls or what was going on in the plane,
but it was not a bomb.
It was an American Airlines jet that crashed into the tower.
Sure.
He's standing about 10 blocks from where the World Trade Center towers used to stand.
You're looking at the collapse.
Of one of those towers right now.
We now have an AP news alert out of Pittsburgh.
Officials at Somerset County Airport are confirming the crash of a large plane just north of the airport.
That's about 80 miles southeast of Pittsburgh.
Again,
Officials at Somerset County Airport confirmed the crash of a large plane north of that airport,
which is located about 80 miles to the southeast of the city of Pittsburgh.
We do not know whether that crash of that plane is related.
.to. What has become an obvious terrorist attack, both here in New York City and in Washington,
D.C.
At the Pentagon.
Cindy,
if you're still there,
I just want to clarify,
you're saying there was a plane down,
a report of a plane down somewhere else in Pennsylvania?
Yes,
we are getting that from CNN as reporting that there is a plane down in Pennsylvania,
a large plane.
As well as now...
A fourth explosion at the site of the World Trade Center.
You continue to look live at the scene across New York Harbor.
What is left of the skyline is truly just smoke and ash right now.
And parents,
as you continue to watch with us,
here's what Cindy had told us regarding children in that area.
Okay,
yeah,
hi.
The police have gone up on the Williamsburg Bridge,
and now people from the walkway,
there's a walkway that goes across the bridge.
They're running back into Brooklyn.
I don't know why,
but they're running.
They're not walking back.
What's going on,
Tom?
What did you just hear?
Part of the Pentagon has collapsed.
Part of the Pentagon just collapsed.
Wait.
Where they say a lot of senior officials'
offices are,
it continues to burn.
I guess about 20,
30 minutes,
sort of lost track of time.
That whole middle section collapsed.
That wasn't from the initial explosion,
apparently from the great amount of fire there and the damage done when the plane hit.
First of all,
we were just in the building and we were looking out the window because we saw the paper going around.
We were looking out and all of a sudden we saw the plane come from this direction.
You were on the same floor?
Yeah,
remember, I told you.
I told you.
We went right through this building, right over here.
Two blocks away.
Second plane came from that side,
right into the side.
Boom.
People trampling each other.
It was terrible.
What floor were you on?
Were you inside or outside?
No,
we were in this building next door, on the 21st floor.
What did you hear?
We came down and saw the explosion.
We were downstairs when it exploded.
Did you see a plane?
Yes,
coming from the left side of the building.
Any markings on it that you might recall?
No,
no.
It was so quick.
Just out of nowhere.
Boom.
And then?
Big.
And then everybody started running,
trampling each other.
I mean,
pocketbooks,
tools,
everything I had was out of my...
My pockets. I went back and got it afterwards. So you felt the explosion? yeah, did you feel the first one or hear the first one? No, no. We just looked out the window, we were in the building and we saw. We said, Where'd the Yankees win the World Series again? It's like a ticker tape parade. We were joking around and then we looked out the window and realized that the children was on fire. We didn't hear whatsoever. Then we came down and checked it out. I saw it all I was.
I'll find the other problem.
Just let's go.
Let's get you guys down to the front here.
Sorry.
I had to learn to go here.
Cooper,
And if you just see that picture that was going by,
it's Rebecca.
In fact,
I was talking,
you get a real sense of what the urgency was in the White House.
First of all,
the White House police came walking out,
and then people began to run out of the White House.
In and of itself,
astonishingly astonishing,
because we...
Live with the notion that if there is any place in the United States which is fiercely protected,
including an anti-aircraft battery,
at least one. On the roof of the White House itself,
this is the place where the president and the vice President,
of course,
are to be secure.
Claire Shipman is on the phone from the White House.
Claire,
we are now looking it at what appear to be fairly relaxed. Security officers on the roof of the White House.
Looking in the distance, as they always do,
talking occasionally to each other.
There doesn't seem to be a high level of tension there.
What's it like on the ground?
Still have conflicting reports over what size plane hit.
We heard one eyewitness tell us that it was a small plane that he seemed to see as he was coming across the 14th Street Bridge.
Believe it or not,
somebody else said they saw something as big as a 757.
We just don't have the confirmation for you yet.
From The Associated Press,
Dateline, Pittsburgh.
Large plane crashes in western Pennsylvania.
They're citing officials at the Somerset County Airport who confirm it.
Again,
AP reporting and citing the Somerset County Airport.
Everyone has been told into the...
Bros,
we hate to interrupt you,
we've just been told.
A fourth explosion.
Now in the area of the World Trade Center.
Obviously,
neither tower is still standing.
We don't know the source of this fourth explosion.
But we do have Cindy Hsu in the newsroom.
Perhaps she can shed a little light on this for us,
Cindy.
I can't tell you that much about the fourth explosion.
What I can tell you is happening right now.
20 minutes ago,
a 767 from Pittsburgh was hijacked.
We believe that plane is headed towards Washington or Northern Virginia.
A 767 from Pittsburgh was hijacked.
Also,
a plane has gone down in Pennsylvania.
That's according to CNN.
A plane down in Pennsylvania.
And the Board of Elections,
also on the elections,
The Board of Elections has canceled today's primary.
So voters stay at home.
Board of Elections has canceled today's primary.
From your vantage point, from where you are,
you don't,
you can't see any portion of the plane.
Is that correct?
There was debris all over the place.
In fact,
I looked down.
Mike Trammell,
photographer,
and Heather Cavita,
reporter here,
said Look down,
and there was a piece,
a small piece of what apparently was the plane.
Hold on,
Dave.
Hold on just a second.
I'm standing.
Were you here working?
I was here earlier with the United States Marshal.
And did you hear anything?
I heard two explosions.
What did you see?
A lot of fire,
just what you're seeing right now.
Can you say anything to comfort those who are concerned about loved ones inside?
Let me find them first,
okay?
Thank you.
Keep safe,
okay?
What's up,
guy?
Oh,
Jesus Christ!
I'm just getting your shirt.
Alright?
Yeah,
I'm sorry,
thanks.
Got a bulletin from AP,
a large plane has just crashed in western Pennsylvania.
Again,
the Associated Press is reporting a large plane has just crashed in western Pennsylvania.
I got you into Stuyvesant High School.
Yeah,
put out the thing.
It's only a block away.
I'm at the corner of Wolfson.
Why don't you come with us, too?
Alright?
This ain't no place to be.
They're going to get the police.
We'll arrive at the site.
We'll leave you back here to get this started.
Please get on as one more to be allowed.
Sorry, I heard you,
two points.
We have someone on the phone,
I couldn't get the name.
Tell me who you are, please.
Dr.
Gerald Post is joining us by phone.
Post,
your reactions?
Well, the coordinated nature of this attack makes it clear we're not just talking about an isolated group. And I'm sure the dominant suspicion,
although no response has been claimed,
will be with the Al Qaeda network of Osama bin Laden.
It's really,
it's really,
when I turned on television,
I thought it was some sort of fantasy movie.
I don't know how to describe this.
I don't know what to tell you first.
But when that building came down...
We were a couple of blocks.
You all, right?
I'm fine,
thank you.
Are you okay?
I'm glad to come in and see you.
An incredible cloud of debris and smoke completely engulfed us.
We couldn't breathe.
We broke down the door to a building just to get out from the cloud.
Thank you.
No,
we couldn't breathe.
We couldn't see.
It was pitch black.
We're just going into a...
A corner restaurant that's allowing us in.
It was as though,
it was,
I swear I've never seen anything like it.
I've never seen anything like this.
This whole place looks like a war zone.
There's debris everywhere.
It's hard to breathe.
And when that cloud came at us,
I could feel it,
the force of it.
And it was as though,
I mean,
an instant took over,
we just...
I had to breathe.
Ashley,
we're going to let you collect yourself.
Obviously, the priority to anyone who is watching in the New York City area,
stay safe.
Do we do anything as a terrorist expert?
What should be our response, since so far, no group has claimed responsibility?
What should we be doing now?
Well,
the first effort,
obviously,
apart from responding to this multiple site attack,
is to identify who is responsible.
Having said that,
as we saw with the embassy bombings,
in fact,
I was recently involved in the trial in federal court.
Dr.
Post,
Let me interrupt you for a second.
Indeed, reports from the Federal Aviation Administration that there are possibly one or two more planes that have been hijacked this morning and are still missing. When you think of the number of aircraft that crisscross the United States, not to mention fly overseas every day.
Apparently, he'll be ready shortly.
I'm also getting words,
Sue,
right now off the wire.
A story out of Pittsburgh has it on the AP wire that a large plane has crashed in western Pennsylvania.
Officials at
Pittsburgh Somerset County Airport have confirmed that as well.
Come on,
quick,
look,
look.
He's helping a lady out.
Come on,
let's get her.
Microphone on.
No,
I wasn't in the building.
I was walking downtown on Hudson Street.
And I saw the first plane coming in.
I work at Two World Trade Center at Morgan Stanley.
And we saw the plane that hit number one.
.National. 1.
Broadway,
BZ stream,
Dust cloud,
unresolved.
People all around,
we have not gotten to the senior camp.
Saw earlier and can see now. There's a gaping hole in the west side of the Pentagon, where a great deal of fire continues to burn. Here at the E-ring,
the west side, near the heliport of the Pentagon.
The biggest problem here is solid information.
No,
we're safe.
We're staying here.
They're trying to walk.
MSNBC World Headquarters,
from The Associated Press,
Dateline,
Pittsburgh,
Large plane crashes in western Pennsylvania.
They're signing officials at the Somerset County Airport who confirm it.
Again,
AP reporting in sight.
What do you think?
Unbelievable.
Never seen anything like it in my life.
I don't want to.
Able to clue us in on that.
Mike?
CBS is reporting that there's been another hijacking.
A 737,
unknown what airline,
has been hijacked.
CBS is reporting that plane is now circling Dulles International Airport.
Again,
CBS reporting another hijacking 737 passenger jet has been hijacked.
The report is it's now circling in the area of Dulles International Airport.
Officer,
this camera is making them slow down.
Seconds are at stake,
lives are at stake.
State away from, uh...
Pat Dawson on, uh...
The west side of the Trade Towers. NBC's Rick Sanchez joins us on the phone. He's also in Lower Manhattan. Rick, what do you got? One of the most desperate situation for these people. I just had five firefighters come to be, many of them in tears, because they've lost so many of their fellow firefighters. And one of them, as I was listening, had his radio on Lester, and you could literally hear. Firefighters that are still trapped in all that rubble are crying,
uh...
Saying things like, get me out, someone get to me, uh...
The, the, the, the. The sense here is that there are still people somehow in that rubble. Some of the maybe firefighters, as well as some of the other office workers who usually work in that building. uh...
The firefighters are you guys you might imagine are extremely desperate about this situation, people.
Please be quiet.
You in that building,
Mr.
Cameraman.
Get up on the sidewalk!
Let's go,
get on the sidewalk!
Hey.
Division
Hey!
The station is...
1 acting to Manhattan.
The command post is going
to be set up at Park Row,
south of City Hall
at Beezy Street.
south of City Hall,
It's the only place
where we can,
where there's weekend.
the dust cloud has relieved,
The dust cloud has...
possibly.
Alright,
this is Division 6,
10-4,
Division 6,
acting Division 1.
The command post
at this point will be
Leasy Street and Park Row
south of City Hall K do you copy
Beezy Street and Park Row,
south of City Hall.
K,
do you copy?
Thank you.
That's the 10-4 case.
We have all incoming
fire department units
report to this location
and stage on TARF low.
Division 6 acting again.
The access,
the down the
FDR is clear.
PD has the FDR lanes open.
But have all units approaching
use extreme caution.
Traffic is going the wrong way.
and numerous civilians.
Get up on the sidewalk!
I'm going to throw you
into the screwing down here.
It shouldn't happen.
Tell you what,
you've got 10 seconds to move
that camera or it's going in the trash.
I'm a lifesaver.
that's what I am.
Back to Dave Statter.
Dave?
Yeah,
I'm here,
Mike.
We just had a military
jet fly over here,
very low.
We can tell you from the people we've
been talking to coming from the Pentagon,
they have very little in
the way of information,
and there's a lot,
as you talk about rumors,
that have been circulating.
circulating through here about
another possible attack and certainly
the hijacked planes you've talked
about that seem to be confirmed.
So that is causing a
great deal of concern here.
Rick,
I'm going to have to
break away from you.
We're getting more information
on the situation in Pittsburgh.
Let me read directly
off the Associated Press.
A large plane crashed just north
of the Somerset County Airport,
80 miles southeast
of Pittsburgh.
The plane,
I just lost it on my screen,
believed to be a
767 is what I
think I read there.
But again...
Oh
Do we have an eyewitness here?
We have an eyewitness,
I think,
to what happened
here at the Pentagon,
if you have a moment.
Heather Cabot's bringing
that person over here.
Can you tell me what you
saw and where you were?
Well,
we were on Columbia Pike,
where the shelter is.
All of a sudden,
you can hear the
noise coming first,
and then you can feel
the shaking of the building.
And we just looked
up out of the window,
and I saw the tail end go.
What size plane?
For me,
it looked like a big-size plane.
It was definitely a
passenger plane.
And everything just,
And everything just shook.
everything shook.
And then all of a sudden,
you just heard
this big explosion.
And somebody said,
my God,
They hit the Pentagon.
they hit the Pentagon,
And I didn't know that they had hit
the World Trade Centers this morning.
And then,
you know...
We've seen a couple
injured who've been taken out.
Have you seen any others?
Have you seen any?
Oh,
I've seen people,
yeah.
I've seen a few injuries.
And they just,
they lined up stretchers or those
things they use for the bodies.
And a whole slew of
people just went in line,
military people,
heading that way.
So I take it that it
was a lot of injuries.
What's your name?
Mark Easton.
Thank you,
Mark.
Yes,
sir.
I'm going to go through
the tunnel right now,
man.
I'm going to do that.
All right,
acting to Manhattan.
To Manhattan.
Engine 321,
say it.
We're in engine 6's area.
321, right?
what route did you say
getting to Manhattan came?
K?
Call 5 to Manhattan.
Standby,
Stand by,
call 5 message.
call 5 message Call 5,
Call 5,
we're trying to establish
a command post.
At Betsy and West.
Notify the department official That's where
we're trying to establish a command post
Car 5,
10-4,
via Vesti.
V-5...
Car 5,
V-5,
via Vesti for Division 6 acting.
They set up a command post,
Park Row,
and off the city hall
by Vesey Street.
And we're going to have
Unis being redirected,
Unis being in the Park
Row for the City Hall,
Okay.
okay?
About six blocks away
now from our hotel.
I'm gonna pan up so you
can see the type of black
fire smoke that's in the
direction of the hotel.
A little more to the right,
behind that taller building,
would have been the World
Trade Center.
Call 5,
receive.
Alright,
Attention all units responding
into the World Trade Center.
We're now receiving,
we're now setting up
a new command post.
Off-road,
south of City Hall
by Bessie Street.
All units responding to the
new staging area on off-road.
Repeating,
all units,
not presently committed,
respond over to
the staging area,
Park Road,
south of City Hall
on Vesey Street.
We advise the SDR
drive is now clear.
You will use extreme
caution proceeding to,
proceeding downtown
of Manhattan.
proceeding downtown Manhattan.
Sign 1045-416.
Phone.
Where are you,
AA,
where are you getting
this report from?
I'm watching Channel 42 News,
it's New Jersey.
They're saying that two more planes got hijacked
out of Boston and they're headed for L.A.
Oh,
my God.
Whoa.
This is sick,
man.
What the hell is going on here?
This is an organized
effort like we've never seen.
I mean,
how could the FBI or the
CIA not be aware of this?
Can you tell me what happened?
What did you see?
I saw,
I don't know,
I saw windows coming out of the building and the
ceiling falling on the floor where I was walking.
That's when we started
heading for the exit.
And then we got downstairs.
We got to the first floor
from the second floor.
All the way to the lobby and all of
a sudden it was this big explosion.
I don't know if it's just
like what you just seen.
That's what we went through
before we came out of the building.
Then when we
get out the building,
then another smoke cloud came.
We had to go through
that smoke cloud again.
Mom,
I just want you to
know I'm all right.
I don't know what
else to tell you.
We came from the
any second floor,
82nd floor and I don't
know where I'm going.
and I don't know
where my peers are.
I don't know.
I hope they got me okay.
I hope to God they're okay.
That's all I can say.
I don't know.
I don't know what.
We saw a shadow,
We saw a shadow.
It looked like a plane.
Next thing we know,
it was boom,
and the floor started shaking.
And then we saw
debris fall down,
and next thing we know,
we had to get
out of the building.
We stuck on the
stairs for a while.
We finally got
down to the lobby.
Then we get to the lobby,
It was as big as a tree.
there was this big explosion.
just like what you just saw.
A big cloud of smoke like that.
We thought we escaped that.
We escaped and then we
wanted to come out and run to it.
We saw a wall of plastic.
It's like pyroplastic.
It was like pyroplastic.
It was heading toward us.
That's when we started running.
I thought we'd
be able to unrun it,
but we couldn't.
It was pitch black.
It was like...
It was like a comet
just hit the earth.
Like a comet?
Yeah.
Look at this,
Look at the clouds.
look at that.
What's up,
Fizz?
I hope it doesn't kill you.
What's the matter?
I was consulting there for
the real estate department.
we first heard the blast and then the ceiling of our office
started falling down and the wiring behind the ceiling,
everything started falling.
And we looked out the window,
we saw windows
coming down from above.
That's when I
started saying that,
well,
this is not just an
ordinary emergency.
it must be something really big.
Before this second explosion,
somebody was telling us...
A plane hit the building,
but we don't know about it.
I was hoping it's not a
suicide bomber or something,
but I don't know right now.
More smoke rising
from the ground.
So there was some kind
of additional explosion,
but I don't know what it was.
Definitely.
Heads will roll on this one.
If there are any heads
left when they're done.
They're also saying that the
White House knew
about this stuff?
They had a credible
report of a terrorist attack.
We're aware that the plane that was
hijacked out of Pittsburgh has crashed.
It did crash.
It has?
Yes,
that's what we're doing.
Where did it crash into?
About 80 miles
outside of Pittsburgh.
Joining me here
is Tito Castellanos.
He was inside the building
at the time of the explosion.
Chris,
I'm going to let him
explain to you what he saw,
what he experienced.
Hello.
Hi,
what can you tell us about where
you were and what you saw and heard?
I was at the subway station
and my ticket stub says 8.45 a.m.
And as I was waiting
for the train to come,
we heard the explosion.
A lot of debris fell on us,
you know,
like dust-type particles
and stuff like that.
And then automatically they started to
tell us to evacuate through another exit.
So finally we were
able to get out.
We come to the sidewalk
on the scene there.
I saw a lot of debris and smoke
on the street and sidewalk,
and the cops on the other side of the
street were telling us to hold on because
there was still a lot of debris falling
from the building that was burning,
actually.
As all this rain of bricks and glass
and stuff that was coming down stopped,
we were told to go on,
but the people behind
us were panicking,
and they started to
push us into the street.
Finally,
I got to the
the corner of the street and I looked
up and that's when the second airplane,
I saw it coming on the horizon and
make it like a small nosedive and boom,
hit the second building,
the one that's
facing the south part.
Anyway,
at that moment,
everybody panicked,
started to run away.
I was under a
debris of hot metal.
Excuse me.
I was in the building
because I was driving a friend.
So I'm worried for her safety.
She works in the U.S.
Customs.
I pray for her to be alright.
I was injured in my leg
and I had my hip almost
dislocated because I had a
hip replacement a year ago.
I'm sorry,
I'm pretty shaky right now.
Chris,
this is Rick.
That's just one of many stories
as people come by us here,
all of them telling us
their stories of the people
that they know that
are inside the building.
people that they fear are
trapped inside the building.
And I would say that of
every 20 people that walks by,
one of them has
some type of injury,
be it a small injury,
a bandage,
they're wrapped,
they're holding their eyes,
they're holding their head.
So in other words,
that's what I was
just told right outside.
We don't know if
it was shot down.
And there are
people on that plane?
I mean,
are you talking
about passengers?
We would assume so,
but we just don't know.
This is a sick day.
I just don't ever recall a time
when a plane was hijacked.
We didn't immediately
know about it.
Well,
we can tell you right now that an
ambulance has blown up in this area.
Apparently,
it was close enough
to the building that,
according to the
information that we just
received moments ago
from one of our producers,
she did an interview with
one of the EMS workers,
and the EMS worker
says that one of her friends,
another EMS worker,
was trapped inside the
ambulance when it blew up,
and she has lost her partner.
Up at 8.45,
At 8.45 we had a
plane crash into the
we had a plane crash into the...
World Trade Center.
This plane crash,
American Airlines is telling us,
the second one that you
see the fireball was Flight 11,
Boston to Los Angeles.
It was a D.C.-based.
It was a DC-based American
Airlines crew aboard that plane.
American Airlines
crew aboard that plane.
Now you're going
to see the first wheel.
Why are they still
being hijacked?
All right,
here's what I know.
The plane crashed
in Somerset County,
Pennsylvania.
Hey,
Howard.
Maybe the pilot just
flew it into the ground.
Yeah.
You think the pilot's here?
I just say,
I'd rather crash in an
unpopulated area at this point.
you know,
Let's just k*** ourselves.
Maybe that's what they're doing.
But now,
you know,
Ganyer just told me
that people are thinking,
assuming that the
actual pilots are not,
you know...
I don't think so.
That can't be.
no,
that they're not
the actual pilots.
They're just like
some terrorists.
It's just like some...
Right,
it'd be some...
I need some terrorists.
NG24,
what a mayday.
go.
NG24,
and one member's
out of the building.
I got two members trapped.
I can't tell the command post.
Two members trapped in the
promenade between the two towers.
10-4,
man,
at the Mobile Command Center.
Mobile Command Center,
okay.
We received that report.
NG24 has five fighters
trapped in the promenade.
We'll try to relay that message.
Right now,
we're at the intersection
of Battery and West.
Thank you.
The ambulance was situated about
500 feet from the area where
the other buildings were at the time.
You have to understand
that when this first happened,
they certainly didn't imagine that there
would be second or tertiary explosions.
So they parked some of
their vehicles in those areas,
and many of those vehicles,
people in those vehicles,
have lost their lives.
As to what fire officials
are trying to do in this area,
Chris,
it's very difficult.
They're trying to get
themselves to the scene,
but they're not able to.
Originally,
they weren't able to because of
all the smoke and all the debris.
And now because of the
people in the area and because
of some of the ways some
of the cars have been parked.
So they have a
real serious problem.
Well,
hold on a second here.
Now you're going to see
one of the towers to collapse.
This is the World Trade Center
110-story tower.
And then shortly after that,
the second tower just
collapsing into a pile of rubble.
the second tower.
Just collapsing
into a pile of rubble.
Here's the AP lead
out of New York.
In a horrific sequence
of destruction,
terrorists crashed two planes into
the World Trade Center and the twin
110-story towers
collapsed this morning.
Explosions also
rocked the Pentagon,
rocked the Pentagon.
and there was a car bomb
at the State Department.
They're telling most
of the fire officials to
meet in the Office of
Emergency Management,
where they're going to hopefully
try and at least get a handle on the
situation by getting most of the
fire officials and rescue officials there.
The Red Cross,
we talked to them
just moments ago.
They told us to
put this number out.
They're in this area.
Dave Statter mentioned
a few minutes ago another
military aircraft that was
scrambled out of Andrews.
We saw it bear off
towards the southwest,
possibly in response to the reports that
you've got of the aircraft over Dulles.
I can now confirm
that the White House,
about a half an hour ago,
vehicles pulled up in the south
entrance of the White House,
entrance of the White House.
apparently moving
some key personnel out.
And we've been able to spot
on the White House roof the
Special Operations Forces
personnel of the Secret Service,
three of them.
Maria Bartiromo,
however,
has been in the financial
district all morning.
She's now live at the
New York Stock Exchange.
Maria,
we'll turn it over to you.
Thank you,
Sue.
Well,
basically,
clearly the city has come
to a halt in New York.
I am on Wall Street.
I have been down here and
witnessed two of the explosions.
I have been down here
and witnessed two...
The explosions.
Now,
the first explosion that I witnessed was the
second plane going into the second tower.
I was outside.
Frankly,
I ran for my life.
It was like a movie.
A plane going right into the
top of the World Trade Center,
the second tower.
The whole
Wall Street area,
Broadway,
It was filled with people.
Everyone just ran.
There was a lot of
debris coming at all of us.
In fact,
things were coming
from the building,
metal pieces as well as papers.
We all ran.
The second explosion
that I witnessed was about...
10 a.m.,
and that was,
in retrospect,
the collapse of that tower.
And again,
debris came at us.
The whole area
turned pitch black.
see was smoke.
We couldn't even breathe,
practically.
We were closing our eyes.
I actually went under the building
across the New York Stock Exchange.
There were steps which I just stayed in
the stairwell as a place to just to hide.
And then when I thought
that it was quieted down,
I made my way back into
the New York Stock Exchange.
It's a gas leak.
That's their plan,
Howard.
They instill fear.
That's what they wanted
to do was the fear factor.
Don't expect KC to defend us.
Yeah,
like,
I want to be the
foxhole with KC.
I'll tell you one thing.
I've never been,
you know,
the Vietnam War,
I never wanted to go fight,
but I'll go fight this one.
This is something
to fight about.
I'll enlist right now,
I'll enlist.
goddammit,
fly over there and help
blow up these pricks.
I'll be right with you,
Howard.
I'll be right there with you.
You bet.
Howard,
you know what I
keep saying to John?
KC,
you get on the ground floor,
buddy,
if you're nervous.
I'm serious.
Don't be safe.
I'm not even making fun of you.
You go ahead.
Go ahead.
Get down.
I'm serious.
If you're not comfortable,
leave.
Go where you're comfortable.
Nobody's comfortable
here now anyway.
Yeah,
I'm shaking.
I mean up on a
high floor like this.
All right,
so go.
Goodbye.
Don't worry.
You can go.
This is a real thing.
If you have a real fear,
you should leave.
As for communications
in this area,
they're really almost
impossible to get.
Because,
as you know,
most of the towers have many of the antennas there
that control most of the phone lines for this area.
There's no way of
calling on any cell phones.
Some landlines is what
we call them in our business.
Some regular phones
are working in this area.
We were lucky enough
to be able to find one,
which is two or three
blocks from the scene,
and that's how we've
been able to contact you.
transmitted by engine 2-1.
All units in the
program at hand,
stand by and left urgent.
Division 6 acting.
Thank you.
transmitted a Mayday.
Intercom,
Any prominent have
firefighters trapped.
I have firefighters trapped.
That's number one.
Number two,
call 5,
call 5.
establishing a command post.
West Street and Vesney Street,
we would appreciate it if
you can respond over to
that location and coordinate
the efforts with him,
the efforts with them,
we have a command post set up at
Vesey and Park Row on the corner.
we do have units coming into
that staging area on Park Row,
K.
I'm keeping contact with Car 5,
Sure.
Any other units calling ahead?
Any other Unicorn that has...
We're looking at a picture
of the Pentagon right now.
We're getting some live
pictures for the first time,
a close-up of the
Pentagon complex there,
which it was roughly
an hour after the
World Trade Center attacks,
if we want to call
it that at this point,
pretty safe to say,
that the Pentagon was
subject to a similar attack,
with eyewitnesses
saying that they saw the tail
end of a jet plow into
the office complex there,
the Pentagon complex.
engine,
urgent,
go.
it's being manned by an
off-duty member from Rescue 1.
Be advised,
it appears that we have lost water
pressure down in Lower Manhattan.
Can you have Marine 1 or any other available fire
boat respond to Vessi Street on the west side?
We're going to need
water supply into the area,
K.
As a result of a 911
call from the airport itself,
there are no other
details on this crash yet.
And it's not clear whether the crash was related to
anything else that has happened in the country today.
Southern Tower.
What floor?
39th.
How did it begin?
What floor?
39th.
Where did it begin?
What happened?
I have no idea.
I just heard the reports that just the
other tower was crashed by an airplane.
Well,
good morning,
Andrea.
Right now with me
is Joel Suckerman.
He was on his way into work,
I believe,
when he saw an American airline.
when he saw an American
Airlines jet crash into the Pentagon.
Airlines jet crashed
into the Pentagon.
Joel,
tell me what you saw.
Well,
traffic was very
heavy this morning,
so it was bumper to bumper.
We were all stopped.
I was probably about 100 yards
from the Pentagon when I heard this
screaming sonic boom and saw the
jet come screaming across the highway.
It was an American Airlines jet,
silver with the markings
along the windows.
And within seconds,
it hit the side of the Pentagon.
My first thought was,
my God,
it's coming in so low
for a landing at National.
But it screamed
across Route 110,
hit the west side
of the Pentagon.
Immediately,
there were flames that shot up,
higher flames,
white smoke.
And then within seconds...
We're interrupting Lauren Ash.
Are they going to try to
evacuate the whole building there?
Well,
at one point,
that's what the
thought process was,
that it was better to evacuate.
And then,
in retrospect,
that wasn't the case because
everyone who went outside,
including myself...
were subject to
large explosions,
very loud explosions that
were accompanied by heavy,
heavy smoke.
We could not breathe.
People are wearing white
masks to cover themselves.
I don't know if you
could actually get a shot,
but I'm covered in soot.
And this is better.
I already tried to
clean myself off.
But just standing outside
a couple of blocks away,
and I was just overtaken
by smoke and debris.
That's the game plan.
People are not waiting outside.
People are not waiting out.
outside.
They're finding a
secure place elsewhere.
Understandably so.
Thank you.
Ashley Banfield.
And Ashley,
where are you?
What are you finding out?
Well,
we just heard another explosion
go off a couple of minutes ago,
Chris.
And saw a bunch more
people sort of running this way.
A woman on her bike was
screaming as it went off.
And there was a
New York City officer.
He's playing clothes,
walking by with a radio.
I tried to stop him to
ask what happened.
And all he said was,
car bomb,
car bomb.
And then I couldn't press
him for any more information.
He said,
I have no time for this.
And we haven't
seen anything since,
but the cloud of smoke is
still extremely thick around,
right around the
direct vicinity of...
The race center,
they're evacuating
the whole area.
The city's basically shut down.
All the subway trains and office
buildings and businesses have been closed.
Mayor's race is
having a primary today.
That has now been canceled.
Evacuate the train boys
are standing on the street.
the sun has come out as blue sky above us we started with i mean sheer
blackness when that when that cloud of debris and of smoke came out of
us when the explosion happened.
We couldn't see anything.
We couldn't read.
We tried to make our way a few blocks up and
we've made contact with some other NBC crew here.
And we're all just trying to,
you know,
get communication because
that's one of the keys here.
Everyone's running around with cell
phones and none of them is working.
Spurns broadcast to go to Gordon
Peterson live near the Pentagon.
Gordon?
Gordon's actually with me,
it's Dave Statter.
We're going to come
to Gordon in a second.
Gordon has an eyewitness,
but first we have
Lieutenant Colonel Art Hobo,
who's
Air Force Public Affairs,
the first official word
we've gotten from anyone.
Colonel,
can you tell us what you know?
All we know at this point in time
was that there was an explosion.
At this point,
away from the building
as far back as possible.
And if people have
loved ones in the building,
please let the fire and
rescue people do their work.
We want to stay away from
the building as much as possible.
as we can because all we're doing
right now is inhibiting the fire and rescue
folks by people trying to come to the
building and find out about their loved ones.
Are there people in
that building dead?
I do not know.
Now he's just
shooting his mouth off.
You know,
he needs his sort of money,
and it also needed people
who are prepared to die,
because obviously a number of the people involved in
this died while these attacks were being carried out.
Keith,
interrupt me for one second.
if I can interrupt
you for one second.
We are looking at these
pictures from America.
We're receiving them live
here in the United Kingdom.
We're not sure.
We're watching the third
explosion cause the collapse.
It's just out of control.
It's the same stuff right now.
Out of friggin'
control.
Let me see if anybody's
got any information here.
Darren,
go ahead.
Darren?
Yes.
Go ahead.
Howard,
you need to stay on the air.
You have the best coverage.
You have a bird's eye view with
Cabby and Doug in New York.
I'm out here in Boston,
and your coverage is fantastic,
better than the network.
Okay,
good.
Then I'll stay on the air.
You're doing a great
public service right now.
You have a network of listeners.
I turned off my
microphone for a while.
I said to Tom,
should I get off the air?
And Tom said,
believe it or not,
you're doing a good job here.
you're doing a good job here,
and people are
calling like crazy.
You need to speak,
and especially for people
outside of New York.
I'll stay on the air.
Definitely,
definitely.
Alright,
thanks.
You're doing a great job.
Alright.
Please revisit origin.
Alright,
we got a number of people trapped
here from the previous collapse.
We need a hand to get them out,
Kac.
We're about four feet under,
About four feet under,
I really don't know.
Where were you operating?
Left side,
guys.
Left side of tower
number one or tower two?
Tower one.
Calling the Mobile
Command Vehicle.
Mobile Command,
We have urgent message
from the Department.
We have contact with units that are trapped in
the vicinity of the west side of Tower Number 1.
They're requesting urgent help.
10-4,
west side tower one.
west side Tower 1,
that's contact call 5,
That's contact call five,
K.
Contact call five.
Call 5,
Tell them that we have a report of
members who are trapped under debris.
10-4.
There's certainly a lot of
crisscross mayhem going on.
As many police
officers as they could...
Thank you.
As many police officers as they could
muster to control pedestrian traffic,
they've tried to
post on corners,
but I mean,
there's bleed through,
they're not able to
keep everybody out,
but clearly most of the people
have been making their way north.
It's terrifying down here,
Chris,
when that last bomb went,
or when that last collapse
happened and the cloud came out,
it was like something
out of Hollywood,
it was literally inescapable,
and hold on,
there's some emergency
vehicles passing us.
You come over here
so we can see you.
I need a mic,
Bruce,
okay?
This is
Omar Campos and his friend,
Adil Raji.
Omar doesn't speak
English, so Adil's
going to translate for us.
Omar,
you were an eyewitness,
yes?
Yeah,
And what did you see?
What did you see?
He was working right
here outside of the building,
you know,
to the building right there.
He was working outside.
We're going to break into
Gordon Peterson's report there.
Number of injured?
I have no idea at this point.
Size of plane?
According to the eyewitness,
he said that it looked
like a corporate jet,
but
I have no official word
on that at this point.
That's the E-ring
of the Pentagon,
senior officials there?
It's really eerie seeing the
people who got caught in that blast,
because everyone
looks like a ghost.
The streets are,
it's like Mount St.
Helens.
The streets are covered in about an inch of this gray
dust and ripped papers and shreds of charred glass.
And a lot of people are,
a lot of people are sort of
milling about trying to connect,
you know,
with,
05530,
17,000,
parking,
2-0.
Somewhere an aircraft
took off without permission,
somewhere south of D.C.
and was heading
in this direction.
there is...
Marine 1,
you're responding with a
vestige crew on the left side,
establish a water relay,
Marine 1 We're at 10-84,
be advised we have numerous
injured people on board,
babies and hundreds of
people So we might have to
relay them off our boat with
another boat or something,
okay Alright,
that's at 10-4,
we'll talk to you in a moment We're
right below the North Coast Marina,
that's a 10-4,
We're right below the
North Coast Marina,
about 100 yards,
I'm not sure what
street we're on
Okay.
Standby,
You know what area to go.
go.
Yeah,
this is Marine 6.
I'm on the west side highway on
Penn. I can't seem to get out,
okay.
This is Marine.
an officer,
Are you an officer or
firefighter for Marine 6?
a firefighter from Marine 6.
This is an officer from the
Marine Division,
okay.
All right.
Are you on the west side highway
or the west side of the building?
okay.
On the highway.
You're on the west side highway?
Okay.
Are you pinned in a
piece of apparatus?
I was,
that's what.
Calling the mobile
command vehicle.
Andrea,
we're back talking to Omar Campos and his
friend Adil Raji is translating for him.
Now,
Omar,
you say this was
a smaller plane,
10 to 15 passengers maybe?
No,
it's muy grande.
He said it's not like too big,
it's just...
It's not too big.
And it...
You know commercial planes?
He said it's like a
business airplane.
It's like a business jet.
Like a business jet,
and it was a jet.
Yeah,
it's like a business airplane.
Yeah.
And what did you
see the aircraft do?
Which one did you see exactly?
Oh,
well,
I saw it.
It just went over my head.
It's come very fast
down each move,
It's come very fast down each move
then it goes straight to the buildings.
then it goes straight
to the buildings.
And the
Israeli embassy in London
has been evacuated.
Obviously,
there is global reaction to the disaster
that is occurring here in the United States.
We had also mentioned,
of course,
that one of the planes that
is believed to have crashed
into the World Trade Center
was an American Airlines jet.
We now understand that
American Airlines officials in Dallas,
where the company
is headquartered,
are going to hold
a news conference.
and shortly.
So it'll be interesting.
Maybe we'll get some more information
on the passenger count on that jet.
Thank you.
Marine 6 to Manhattan.
The member you just
spoke to is Captain Fuentes.
He is the Marine Division.
Trying to get him some help.
Calling the Mobile
Command Vehicle.
Where do you have
members trapped?
35 members trapped.
In the
28 Engine.
Marine Division.
Where?
We're on the West Side Highway
opposite the World Trade Center.
We have Captain Fuentes
trapped in a vehicle.
Head for...
Head 4.
36 Alpha to Manhattan,
K.
3-6 Alpha.
Alpha. Where do you want us?
3-6 Alpha,
where are you right now?
We're heading out of
the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
Far out below Manhattan,
Far down below Manhattan,
opposite the World Trade Center.
Yeah,
it's like...
Ah,
yeah,
it's a big one.
Do you know what color it is?
Ah,
I can see it.
Yeah,
It was like white...
Ah,
yeah,
it's a big one.
What color was it?
It's like white on the top,
It's like white in the top.
it's like blue color downstairs.
White on the top
and blue on the color.
and blue on the color?
It's not like blue,
like white blue.
Like the airplanes
here in America.
American Air?
Something like that.
Something like the United,
you know.
like white blue.
American Air?
And Gordon,
you know,
there's one thing we've heard
from some conflicting information.
They're saying like a large
business type airplane.
Others have said it's
been as large as a 767.
There are conflicting
reports we should tell people,
we should tell people,
including some
military people who...
seem to have witnessed or getting
information that it may be that large.
Conway calling Manhattan K.
At least three
engines down on one.
We got car fires that...
Unit transmitting is
totally unreadable.
Everybody stand by unless
you have an urgent message.
If there's an urgent message,
go ahead.
You're breaking up and
tying up the frequency.
Go to another radio.
Are you an eyewitness as well?
Well,
I only seen the back part as
it was going over our building.
What's your name?
Mark Eason.
And what did you see,
Mark?
Just the plane.
We were upstairs in the window,
and we heard the rumbling first,
and then the plane
just flew over top of us.
It was so low that
everything just...
Where were you?
On Columbia Pike,
On Columbia Pike.
and it just,
And it just scared
the mess out of us.
it scared the mess out of us,
and all of a sudden,
we,
when it went past,
you know,
I ran downstairs,
and they just said,
you know,
it was a big explosion,
it was a big explosion.
They said,
oh,
my God,
it hit the Pentagon,
It hit the Pentagon.
Now,
I know you just
caught a glimpse.
Thank you.
One tower collapses
and the other collapses.
Carol Marine,
our CBS News correspondent
based in Chicago,
is just back from this
part of New York City.
Carol?
Dan,
I think I was in the second collapse
or an explosion right after that
because I was trying to make my
way around Stuyvesant High School.
I believe that's correct.
I'm not a New Yorker.
But
I was coming...
toward the World Trade
Center looking for CBS
crews and asked a
firefighter if he saw any.
He told me to walk down
the middle of the road.
All of a sudden,
there was a roll,
an explosion,
and we could see coming at
us a ball of flame stories high.
He and others screamed run,
and I ran.
I fell.
One of them picked me up.
We ran as fast as we could.
and then he threw me into the
wall of a building and covered me.
Forgive me.
I am in it.
I am in his debt.
You know,
Dan,
I know firefighters do
incredible work all of the time,
but this was exceeded
anything that I can imagine.
He threw me into a wall,
covered me with his body.
I could feel his heart
banging against my back.
We were both so sure
we were going to die.
The flame somehow
stopped short of us.
An expert with us on the phone,
George Eisen,
who is a terrorist expert at
William Patterson College,
joins us.
Professor Eisen,
can you hear me?
Yes,
I can.
Your reaction,
please,
and how this could happen.
This is such a coordinated activity
that it had to have an extremely highly,
highly sophisticated
infrastructure to carry this one out.
Obviously,
when I was talking to you,
there's no such thing
as terrorist expect.
Such a magnitude,
As I'm watching myself,
this is a tragedy
beyond description.
Let's go back to Frank Herzog,
who is near the
Washington Monument.
Frank?
We're seeing what looks like
a medevac helicopter going
up the Potomac River right
now from the Pentagon area.
Smoke continues to billow there,
and we can confirm that no signs of any smoke
or anything around the State Department.
So I think that
was a bogus report.
I can tell you that the security is still
very heightened on top of the White House.
The security people up there
are looking out to the west.
We have got an
unconfirmed report,
another plane out there.
They say about four miles out.
But we have not been
able to confirm that at all.
Carol Marine,
did you see any bodies?
Did you see anyone
that you said to yourself,
that person is dead?
I saw people on stretchers
that I was certain were dead.
I saw firefighters and
paramedics going into buildings
where they themselves had to
wonder if they were coming out.
But there were...
A surprising number of people
ambulatory and making their way out.
I saw much more of that
than I saw actual carnage.
The concern that I heard
from police and fire was that the
people who were dead didn't
make their way out of those towers,
that most of the death...
...is contained
within those buildings.
Contact my daughter
who lives in Manhattan,
and I just got a hold of her,
but I mean,
it's crazy.
Yeah,
my wife Marlo is,
she's in the 20s,
and she's in a panic mode.
She can't get home.
she's just running
on the streets.
Yeah.
Wow.
You know,
she's running home
as quick as she can,
and it's scary because she
doesn't have a cell phone.
I can't get in touch with her.
I am returning again
to my earlier point.
The sophistication of this entire
enterprise leaves me speechless.
The coordination.
It cannot be just a lone
cowboy who is just riding into the
Twin Towers,
per se.
But whatever collapsed created,
and you saw it in
some of that video,
Dan,
a rain of cinders so thick that you
couldn't see this far in front of you,
and you couldn't breathe.
A police officer,
and I wish I knew
the firefighter's name,
a police officer by the name of
Brendan Duke grabbed my hand,
and he and I tried to
find our way through it.
until we could hit a
clearing in the light.
What you're seeing
on the ground here,
Dan,
was in the air,
and you couldn't see.
And again,
we thought we were finished.
We somehow got to the light.
Another firefighter gave me his
mask for a moment so I could breathe,
And then I made my way somehow through
the smoke into the light to our crews.
There was a cameraman
there whose head was bloody,
and he was trying
to shoot and set up.
some of these shots there.
The firefighters,
the police,
the crews,
the people,
people streamed toward me as I
made my way to the Trade Center,
sobbing and crying and trying
to call home on dead cell phones,
but they couldn't get through.
Unit,
Go ahead.
Rescue,
coming.
Go ahead,
Sam.
I'm coming to the police.
Double Command Center.
we got no hands.
We got movement
trapped on the website.
Rescue 1,
squad.
Unit,
You're breaking up.
Repeat your message.
People trapped on the west side,
low in hashtag.
What unit is this?
Marine Battalion 8.
Alright,
Marine Battalion,
we have help coming in.
If you tell me exactly
where you are,
I'll get you some help.
Where are you?
I can't read it.
Calling the mobile
command vehicle.
Any unit at the scene of
the World Trade Center.
What's happening for me,
the ultimate puzzle is
how possible to hijack.
That's what I was going to ask you because
it is not simply one hijacked airplane,
obviously,
that we are talking about.
you bring up the the issue
of a coordinated effort it is
almost unbelievable there is
so much fear out there even
now because of gas main
leaks there was a point at which
i watched firefighters run
someone threw me forward a
paramedic truck let me jump inside
and drove me halfway and then a
New York City bus driver
He opened his doors of an empty bus
and drove me here to the broadcast center.
to all of them,
I mean,
citizens of New York,
citizens of New York and...
and have remained amazingly
calm but deeply frightened.
have remained amazingly
If we're looking into the
possible organizations
that can pull through
this kind of thing.
they have to have,
any organization must have an
infrastructure here in the United States.
And I very strongly believe.
I didn't know.
Come on.
Where'd you get the
fucking balls from?
Out of the front row.
All the people who
are going to get you.
Um...
am sure that both the
FBI and the CIA is already,
they are already
working on the leads.
I think what they need
to look into is their origin.
One is in Boston.
Another one is,
of course,
in...
New Jersey,
Newark,
as I understand.
And I'm relying only
on the newscasts.
So they're already
trying to figure out.
I really believe
it will be solved.
It's too large of an operation.
Very sophisticated again.
But it will be
definitely solved.
What
does this tell us
about US security?
I do not believe that foolproof
security can be achieved.
What can be done,
however,
on this for me,
the puzzle here,
how possible four
jet blinders hijacked?
I'm hijacked.
just a...
Two or three minutes ago,
there was yet another
collapse or explosion.
I'm now out of sight.
A Good Samaritan has
taken me in on Duane Street.
But at a quarter to
eleven there was...
Another collapse or explosion following
the 1030 collapse of the second tower.
And a firefighter who rushed by
estimated that 50 stories went down.
The street filled with smoke was
like a forest fire roaring down a canyon.
Now,
as I think Patty Sabg
and others have told you,
all of Manhattan is covered,
downtown Manhattan is
covered with thick white ash.
Could you give me the
location of Chief Blach,
please?
We believe they're at the west
side of building number one,
on the west side of
building number one.
7-10-4,
be advised there's
several units with,
We're transmitting
out of ladder 124.
we don't...
We don't have a rig or anything.
We believe there are numerous
members trapped in the vicinity
of the west side of that
building in the collapse zone.
West side of building one.
That's the best
I can do for you.
I'm getting that from a member who is
trapped and unable to tell me where he is.
where he is.
He's in a vehicle?
I don't know that.
Calling Captain Fuentes.
What units do you have at
Broadway and VZ at this time?
Oh no,
Kay,
we're not sure.
You'll have to send
somebody over there.
Also,
be advised that we're in radio contact
with Captain Fuentes and his people.
They are trapped.
He's trying to
give me a location,
but he's unable to.
All right,
10-4,
like I said,
Chief Glace is on his way.
He's trying to
get into them now.
As soon as Mobile
Command sent a can,
we're going to head out
to Broadway and VZK.
calling
Captain Ford.
The Pentagon just turned black,
charred,
and then the flames came up.
We were all worried because
it was bumper-to-bumper traffic,
We were all worried because it was bumper-to-bumper traffic
and everybody stopped and everybody got out of their cars.
and everybody stopped,
and everybody
got out of their cars.
We were just worried if
there was another explosion,
it would just come and
shoot fire at us and
we would all be toast.
There was just nowhere to go.
Right.
I? Saw a plane coming
in from completely the
wrong direction flying
very very low and as soon
as I thought out my
window I knew it was headed
directly towards the
Potomac River and and I
and I saw it go right
into the Pentagon.
Could you describe
the size of that plane?
Do you know what
kind of a plane it was?
It looked like a
commuter-type plane.
It was larger than
the private planes,
which sometimes do
take a different air path.
get to the airport they
go a little bit around uh...
around about way to get into the
airport frequently this plane was
substantially larger than that flying
in substantially lower than anything
i've ever seen almost grazing the treetops out of my window here could
you feel the sound and sensation as the ground shook i could not i
crash and the billows of smoke,
which have not
yet subsided at all.
And so I'm actually just seeing the billows of smoke and the
mass exodus over Route 50 here with everyone fleeing town.
It's a bit of a harrowing sight.
This is the Queen of Queens.
Other unit calling Manhattan.
We have the collapse unit.
This is Captain Fuentes,
This is Captain Floyd.
There's a couple
other members here.
a couple other members,
I told them our mission
is to protect major centers.
We're going to take care of it.
We're gonna drag you down to Pittsburgh and
do this Because I got a tanker coming now,
there's still a bit
of traffic airborne,
they're not all completely down,
I imagine it's all
low south of you.
Let's move our hold to Luke
to confirm the tech or get back.
Oh shit,
I need a checklist Alpha
All right,
so we have help
on the way to you,
Cap.
We believe that you're in the west side
of the number one World Trade Center,
Number one World Trade Center.
out in front of
the collapse zone.
Out in front in
Is that correct?
All right,
In front of the collapse zone.
we're sending you some help.
All right,
10-4.
All right.
Sending you some help.
We're on our way.
Let them know.
Cap.
Stand by,
All right.
7 engine,
1 truck members are on the way,
and the staff chief is
aware of your location,
Captain.
So stand by.
We'll be there
in a little while.
I'll be there in a little while.
For you to call in.
Jack,
tell me what's going through your mind when
you hear the shooting that's happening.
When I first got
When I got on the scene,
it was like I've
never seen before.
People getting ready to,
helpless people at
the top of the building,
waving their hands,
ready to leap out
of the building,
overcome by smoke.
Um...
I got on the scene
and basically...
You see people jumping
out of the windows.
You know,
it's almost unreal when you're
looking through a camera,
when you're seeing
things happen and,
you know,
just so happened to be that way.
when the building collapsed,
we saw your footage,
you actually saw it.
What happened?
As the building collapsed,
I was maybe
200 feet from the building.
Rolling on the footage and
overwhelmed by feelings of...
Did you think this was it?
I thought it was it.
I was saying my prayers.
We were overcome by
blackness and smoke.
I was running from the building.
I didn't know what was
going to hit me in the back.
Basically,
I was just...
hanging on to it.
I was trying to
calm myself down,
hold on to my breath.
I was saying my prayers.
I thought it was it.
Good to see you alive.
you too.
Good?
Yeah,
good.
Alright.
Dave,
you and I and Jack and Keith were all in the middle of this thing when all of a sudden the building collapsed.
you and I and Jack and Keith,
we were all in the middle of this thing when all of a sudden the building collapsed.
What was going through your head?
I mean,
first of all,
I didn't think we were that close.
I didn't think we were that,
we were half a block from the building.
We were half a block from the scene.
from the scene,
but when this thunderous roar happened and the building started to come down,
when this thunderous roar happened and the building started to come down I thought we were far enough away next thing you know a plume of smoke just enveloped us which is like I mean once it turned black I don't know where to turn I couldn't see my hand in front of my face what were you thinking
I thought we were far enough away.
Next thing you know,
a plume of smoke just enveloped us,
which is like,
I mean,
once it turned black,
I don't know where to turn.
I couldn't see my hand in front of my face.
What were you thinking?
I was thinking I stayed here too long,
I'm thinking I stayed here too long,
way too long,
because I thought I was going to be able to run,
get away from the smoke,
but,
but
I mean,
I mean within seconds it had caught up to me,
within seconds it caught up to me,
enveloped me,
turned pitch black,
couldn't see my hand in front of my face,
and at that point I was way worried that I'd stay a little too long.
and at that point I was way worried that
I'd stayed a little too long.
Great footage,
Great footage though.
though.
Great footage,
but at what cost?
Now we're back here.
Have you ever seen the city look like this?
Have you ever seen a city look like this?
No.
No,
This is surreal.
this is surreal.
It's surreal.
I mean,
it's the only way to describe it.
It's surreal.
You can't walk into the streets.
It's a ghost town now.
It's very quiet,
contrary to what it was hours ago.
But
I don't think anyone in this country has seen anything like this.
Behind you,
there's no more town.
There's no town.
And unfortunately,
It's unfortunate.
A lot of people dead underneath the rubble.
a lot of people are dead underneath the rubber.
Good.
Chamber of Speed and Read.
Down towards the World Trade Center.
...towards the World Trade Center.
The World Trade Center collapsed about
20 minutes ago.
Bring a towel out of the way.
No,
we'll just put the back up behind you.
Touch your side.
More collapsing going on in here.
More collapsing going on you can hear.
In New York,
Allen Dodds Frank joins us on the phone in lower Manhattan.
Alan Dodds-Frank joins us on the phone in lower Manhattan.
Alan?
Allen?
Allen,
Alan,
just two or three minutes ago there was yet another collapse or explosion.
I'm now out of sight.
A Good Samaritan has taken me in on Duane Street.
But at a quarter to eleven there was...
But at a quarter to 11,
there was another collapse or explosion following the 1030 collapse of the second tower.
another collapse or explosion following the 1030 collapse of the second tower.
And a firefighter who rushed by us estimated that 50 stories went down.
And a firefighter who rushed by estimated that 50 stories went down.
The street.
The street filled with smoke was like a forest fire roaring down a canyon.
Now,
as I think Patty Sabga and others have told you,
as I think Patty Sabg and others have told you,
all of Manhattan is covered,
all of Manhattan is covered with...
downtown Manhattan is covered with thick white ash and building material.
Thick white ash and building material.
It's now 11 o'clock.
Division 6,
that's Division 1.
Have all officers report in when they park on Park Road to Chief Brandes.
Have all officers report in when they park on Park Row to Chief Brandes.
You got that,
man?
Okay.
K?
Rescue to rescue battalion.
Rescue the rescue battalion.
Everybody stand by unless urgent.
Urgent.
Go ahead,
urgent.
I'm trapped here because from the previous collapse.
I need to let you know,
I need to make sure that's okay.
okay?
Andrea and Mike,
Andre and Mike,
I'm here with a familiar face,
Mike Walder of USA Today.
Mike Waldron of USA Today.
Mike,
you actually saw this happen.
Tell us what you saw.
I did indeed,
Gordon.
You know,
like everyone else,
I was listening to the radio,
to the accounts of what was going on in New York.
I was listening to President Bush,
and we were stuck in traffic.
We're coming off the exit here,
and I looked up,
and I saw this American Airlines jet coming in very...
and I saw this American Airlines jet coming in very low,
And I watched it and it and it clipped,
and I watched it,
and it clipped.
I don't know if you can see it over here,
I don't know if you can see it over here.
it clipped this bowl over here.
It clipped this pole over here.
The emotion slammed right into the building,
huge explosion,
and then utter pandemonium as you might imagine.
and then utter pandemonium,
as you might imagine.
I mean,
everybody was screaming,
oh my God.
People started saying,
we've got to turn around.
we've got to turn around,
they hit the Pentagon.
They hit the Pentagon.
A frantic woman turned her car around and started weaving her way.
A frantic woman turned her car around and started weaving her way out.
out.
I got out of my car and went over here and we could see military personnel bringing tarps out and setting up like a triage unit,
I got out of my car and went over here,
and we could see military personnel bringing tarps out and setting up like a triage unit,
a number of stretchers.
You could hear fire engines,
just sirens,
sirens,
sirens as they arrived.
They started to hit the building with the foam,
They started to hit.
hit the building with the foam,
and actually were doing a pretty good job.
And then we saw the triage people with the stretchers running,
sprinting over here,
but at that point they moved us back,
and of course there was a threat of another plane coming here at that time.
I don't know what's happened with that.
Sir,
you know we're talking on the 129th.
I'm urgent.
I'm trapped here because from the previous collapse.
Go ahead,
urgent.
I'm trapped here because from the previous collapse.
I need to make sure that's okay.
I need to make sure that okay.
Are you at the west side of World Trade Center,
Are you at the west side of World
the building number one in the city of the street?
Trade Center,
the building number one in the city?
In the rear side of building number one.
number one all right 10-4 units that are responding in to assist the trapped members they now report to be in the rear of tower number one rear of power number one all units responding in to assist members who are trapped the rear of power number one are you sure it was an american airlines plane i would you know we were stuck in traffic could not move i could see the big aa the silver jet itself i thought it was a 737 i may be mistaken there
All units responding in to assist the trapped members are now reported to be in the rear of tower number one.
Rear of tower number one.
All units responding in to assist members who are trapped,
to rear of tower number one.
Are you sure it was an American Airlines plane?
You know,
we were stuck in traffic,
could not move.
I could see the big AA,
the silver jet itself.
I thought it was a 737.
I may be mistaken there.
But there was no doubt about it,
But there was no doubt about it.
It was an American Airlines slammed right into the building.
it was American Airlines slammed right into the building,
and there was no doubt about it,
And there was no doubt about it.
whoever was piloting that plane was aiming for the Pentagon.
piloting that plane was aiming for the Pentagon.
And we do know they hit a taxi cab.
And we do know they hit a taxi cab,
The plane hit a taxi cab up here on the bridge,
the plane hit a taxi cab up here on the bridge,
the overpass.
I didn't know that.
I didn't know that,
I did not see.
I did not see,
I saw the ball of fire,
and I saw it clip these poles,
and then the billowing smoke,
a gray column of smoke,
and then pandemonium.
Some fire.
Fire.
Is your car on fire?
Your car on fire.
Ashley,
tell us what you've seen and heard.
It's just been another explosion,
and,
as happened with the last two.
It may be a car bomb.
That's what we were hearing from passing police officers.
The last two were thought to be car bombs.
This third one,
I haven't had any confirmation on it yet.
But there is,
I mean,
the plumes of smoke have been so thick anyway.
Get out of here.
Oh,
we're on it!
We're still burning.
Oh,
you...
Better.
hold on a second.
You guys are going to see it.
All of you,
Hold on a second.
the empty command center.
Fighting the fire and dealing with the injury.
Gordon,
I talked to a staff sergeant who was in the building on the third floor.
He arrived for work probably around 745,
He arrived for work probably around 7.45,
and he said when it hit,
the doors to the offices flew open.
But he did say it was an orderly,
it wasn't chaotic,
it was an orderly transition out of the building and everyone got out.
All right,
Alright,
this is...
A new type of war.
That new type of war.
That's what it is.
Is today like the national terrorist day or something that we missed out on?
No,
actually this is the day we were on the line.
actually this is the day we were on the line on.
September 11th,
September 11th.
2001.
2001 That's another explosion.
It's another explosion.
Let's join MSNBC,
Let's
join MSNBC,
of course our sister network.
of course,
our sister network.
They have been following us all morning with us as well.
Let's listen in at the Pentagon.
10,000 people in each tower.
10,000 people in each house.
10,000 people in each tower would typically be in there on a normal business day.
And we get about another 5,000 visitors during the course of the entire day.
And we get about another 5,000.
visitors during the course of the entire day.
So by 8.30,
9 o'clock,
the building should have been full.
Okay,
so in other words,
by 8.30 to
by 8.30 to 9,
9, you figure the building would have been approaching full capacity with the workers.
you figure the building would have been approaching full capacity with the workers.
So we are talking about roughly 10,000 people per tower.
Was that the plane that is flying over Dulles Airport is a hijacked plane,
was that the plane that is flying over Dulles Airport is a hijacked plane,
they believe,
and it's surrounded by Air Force F-16s.
And...
And today is the anniversary of the Camp David Accords,
Today is the anniversary of the Camp David Accords where the United States and Israel really became tight.
where the United States and Israel really became tight.
Oh,
is that right?
So this is why today was chosen.
Yeah,
I knew there was some significance to today.
I have no idea what it was.
Yeah,
it was a big deal to them.
It's the arrogance of religion that's causing this.
Is that what it is?
Yeah,
they're doing this in the name of...
they're doing this in the name of
Allah. Yeah,
Allah.
Yeah,
I got something for Allah.
Now,
bin Laden has denied any involvement.
Yeah,
okay.
Right,
now nobody's taking responsibility for this.
Well,
you know what?
You know what?
Let's go get them anyway.
Let's go get him anyway.
You did this one,
I did this one,
you did others.
Yeah,
Get him on the way to...
Get them on the way to...
So you didn't do this one.
To get the real people.
Even he's afraid to take responsibility for this.
Well,
I think he's beginning to realize they missed their target,
and there's going to be retribution.
Yep.
I guess the next step is between the chief and myself and my staff.
We're going to go assess the condition and determine whether it's safe or not to send personnel into the building to continue looking and evacuating people.
Are there any emergency workers in there now?
We don't know that.
We don't know.
If they were in there now,
presumably they would have been trapped in there from the earlier...
It's possible.
It's possible from what we saw happen there.
Yeah,
very much so.
We were trapped ourselves in a building in a basement.
We were trapped ourselves in the building in the basement.
We were...
The building collapsed.
The building closed.
collapse when we came out of that but yes you were in the basement of the south tower we were in the basement of building five six okay and i was in building five we had to dig our way out to get dug your way out what was that like scary scary but i was a volunteer fireman for years so you learn not to panic we're going to move what was the one last thing what was we've just been able to get reporters
collapsed when we came out of that but yes you were in the basement of the south tower we were in the basement of building five six okay and i was in building five we had to dig our way out to get out you dug your way out what was that like scary scary but i was a volunteer fireman for years so you learn not to panic we're going to move what was the one last thing what was the just been able to get reporters
and photographers and people who work at the white house many of them running.
and photographers and people who work at the white house many of them running
From the scene concerned about this report of a plane,
from the scene concerned about this report of a plane.
and again,
And again,
I think that that threat has passed,
but the perimeter is now probably four blocks away from the White House in any given direction.
but the perimeter is now probably four blocks away.
The camera hooked up to
camera hooked up to uh ashley banfield and ashley tell us where you are and and what's happening i'm on uh west broadway right now uh it's kind of hard to say you know west
Ashley Banfield.
And Ashley,
tell us where you are and what's happening.
I'm on
West Broadway right now.
right now,
it's kind of hard to say,
you know,
West Broadway,
Broadway,
Reed Street,
but if you look down here,
follow me down,
you can see what it looks like finally,
Chris.
Down West Broadway,
into that plume of smoke,
that was where those World Trade Centers once stood.
And you can see people milling all about.
And you can see people milling all about,
Emergency vehicles are trying to get through this area.
emergency vehicles are trying to get through this area,
Police are trying to wrangle people to clear the way so that they can get through.
police are trying to wrangle people to clear the way so that they can get through.
Just look at the ground,
Just look at the ground.
Look at all the debris everywhere.
look at all the debris everywhere.
The dust,
The dust.
The mess.
the mess.
I just saw a shot from downtown right by the zone.
It looks like it snowed.
It looks like it's
It snowed.
There's so much soot.
It's thick,
inches thick on the ground.
They're all wearing gas masks.
My wife just got home,
thank God.
Yeah,
that soot is traveling through the sky.
I mean,
like,
I don't know.
It's like the ash from a volcano.
You don't want to breathe it.
It's toxic if you breathe it in.
Yeah,
the airport's completely shut down,
And the airport's completely shut down.
and they're searching cars,
And they're searching cars,
and the soot appears to be heading that way.
Is it Mr.
Borden?
You were in the area when this happened.
Tell me what happened.
I was walking by the building early in the morning and there was a loud cracking noise.
And all of a sudden this guy looked up and screamed and I thought he was joking.
And I looked up and all sorts of pieces of the building were coming off the building.
And so we started running and pieces of the building started falling like 20 foot in front of us and there was nowhere to go.
Did you get hit with anything?
No.
Did you run?
Yeah,
we ran and it fell under the thing.
And then we came back and we were walking around the other side and the other building blew.
And I pulled a woman underneath a truck because all the debris was falling down then.
And now they both collapsed.
There's no more World Trade Centers.
Marlo,
Marlo.
pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone.
Hey Howard,
Hey,
Howard.
I'm gonna have Marlo pick up.
Yeah.
I'm going to have Marlo pick up.
She just ran home from downtown.
She just ran home from a...
from downtown.
She said it's like...
She said it's like,
it's absolute chaos.
Where was she?
She was down in the 20s.
Howard,
Hello?
you're...
Molly,
Marlo,
you're on the air with Howard.
you're on the air.
Hey,
Hey Marlo.
Marlo.
Hello,
hi.
Where were you?
I was just walking back from the office,
I was just walking back from the office and I didn't even want to get into a cab.
and I didn't even want to get into a cab.
Actually,
there was,
um,
I don't know,
I think it was like,
um,
I don't know if the driver of the cab was,
Arab or whatever,
but some guy was punching the windshield of the,
the front of the,
I'm sorry,
I can't even breathe.
I can't even breathe,
I just walked in the door.
that just walked in the door.
Right.
Um,
It's mayhem outside.
it's...
mayhem outside.
People were punching the cab driver?
No,
not the cab driver,
but the windshield.
Oh,
they were attacking the cab.
they were attacking the cab?
He was trying to attack the cab driver.
The cab driver.
What?
The cab itself.
Because he was an Arab?
I think that...
I think that people probably thought,
that people probably thought it's a taxi,
it's a taxi,
it must be an Arab driving a taxi,
and let's attack the taxi.
I mean,
I would think...
Yeah,
I would think that ain't the right way to go.
that ain't the right way to go.
No,
exactly.
that ain't the right way to go.
That's what they would love.
They would love for this country to collapse in chaos.
Yeah,
we got to we got to we have to unite.
we have to unite.
We get united behind the president.
We get united behind the president,
no matter what you think of him,
No matter what you think of him.
And he's got to come up with the plan.
and he's got to come up with a plan,
And then let's hope that this dude comes up with the right plan.
and then let's hope that this dude comes up with the right plan.
And you all know what the plan is.
And what happened to you?
Was there emergency personnel who looked you over to help you out?
Did you just escape the area?
No,
I just walked around and see if anybody else is OK,
because I was OK.
This is where you work every day.
Yeah.
Down on Wall Street,
yeah,
on that shot.
All right,
thank you.
Just want to clear this area,
please.
They were heading into that area.
What's so frightening at this time is that we've heard three explosions since both towers collapsed.
I stopped another police officer,
he was a New York City police officer who was working traffic in this area,
to ask him if he'd heard over his radio transmissions whether in fact those were car bombs as well.
one officer had told me or whether he'd heard anything else.
He said he thought they were just residual collapse sounds and explosions that were just from the original collapse,
but we haven't had confirmation on that.
The first officer that I did get the information from that that was a car bomb looked as though he was an inspector,
plainclothes of some sort.
He had a radio as well and a cell phone.
It was walking right past me down this area and
I walked with him as he was talking on the cell phone.
I said,
what was it?
And he said,
car bomb.
And when I asked him to elaborate,
he said,
no time,
no time.
And he continued to walk forward.
The concern is that there are so many emergency...
Thank you.
We're down to Marine Battalion.
I'm in the Marine Battalion.
Alright,
urgent,
I got a trapped firefighter.
What's your version?
Anybody operating on the west side,
on the West Side Highway here,
on the west side highway here,
I got a member down.
I need some help,
anybody that's over here,
anybody that's over here searching with me.
start to with me.
Alright,
you're the person calling for help,
what's the IDK?
Identified.
Identify.
Marine Battalion Chief Fuentes is trapped.
Marine
Battalion Chief Pointe is trapped.
I have him.
It's Flatley for rescue.
It's Flatley from Rescue.
West side,
highway.
I need some help getting him out.
There's members over here.
I have no radio.
All right,
10-4.
We do have some units on the way over.
We do have some units on the way over there trying to assist you.
over there and try to assist you.
Marine nine should be back in a moment,
Marine 9,
it should be dark a moment,
Charlie.
Here again,
rescue personnel also on board.
Rescue personnel also on board.
Bye.
We also were able to interview a security guard who was working on the Concord in the plaza between the two oil trade centers when the first explosion happened,
when the first plane hit the first tower.
He said he was dispatched down to the concourse to clear people away and to try to move people out of the World Trade Center.
And then he said that's when the second explosion happened,
which of course was the second tower.
He said everything went pitch black.
pitch black.
It was a cloud of smoke and a cloud of debris.
When we happened upon him,
it was extremely strange.
He was all dressed in his black security uniform,
but he was fully covered from head to toe in gray and wandering aimlessly.
He said he was okay.
Hold on one second,
Ashley,
if you can,
because Pat Dawson...
Far from you is being asked to move.
All right,
Tom,
we have just,
we've just been told we're being evacuated.
You can see all the emergency workers walking north on the West Side Highway in New York.
We've been told by firefighters here that there is a report of a bomb in this building.
This is a school,
a high school right here.
And as you can see,
they're moving everybody away from this building.
They've said that there's a bomb in the building.
They are evacuating us north now.
That is according to firefighters on the scene.
And we're going to move out of here right now just to keep ourselves safe.
An FBI spokesman says the planes involved two American flights,
American Flight 11,
Boston to Los Angeles,
involved in hitting one of the trade towers.
Also,
American 77 was involved,
apparently one of the tax elites was hijacked.
We don't know where that plane ended up.
Two United airplanes,
United 175,
that was scheduled Boston to Los Angeles.
I just checked United's website.
That plane supposedly left Boston at 8.14 this morning Eastern Time.
Also,
United 93 from Newark.
to San Francisco.
According to the United website,
that plane left at 8.42.
We do not know,
except with American 11,
exactly which plane ended up where.
But according to the source and the FBI,
those are the four commercial planes that have been involved in what is going on today.
The fact of the matter is that there's so much information and there's so much chaos that we literally can't even,
we can't confirm anything,
we can't confirm anything.
we don't know what's going on.
We don't know what's going on.
It is so eerie looking outside,
It's so eerie looking outside.
I mean,
it is just dead.
The FDR drive is just,
there's not a car on it.
there's not a car on it,
The bridges are all completely,
the bridges are all completely,
there's nothing.
We're under attack.
Yeah.
It's so unbelievable that more things you keep hearing.
They're insane,
They're insane and we're fighting insane people and if you ever fight anyone who's insane,
and we're fighting insane people.
And if you ever fight anyone who's insane,
you know it's almost impossible.
There's nothing to do but shoot them.
Chuck,
go ahead and say something.
Rack 2,
acting as Rescue 2,
2nd Support Unit,
to Manhattan,
urgent.
Rescue 2,
Support Unit,
Rack 2.
urgent.
I am acting as Commander here to the Captain of Rescue 2.
I am acting as Com- I am here as the Captain of Rescue 2.
We have commandeered a city bus,
we have tools,
equipment,
18 men,
3 officers.
I'm currently at Vessi and at Park Row and in front of City Hall,
moving into the scene with members.
I have advised the captain that other trap members on the west side of the World Trade Center.
10-4,
you're responding over there.
you're responding over there,
10-4.
10-4?
Affirmative,
Affirmative.
I'm having a member...
directly of rescue right now.
10-4.
So we're going to start walking north ourselves,
but that's what we're being told by New York City firefighters here,
that there were reports of a bomb in that high school right there.
It's called Stuyvesant High School.
And so we are walking north to get out of the way.
You can see just to my left here,
these are the,
even the ambulances which were down there are being moved north.
The firefighters are being moved north.
Everybody is being moved north.
We're being asked by the police now to go north and get out of the way.
He said,
Is it officer?
officer.
Do you have any idea of what the problem is?
There's a report of a secondary device possibly in the area of this school,
so they're going to move everybody back as a precaution.
A secondary device meaning a bomb?
Secondary device meaning a bomb?
Possibly.
Okay,
and where did that report come from?
It came in over our radios,
and it's reported through our supervisors on down,
so we're pulling everybody back.
And that's in the Stuyvesant High School right there?
Yes.
Okay,
thank you very much,
Officer McQuaid.
That's Officer McQuaid of New York City Emergency Service.
Howard,
stay on the air,
bud.
You're doing a fantastic job.
Thank you.
So far,
L.A.
standing tall.
We're all deployed,
obviously,
watching you guys.
A Taliban news conference soon.
What is that?
What is a Taliban news conference,
Robin?
I have no idea.
That's,
That's what's it called?
what's that guy's been,
Bin Laden.
Laden?
I think that's Taliban.
Yeah,
A terrorist organization.
that's a terrorist organization.
I think they're going to call a press conference to deny any involvement.
Oh,
they're involved.
Don't buy it.
When you get your cameras in there,
shoot them.
Exactly.
Now,
we have been reporting another plane down some distance from Pittsburgh today.
According to reports,
and I want to stress this is coming from the affiliate there who got this in the scanner,
so let's put this in perspective.
But that plane believed it originated in Chicago and was headed to Cleveland with 90 people on board.
No word on the airline.
And I'm just seeing crossing the Associated Press wires now.
American Airlines says it has lost two aircraft carrying a total of 156 people.
planes were American Airlines flight number 11 and 77 and United Airlines flight number 175 and 93 and Scott
Planes were American Airlines flight number 11.
And 77 and United Airlines flight number 175 and 93 and Scott.
I just lost an 8200 lens.
Yeah.
Another explosion.
Oh,
I thought
I had one.
Did I hit something?
No,
it's closed.
I don't know if EMS is aging.
How much EMS staging is it?
1125 and it's black as night.
1125 and it's black as black.
Let's also look at some passenger cases.
Let's also look at some passenger counts from those planes.
...from those planes.
American Airlines Flight 11 was one of the ones believed to have crashed into the World Trade Center.
We believe it was a Boeing 767 with 81 passengers,
9 flight attendants and 2 pilots.
American Airlines Flight 77 was believed to be en route from Washington Dulles to Los Angeles.
American Airlines Flight 77 was believed...
To be en route from Washington Dulles to Los Angeles,
A Boeing 757 with 58 passengers,
Boeing 757 with 58 passengers,
4 flight attendants and 2 pilots.
United Flight 175,
there is no information at this time as to how many passengers were on board.
The other United plane involved,
number 93,
was believed to be en route from
Newark to San Francisco.
And this could be the plane,
this is believed to be the plane that crashed outside of Pittsburgh.
And we understand that about 9.58
And we understand that about 958.
Eastern Time,
this is being reported by WPXI television in Pittsburgh,
that a 911 center got a phone call from a cell phone from the plane,
that a 911 center got a phone call from a cell phone from the plane.
saying in fact that the plane was hijacked.
There was an explosion,
a cloud of white smoke,
a cloud of white smoke and of course the phone then went dead.
and of course the phone then went dead.
And Scott,
before we go to...
Rick Sanchez is in Lower Manhattan.
Rick?
Yeah,
there have been...
Lester,
am I on?
Is that you?
Yeah,
Rick,
go ahead.
Lester.
Yeah,
Lester,
there have been about four explosions here since about 11 o'clock.
The most recent,
about two minutes ago,
that seemed to shake the ground that we're on.
We're about a block and a half away from what used to be the World Trade Center.
The area is completely surrounded in soot and ash.
Firefighters and rescue officials are still really trying to get their act together.
They're not quite sure how to approach this situation.
They just did finally set up a command center.
It's going to be set up at the end of the day.
I'm going to go ahead and get out of here.
that the chamber
Sue,
let me mention that in about five minutes,
Thank you.
in about five minutes.
the Afghani ambassador representing the Taliban government is going to hold a news conference.
The Afghani ambassador representing the Taliban government is going to hold a news conference.
Sources in Afghanistan say that they will deny any link or knowledge that known terrorist Osama bin Laden would be involved.
And as far as they are concerned,
he is banned from carrying out activities against anyone.
Now,
we should take this with a huge grain of salt because there are administration officials who are saying that the only,
we should take this with a huge grain of salt because there are...
administration officials who are saying that the only if we are to believe that this is a coordinated attack and there really is no reason to believe it isn't given the timing of all of this today that administration officials are saying that it should be considered a coordinated attack on the scale that an organization put together by Osama bin Laden would be capable of carrying out if in fact that's what this is.
if we are to believe that this is a coordinated attack,
and there really is no reason to believe it isn't.
Given the timing of all of this today,
that administration officials are saying that it should be considered a coordinated attack on the scale that an organization put together by Osama Bin Laden would be capable of carrying out if in fact that's what this is.
American Airlines is...
American Airlines is now...
As they
try and work into the area,
what they're doing now,
Lester,
is lining up on some of the adjacent streets.
and setting up as what you know from covering stories like this,
field forces,
where they tell them,
don't go out and freelance.
Don't go out on your own.
Stay in a group.
We'll move into an area and we'll somehow move in little by little.
You're late.
...flights and diverted all international flights to Canada.
We've never had to take that kind of action before.
You know what?
It hasn't even sunk in with me yet.
It seems like you're watching a movie or something.
Yeah,
it hasn't even sunk in that the World Trade Center is gone.
It's Pearl Harbor.
That thousands of people are probably dead.
Tens of thousands.
Tens and tens.
Probably 50 plus,
I would say.
I would say at least.
I would say,
at least.
Yes,
and that the Pentagon,
and that the Pentagon...
God only knows what was going on there,
and who knows what else is going to happen next.
Well,
our government was attacked.
There's probably not one of us in this New York area or in this country who's not going to know someone who was killed in this.
I can start by telling you,
nothing's wrong with her,
but one of our interns,
one of our brand new interns,
was supposed to start today.
Her mom called to tell us she's being held in a garage in New York City because her building's gone.
Wow.
Ambulance for Command Post,
Manhattan.
Brooklyn to Manhattan,
urgent.
Brooklyn,
go.
I just had a report from
PD that they have a report of a bomb or a suspicious package that is in the Battery Tunnel at the present time.
Would you advise all companies to stay out of the tunnel until we get this cleared up from PD?
10-4.
All right,
attention all units,
attention all units.
we would avoid the Brooklyn Battery Term report on the point of the tunnel.
We're going to point to your Brooklyn Battery Tower reporting a fire on the tunnel.
Smoke I got when it collapsed.
Tell me about what you saw.
It just went from night to day instantaneously.
The whole sky turned black from day to night.
Tell me again what you saw.
It went from day to night instantly,
and the whole sky just turned black.
and the whole sky just turned black,
And a thick smoke that you couldn't breathe,
and a thick smoke that you couldn't breathe.
You had to go inside.
you had to go inside,
or you'd be choking.
And there were many people getting sick from the smoke.
You're lucky to be alive,
aren't you?
Yes,
I am very lucky to be alive.
I actually was at work late today.
If I had come in 15 minutes earlier,
I might have been in a lot worse shape.
That is good.
Larry,
that's great.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Meanwhile,
firefighters and rescue officials,
I just saw them come in as well.
They had what appeared to be PICS axes and other devices that they're going to be using perhaps to try and extricate people that might still be in there.
The items that they had were...
were handheld items that they were probably going to be using,
we would assume,
in some form,
to get into the area.
However,
at this point,
we're only about a block away,
and it does not appear that they're moving into the area.
Rick,
I'm going to interrupt you here.
You know,
I don't mean to blame anybody,
but,
you know,
it's funny because,
you think you're so safe in this country.
you think you're so safe in this country,
and we were taught when I was in the military that,
And we were taught when I was in the military that,
you know,
that the Air Force is always up in the air,
that the Air Force is always up in the air and there's always someone watching.
and there's always someone watching.
And for airplanes to just be hijacked in numbers like this and crash into our own populated areas.
Thank you very much.
Let me read from our hot file some new information coming in from two senior counterterrorism officials in the Clinton administration.
They tell NBC News that the only organization with motivation and capability to execute a terrorist mission like this is Osama bin Laden.
One official described this as the worst intelligence...
failure since Pearl Harbor,
noting these attacks take months,
if not years.
Well,
let me tell you something.
What we learned in Vietnam is when you're using guerrilla tactics,
it's impossible for the military to stop.
it's impossible for the military to stop you.
And remember the mistake in Vietnam.
We should have nuked those dudes and we never did.
We should have nuked those dudes,
and we never did.
And if we don't nuke some of these countries over there,
And if we don't nuke.
some of these countries over there.
I mean,
I mean literally nuke them,
literally nuke them.
Fry them.
fry them,
Fry their children.
fry their children,
Fry everything.
fry everything,
They will never stop.
they will never stop.
And I know it's an unpopular thing to do,
but you've got to be the strong one,
but you've got to be the strong one.
and Bush is going to have to make that decision.
And Bush is going to have to make that decision.
Target three countries over there and level them.
Yemen is one of them.
It's disintegrated.
Disintegrate it.
You know what it feels like now?
It feels almost like...
It feels almost like when we fought the British.
Remember when we fought the British?
It's like we're the Redcoats.
It's like we're the redcoats.
We're playing like idiots.
Yeah,
we're playing fair while gorillas are...
we're playing fair while guerrillas are...
Yeah,
we're standing in line waiting for people to shoot us.
military action has changed.
To plan and a large number of people joining us now on the telephone to talk about this
Lawrence Eagleberger is former Secretary of State under the Reagan administration
Mr. Secretary,
thank you.
What is your reaction?
Well,
you've said part of it already,
which is that this clearly is an intelligence failure of some magnitude
Although, you know,
the thing that I'm particularly
I thought the one thing we had under control was that people couldn't hijack aircraft in the U.S.
anymore,
but it's fairly clear now that that's also failed.
I thought we had that one pretty well licked,
but apparently we don't.
Osama bin Laden,
how hard is he to find,
to capture,
how elusive is he?
He's very elusive.
We've had a hard time tracking him,
having said that,
since I happen to believe that this now is his...
as much an act of war as anything,
I think it now becomes much more incumbent upon us to go massively against him,
not just try to find him,
but any place where he may have been,
and any government which may have housed him,
as far as I'm concerned,
now ought to be declared an enemy,
and we ought to declare ourselves at war with all of them,
and we ought to get massively engaged in cleaning it out,
even if we are not necessarily hitting precisely the people that did this.
I got Madison Wisconsin.
I'm just here to help.
Want to help?
What's on the counter?
We're just sitting here in shock.
You know how you see the pictures from like the Gaza Strip when there's a car bomb?
It's from like the Gaza Strip when there's a car bomb.
Yeah,
but it never feels real enough.
It's us.
Yeah,
now it feels real,
right?
It's the exact pictures you see from overseas that you just say,
oh my God,
you can't even imagine it.
This is us in New York City.
As someone said earlier today,
this is Israel every day.
That's right.
There are fires that have happened in the Pentagon before,
There are fires that have happened in the...
the Pentagon before,
certainly not from terrorist attacks.
And it's a very difficult situation to fight a fire in the Pentagon.
Again,
the largest office building I think it's been in the past.
the world's largest office building,
I think it's been called in the past.
And there's so many nooks and crannies that fire can get into.
And there are so many nooks and crannies that fire can get into.
And I'm sure that's a big problem here.
I'm sure that's a big problem here.
And as you saw earlier and can see now,
there's a gaping hole in the west side of the Pentagon where a great deal of fire continues to burn here at the E-ring,
the west side,
the west side near the heliport of the Pentagon.
near the heliport of the Pentagon.
But the biggest problem here is solid information.
As you can imagine,
you can imagine the line of communications are down.
the line of communications are down.
You talk about cell phones,
almost impossible to use.
Anybody out there is waiting for a call from a loved one,
Anybody out there who's waiting for a call from a loved one and you know they have a cell phone?
and you know they have a cell phone.
Be advised,
we have set up a Liberty Street Command,
we have set up a Liberty Street command,
commanded by Chief Mosier,
commanded by Chief Mosier and a church.
and a Church Street Command,
Church Street Command,
commanded by the Fort 2 Battalion.
commanded by the Fort Two Battalion.
We have seven teams at the Liberty Street Command.
We have a second alarm assignment that's going to report to the Fort 2 Battalion.
We have a second alarm assignment that's going to report to the Fort Two Battalion.
Have all other incoming units report to the staging area.
Also,
please contact the other command post on West Street.
please...
contact the other command post on West Street,
Advise them of our side.
advise them of our side.
I cannot contact them via handy talking.
I cannot contact them via handy talkie.
208,
208 to Manhattan,
come to that,
K.
Stock,
okay.
Charlie,
Scott,
to Manhattan,
K.
Charlie,
208,
come to that,
okay.
208,
I'm sending you a response in Manhattan's response area,
I'm sending you a response in that response area.
K.
All units stand by.
Manhattan is Division 6 acting,
Menandu,
this is Division 6 acting,
K.
Division 6 acting,
did you copy?
This is Division 6 acting.
we have a Liberty command post,
We have a Liberty command post.
we have a Church Street command post,
We have a Church Street command post.
The other staging areas,
The other staging area,
we're going to use Park.
we're going to use parkway.
Walk,
row,
investigate.
Pro-investigation.
Yes.
Fuck,
fuck.
NBC's Andrea Mitchell for more from your vantage point.
Andrea,
where are you and what can you contribute?
The State Department has been evacuated,
so I am here in the Washington Bureau.
And Secretary Eagleburger is exactly right.
right.
The view within this administration as within prior administrations is that this is an act of war and that they do have plans.
They have already,
within the last three weeks,
warned the Taliban government in Afghanistan that any act against the United States would be considered an act of war against the Taliban,
against Afghanistan,
or by the Taliban,
I should say,
and that retaliation would be done against Afghanistan.
You will recall that after the embassy bombings in Tanzania...
And in Kenya,
the U.S.
did retaliate against Afghanistan and did retaliate against Sudan.
That one,
the latter,
against Sudan,
highly controversial because there were suggestions that they didn't have adequate evidence that Sudan was really implicated.
Well,
here's Gary with something.
Go ahead.
On line two,
and I checked this out so it's for real,
is Congressman Gary Ackerman.
He's from the 5th District of New York.
Yeah,
we know Gary Ackerman.
He got a briefing from somebody and he wanted to come on the air and talk.
Hi,
Congressman.
Congressman?
I don't think I have him.
Yes.
Oh,
hi.
Hi.
What'd you hear?
It's an absolute nightmare.
This is going to go down as Black Tuesday and it's going to change each of our personal lives as well as our civilization forever.
This is going to go down as Black Tuesday,
and it's going to change each of our personal lives as well as our civilization forever.
You're not kidding.
The way we do business,
who we do business with,
our security precautions that we're going to have to take.
I think this is driven home in the most dramatic way that anybody with a suit and a blue tie can get on a plane and do all kinds of damage almost at will.
Congressman,
were you briefed in any way on this?
No.
No,
Everybody who is supposed to be in secure places right now is there.
everybody who is supposed to be in secure places right now is there.
We've closed down the whole Capitol.
I'm in New York.
I stayed here for the primary,
I stayed here for the primary and I was going to go down a little later.
and I was going to go down a little later.
Right.
And I just voted.
Of course,
the election has now been called off.
The Director of Central Intelligence is in meetings with his top officials,
not in his normal operations center,
not in his office,
but in a special secure location.
The State Department Operations Center has been moved out of its location to another location in Virginia.
Mr.
Secretary Lawrence Agleberger,
you're still with us.
If you are,
what happens?
You've worked for a great many years in government.
What happens in the Situation Room?
What does the president do with his advisors?
Well,
listen.
you know,
assuming that this president acts like most presidents,
he will gather them together and he'll ask for advice.
And in the last analysis,
he will make up his mind on what ought to be done.
He'll have to hear from his military advisors on what is available to react.
He'll have to hear from Secretary Powell on how you deal with the other governments around the world to explain what it is we're doing,
assuming we decide to do something.
And by the way,
I hope more than what we did.
when we responded to some of the last time.
The retaliation has to be massive,
and I might say,
I don't care very much about which terrorist...
they're going after.
If they are clearly terrorists and they are antagonistic to the U.S.,
they ought to be considered,
although it is also true that Osama bin Laden ought to be target number one.
Nobody knows ahead of time which one he's going to be at.
Brian,
you want to say something?
Go ahead.
Yeah,
they just reported that there was 164 people killed on the plane crashes into the
World Trade Center.
Right.
That's on one of the planes.
That's on the plane.
One plane.
On one plane.
On one plane there were 164 people.
So we were planes full of passengers.
We're going to be talking in terms of thousands of people.
Tens of thousands.
Anybody within the sound of your voice,
and that's millions of people.
Stay keyed up on the next tub as I keep losing you.
Fake heat up on the next tub as I keep losing you.
3,
2,
1.
You're on.
2,
1.
You're on.
We apologize.
Having some technical difficulties getting cells down here because a good deal of our cell transmission come from the top of the World Trade Center.
And you can see the black smoke continues.
I'm going to give you a live picture down Church Street.
Fire crews now walking back toward the scene.
We have seen them all morning trying to walk away because what happens is every time a little piece of the building comes down...
We have seen them all morning trying to walk away because what happens is every time a little piece of the building comes down,
a huge black cloud comes at us,
A huge black cloud comes at us,
making it almost impossible to breathe or see anything in front of them.
But now,
at least for the past couple of minutes,
it has been clear from this space back on chambers in that area.
So now they're walking back toward the World Trade Center.
And as we keep letting you hear the personal stories,
the survivor stories,
the survivor stories of exactly what happened inside the World Trade Center when that first plane went in,
of exactly what happened inside the World Trade Center when that first plane went in,
And,
and of course the collapses since then,
of course,
the collapses since then.
We're going to bring more of those to you now.
we're going to bring more of those to you now.
Barry Jennings,
you were on the 8th floor.
you're on the eighth floor.
You worked for the City Housing Department.
You work for the City Housing Department.
Explain to me the moment of impact.
Well,
me and Mr.
Hesch,
the corporation counsel,
the Corporation Counsel,
were on the 23rd floor.
I told them we got to get out of here.
I told them we've got to get out of here.
We started walking down the stairs.
We made it to the 8th floor.
Big explosion.
Blew us back into the 8th floor.
And I turned to Hesch.
I said,
this is it.
We're dead.
We're not going to make it out of here.
I took a fire extinguisher and I bust the window out.
I took a fire extinguisher,
and I bust the window out.
That's when this gentleman here heard my cries for help.
This gentleman here heard my cries for help.
This gentleman right here,
and he kept saying,
stand by,
Stand by,
somebody's coming to get you.
They couldn't get to us for an hour because they couldn't find us.
You thought that was it?
I thought we were dead.
I thought that was it.
I started praying to Allah,
I said that's it,
I said,
that's it,
we're going.
we're gone.
What was it like for you?
You were inside there as well.
It was pandemonium.
I mean,
it was something like out of a
Bruce Willis Die Hard movie.
He was there and he was crying and there was another gentleman crying and for help.
He was there and he was crying,
and there was another gentleman crying,
and for help,
We couldn't get to him.
we couldn't get to him.
We tried to get through the,
we went through the buildings.
we went through the buildings,
We were lost.
we were lost.
Both staircases,
the backside was completely blown away.
There was no way to access it.
We couldn't get to them.
We couldn't get to him.
And finally,
and finally
one of the fire department teams found them.
One of the fire department teams found them.
But we didn't think they were going to make it.
Well,
certainly you got out.
Many others didn't,
of course.
Eagleburger,
and let me read from Reuters,
Mr.
Secretary.
Quote,
it is most likely the work of Islamic fundamentalists.
Osama bin Laden warned three weeks ago that he would attack...
American interests in an unprecedented attack,
a very big one.
This according to the editor of the London-based Arab newspaper.
Mr.
Secretary,
given that the warning was well known,
and certainly
American intelligence must have known about it,
and given the fact that we knew that Osama bin Laden favors the use of aircraft,
And has launched a couple of attacks,
one of which was actually defeated before it took place through intelligence.
How is it we could not have known about this?
Is no longer,
It's no longer,
at least not like we knew it.
This man just embraced.
This man is crying.
It has been that traumatic.
I don't want to cry on the air,
man.
I thought that was it.
I thought I was dead.
I'm thinking about my sons,
you know,
my wife.
It's too much.
And certainly,
he echoes the statements of many others.
We were speaking with a couple of officials earlier,
trying to get information.
They said,
stand back,
we lost a bunch of guys today.
It has certainly been a horrible...
In fact,
let me come around right here as this happens.
They're now clearing the area.
They're trying to evacuate the area because certainly they don't know what's going to happen next.
Well,
I think that's fairly understandable.
You said or somebody said that this was highly sophisticated and very well planned,
and I think that's true,
including,
obviously,
the ability to keep the thing quiet,
and obviously also...
It required a great deal of money,
which leads you again back to Osama bin Laden.
The one thing I don't understand,
and it's critical to the rest of this,
I guess,
is,
as I said,
I thought we had licked the problem of hijacked aircraft in this country.
It can only tell me that there was really sloppy procedures.
Felipe Iola was on the
81st floor when a plane struck the tower.
He is on the phone with us now.
Were you in the first or the second tower,
sir?
I was in the second.
Tell us what you saw and heard and what happened.
I was actually on 81 and two world trade and then an explosion and it was in one world trade and I saw the flames.
I ran down to 78 which is the main concourse where I met up with my wife and co-workers and then I was asked to go back upstairs because it was safe and the problem was only in one world trade.
And then when I went upstairs I left my wife there and told her it was okay.
I went up to 81.
I was looking out the window with a co-worker of mine as another explosion happened and the entire room just collapsed on me.
And I was able to find stairs and
I can't find my wife and I'm looking around now for her.
So if she's listening,
I just want to let her know that I'm okay and I'm trying to find her.
Well,
this is the worst I've ever seen.
Is that what's left of it?
That's what's left of it?
Yep.
Is that all?
Is that power?
Chris,
I'm looking at the airplanes involved here and have concluded just based on the information that in air traffic control centers,
they must have known something was up.
Let's take,
for example,
the American Flight 11.
It's a 767 going from Boston to
L.A. New York City is not one of the places it will cross over on that flight.
That plane at some point left its flight path.
The other American flight,
American 77,
that was going from Washington Dulles to LA.
American says it was involved in the World Trade Center attack.
Again,
New York is not between
Dulles and Los Angeles,
so once again this is a plane that controllers would have seen veer.
from its flight path.
The
United flight,
the one we believe down in western Pennsylvania,
that one,
that would have been on its flight path.
But those two that involved the New York attack would suggest...
that warning bells were going off somewhere.
They may not have known the intentions,
but they knew something was going wrong with those airplanes with some lead time.
Thank you.
Can you hear us,
Teresa Ward?
We seem to have...
Peter Esmantle for CND3.
Hi,
Teresa?
Yes,
hi.
Hi,
this is Chris Jansing at MSNBC.
I understand that you were in the second building when the first one collapsed.
Is that right?
I was in the second building when the plane hit.
What can you tell us about what you saw and heard?
Well,
I was at my desk.
just starting my day,
and we felt a shudder.
The entire building sort of shuddered.
And at first we didn't really think,
we sort of didn't know what happened,
and we looked out the window and there was just debris and papers like a ticker tape parade falling from the sky.
And immediately we just,
everybody calmly walked down the stairs,
and a lot of people who had already been part of the original bombing were there with us and we all calmly
started exiting the building.
And then we heard an announcement that there was an incident in one World Trade Center,
but two World Trade Centers were just fine so we could return to our offices.
So we then took the elevator down and clearly that was not correct.
And as soon as I got out of the building,
I could see that there was a second explosion because there was just burning debris coming.
Down,
showering on us,
and we had to run for cover,
and then they rushed us back into the concourse,
and we were able to exit the other way.
And by the time I got up to
Houston Street,
I turned around and you could see that Two World Trade Center was just a cloud of smoke.
Thank you.
So you had been told to go back to your offices,
but you made the decision to leave the building?
Yeah.
Obviously a...
At that point,
though,
there was only an incident in One World Trade Center,
and no one really knew what the incident was.
And you mentioned that you were with people who were there during the other attack,
which you're talking about the 1993 bombing.
What was the conversation?
What were people saying?
What were they doing as you were getting out of the building?
You know,
we were just calmly walking down the stairs thinking,
you know,
what the heck happened?
You know,
somebody said a plane hit the building.
Another person said a bomb.
We really had no clue what was happening.
So everybody was relatively calm having been through the experience of...
The first one and there wasn't any smoke in the stairwells this time or anything like that so the the mood was was very calm and we were able to get out but we got out right away as soon as the as soon as we felt the shutter of the first explosion so we
were very very fortunate.
I understand.
Listen,
everyone go north.
What happened?
What happened here?
Dude,
man,
that guy's thing's gone.
it got things gone.
It blew up.
I don't know.
I came down.
I'm alive.
I just want to know if my wife is alive.
I was on 82.
82?
Yeah.
How'd you come down the stairs?
How'd you come down?
The stairs?
Stairs.
What was that like?
Panic?
No,
it was calm.
it was kind of...
Until I got down.
Then the top came down.
What was that like when the top came down?
All right,
Look at me,
look at me,
man.
It was fucking frightening.
It was frightening as all hell.
Come on.
The loud rumble?
Tell me about that.
I don't know.
I don't remember anything after that.
I just crawled out.
But I lost my people.
I don't know where they are.
Hang in there,
man.
All right.
We'll let it make our right.
All right,
whoa,
All right?
We'll let him make it all right,
Thank you so much.
all right?
We're going worldwide.
We're Reuters television.
We're Reuters Television.
Yeah,
See,
I was here when they blew up the parking garage.
I was here when they blew up the parking garage system.
This is the other one.
No,
the other one back there.
the other one.
No,
back there,
yeah.
Chief Albert Turi told me that he was here just literally 10 or 15 minutes after the events that took place this morning,
Chief
Albert Turi told me that he was here just literally 10 or 15 minutes after the events that took place this morning.
that is the first crash.
That is the first crash.
He said that at one point he had roughly 10 alarms,
He said that at one point he had roughly 10 alarms.
That would equate to roughly 200 to 225 New York City firefighters who were in the building.
that would equate to roughly 200 to 225 New York City firefighters who were in the building.
This was after the crash,
trying to rescue civilians who were in there.
Now,
earlier this morning on the Today Show,
earlier this morning on the Today Show...
we spoke to the director of the World Trade Center.
We spoke to the director of the World Trade Center.
He said that at that hour of the morning,
you could have upwards of 10,000 people in each of those towers.
That would be 20,000 people total in each tower.
Okay.
So tell me,
where did you see me?
where does TV tell me?
Tell me what happened?
What happened?
What did you see?
Up near the top of the building,
Up near the top of the building there was,
there was a...
off to the,
as I was facing the building this way,
As I was facing the building this way,
to the left hand corner,
to the left-hand corner,
there was flames coming out of the side of the building,
there was like flames coming out of the side of the building and then it started to spark,
and then it started to spark,
and then there was an explosion,
and then it all became smoke.
And it was just dust and clouds everywhere?
It was just dust and clouds everywhere?
Dust and clouds everywhere.
I mean,
look around the street.
This is what's left of the building,
I guess.
We were talking about,
you think there's a chance for people on the street?
I'm sure,
I'm sure.
Rescue workers,
people that might have still been in the building.
It looked like the whole top of the building came down.
How many floors can you tell?
Probably the top 40 floors,
yeah,
yeah.
Because it was up that high.
because it was up that high.
What's your name?
Don Hallacy.
How do you spell that?
H-A-L-A-S-Y.
Photographer with the Post.
Yeah,
New York Post,
man.
The chief of safety,
Yeah,
New York Post,
man.
the chief safety of the fire department of New York City told me that shortly after 9 o'clock he had roughly 10 alarms,
The chief of safety of the fire department of New York City told me that...
Shortly after 9 o'clock,
he had roughly 10 alarms,
roughly 200 men in the building,
roughly 200 men in the building trying to effect rescues.
trying to effect rescues of some of those civilians who were in there.
of some of those civilians who were in there,
and that basically he received word of the possibility of a secondary device.
And that basically,
he received word of the possibility of a secondary device.
That is another bomb going off.
off.
He tried to get his men out as quickly as he could,
but he said that there was another explosion which took place.
And then an hour after the first hit here,
the first crash that took place,
he said there was another explosion that took place in one of the towers here.
he said,
there was another explosion that took place in one of the towers here.
So obviously,
So,
And obviously,
according to his theory,
he thinks that there were actually devices that were planted in the building.
One of the secondary devices he thinks that took place after the initial impact was,
he thinks may have been on the plane that crashed into one of the towers.
The second device he thinks,
he speculates,
was probably planted in the building.
So that's what we have been told by
Albert Turrey,
who is the chief of safety for the New York City
Fire Department.
He told me that just moments ago.
Now,
we are continuing to hear explosions.
We are continuing to hear explosions here downtown.
we are continuing to hear explosions here downtown that's right i'm standing here right now i'll just go broadway by city hall with michael has to be cities corporation council mister have you were trapped in i believe that a world trade center go ahead that i was i was up in the emergency management center of the twenty third floor and when all the power went out of the building another
That's right.
I'm standing here right now just off Broadway by City Hall with Michael Hess,
who is the city's corporation counsel.
Mr.
Hess,
you were trapped in,
I believe,
7th World Trade Center.
Go ahead,
sir.
Yes,
I was.
I was up in the Emergency Management Center on the
23rd floor.
And when all the power went out in the building,
another gentleman and I walked down to the 8th floor where there was an explosion.
gentleman and i walked down to the eight where there was an explosion and we've been trapped on the eighth floor with smoke thick smoke all around
And we'd been trapped on the 8th floor with smoke,
thick smoke,
all around us for about an hour and a half.
around us for about an hour and a half.
But the New York Fire Department,
but the New York Fire Department,
as terrific as they are,
just can't do it.
just came and got us out.
came and got us out.
Why did you happen to be at that particular place when the explosions took place?
Well,
the Emergency Management Center is where city officials go when there is any emergency such as this one.
How do you feel that the OME,
the Emergency Management,
the emergency management,
is going to be handling the situation?
It seems like they're still trying to arrange triage.
It seems like they're still trying to arrange triage areas and areas of command and setup.
...areas and areas of command and setup.
Where will they be now?
I don't know where the centers will be,
but obviously the mayor and
Commissioner Shira of
OEM are watching the situation carefully,
taking all the...
taking all the right moves,
right move,
and everything's under control.
Where is the mayor located now?
I don't know myself.
I don't know.
Myself,
As I say,
as I say,
I was trapped in Seven World Trade Center for the last hour and a half.
Thank you very much.
That's Michael Hess.
That's Michael Hesse,
He is the City Corporation Counsel who was trapped over by Seven World Trade Center.
the city corporation counsel who was trapped over by Seven World Trade Center.
This is Frank Uciardo reporting live from Lower Broadway,
This is Frank Isiardo reporting live from Lower Broadway,
right down the Boston City Hall.
All right,
Frank,
stay with us on the phone here for...
stay with us on the phone here for a moment.
Their lives,
wreck their lives for once.
wreck their lives for once,
Allow us...
allow us,
whether you need Israel to do it or the United States to do it,
Whether you need Israel to do it or the United States to do it,
I don't care which.
You know,
to me,
that alone is a reason to bomb them.
Allow us to bomb them.
They're out in the streets,
They're out in the streets.
Throw a bomb on them right now.
throw a bomb on them right now.
Bomb them now in the streets.
Bomb them now in the street.
How would they have kids in the street,
How would they have kids in the streets,
five years old,
jumping up and down celebrating?
Five-year-olds.
Those five-year-olds will grow up to attack our children.
I can't be showing it right now.
Kill them.
Kill them for celebrating.
In their schools,
at five years old,
they're being in doubt.
Here they are.
They're all celebrating in the streets.
The Palestinians are celebrating in the streets,
ladies and gentlemen.
They're putting up the victory sign.
Children are cheering.
The Port Authority police chief told us that they were at that point about,
The Port Authority police chief told us.
that they were at that point about,
I'd say 40 minutes ago,
I'd say,
40 minutes ago,
about to make a decision on whether or not it was safe to send emergency workers back in there.
But the bottom line is that according to the chief of safety of the New York City Fire Department,
he says that he probably lost a great many men in those secondary explosions,
he says that he probably lost a great many men.
in those secondary explosions and he said that there were literally hundreds if not thousands of people in those two towers when the explosions took place.
and he said that there were literally hundreds,
if not thousands,
of people in those two towers when the explosions took place.
He said everything above the 60th floor was extremely difficult to get to as you can imagine.
He said everything above the 60th floor.
It was extremely difficult to get to,
as you can imagine.
Pat Dawson.
Back to you.
Pat Dawson,
thanks very much.
The force of the blast broke my eyes.
They were around here.
And right there,
landing on the tower,
you can see.
The parents have taught them well.
Let them all live.
Go ahead.
Go ahead and more of us will die.
I think you know what Bush needs to do.
I mean,
he needs to grow a Senate,
you know what?
We all know what needs to be done.
If Bush doesn't do it,
he's gone.
We have to get a new president.
We've got to get a new president.
He's got to get a new president.
He hasn't said much,
really,
Bush,
but wait for him to come on and say,
I mean...
Look at them celebrating in the streets.
And this is why I say you cannot negotiate with these people.
This is why I say you cannot negotiate with these people.
They are so happy.
They are so happy,
They're so insane.
they're so insane.
Today,
drop the nuclear bomb on them.
drop the nuclear bomb on them!
There's no reason for those people.
Give them nuclear warfare.
It's the only thing they understand.
Like the bastard children they are.
This is terrible.
I can't even believe that.
I think it's great you guys are still on the air,
though.
I'm getting too worked up and I'm starting to say stuff.
Yeah,
I really want to say nasty,
awful things.
I know how this is getting me worked up.
I'm worked up.
I'm so pumped up.
Somebody said to me earlier,
where do you think it's safer?
I said,
I don't care about safety at this point.
They're bombing my country.
Revenge.
That's it.
Revenge is going to be sweet.
The thought that these people are celebrating the death of others.
This thought that these people are celebrating the death of others.
Please,
please,
please do something.
do something.
This is horrible.
I'm sick of seeing it.
It's one thing to strike military targets,
but when you strike the heart of a city like New York...
but when you strike the heart of a city like New York,
and you strike the World Trade...
I'm sick of looking at them.
I'm sick of looking at them celebrate.
I can't imagine these little school kids.
They probably don't even know what's happening.
They're all celebrating.
They are taught to hate...
They are taught to hate America at the youngest age.
America at the youngest age.
And they're going to grow up and kill our children.
They're going to be worse than the parents.
It's time to stop the madness now.
They do it in schools.
It's organized.
The teacher stands at the front of the classroom and says,
this is a country and a people you should hate.
This is a country and a people you should hate.
Tell us where you are
and what the latest is.
Well,
I'm in that area,
if you're familiar
with this area,
of where West Broadway and Hudson
come together right at Chambers.
That would put us
about a block and a half
away from the site of
where the explosion...
That area has just been
evacuated because police
have found what they
describe as a suspicious device,
and they fear that it might be something
that could lead to another explosion.
Obviously,
there's a real sense of...
caution here on
the part of police.
I spoke with some police
officials moments ago,
Chris,
and they told me that
they have reason to believe
that one of the explosions
at the World Trade Center,
aside from the ones that
may have been caused
by the impact of the
plane with the building,
may have been caused by a
van that was parked in the building
that may have had some
type of explosive device in it.
So their fear is that there
may have explosive device
planted either in the building
or in the adjacent area.
And that's why they're being so
cautious in this vicinity right now.
You know,
For Reuters,
it's saying that,
I guess,
an Arab journalist who has access to bin
Laden interviewed him three weeks ago,
and he warned of an
unprecedented attack on the U.S.
interest for support of Israel.
Right.
There you go.
That's enough for me.
They said earlier that he's
saying it had nothing to do with it.
you think he's a brave man,
Tom? no,
clearly not.
But this is a journalist who claims
he interviewed him three weeks ago.
So for Reuters.
Pat, hi,
you're on the air.
You know what?
Honestly...
Guys like Bin Laden
say this all the time and
it doesn't necessarily
ever come to fruition.
but the point is I'm
crediting him with this attack.
No, totally.
You know he did this.
Yeah,
Pat,
go ahead.
This is what
they're trying to do.
They're trying to set up several field
forces to go into command centers.
Some of them have been set up,
but it's really
still preliminary.
This is why it's so difficult for
them in this area where we are.
Imagine,
they came here originally to...
deal with the crisis they set up
some command centers and they had
many of their chiefs and many of
their supervisors in the area of the
building the second and third
explosions literally have wreaked havoc on
those field forces and those command
centers so they've had to back up
and now they're trying to see
how they can approach it again.
They are enlisting the
support of doctors in this area.
One,
a medical conference that happened
to be down the street in Manhattan.
Surgeons from all over the country that
happened to be here in New York City.
They've gone to the hotel,
put them on a bus,
and they've just brought
them into this area,
and they're going to be assisting in this
triage unit that they're hoping to set up.
We're still not sure that they've
actually been able to set it up,
but to be perfectly
honest with you,
Chris,
It appears to us,
looking at it here firsthand,
that officers and...
and rescue officials are really
having an uphill time trying
to figure out exactly how they're
going to attack this problem.
Um,
Yeah,
hi Howard.
Um,
I was doing work on a
rooftop in Jersey City,
and we didn't
see the first crash,
but we saw the smoke.
and as we were watching,
I saw a plane coming in from
about three or four miles out.
Wow.
And I commented to the
other guys on the roof.
I'm sorry,
but I commented to the
other guys on the roof.
and I said to him,
you know,
hey,
look at this plane,
you know,
coming in pretty close
too and I just said,
oh my God,
it's going to hit
it and as I said it,
And as I said,
it just,
it just hit it.
It hit the second tower.
Well,
you're never going to get
that image out of your head.
Yeah, it
And when it hit,
you saw the fireball go past it.
Awful.
It's just awful.
And it's just ridiculous.
We've been too lenient with
these people for way too long.
We have.
That is the truth.
And that's the problem.
You look at our
own backyard stuff.
I've been on radio 20 years.
I've been screaming about that the
chickens were going to come home to roost.
You look in your own
backyard what we do to our
own people and we just
smack them on the wrist.
These people don't
even belong here.
No.
And we let them get away.
Our society has
become too lenient.
But we've also ceased to be
amazed that people will actually...
launch an attack in which
they know they will be killed.
That is not amazing
to us anymore.
Yeah,
we have to just
level them all out.
Elizabeth,
you're on the air.
Yes,
I happen to be thanking my
blessings right now at my grandparents'
house.
I was in my office when I saw the flying
balls of fire and debris after a car crash.
I worked in Two
World Trade Center.
You were in the
World Trade Center?
Yes,
in the Two World
Trade Center on the
35th floor.
You were on the
And what happened
when the plane hit?
How did you get out?
When the plane hit, it hit one
but we thought it
was another building.
We never had an idea that it
was the World Trade Center.
We only saw flying debris,
glass,
and balls of fire
hitting our offices.
At that point,
we were told to go to the lobby for
a fire drill to evacuate the building.
like for a fire drill,
to evacuate the building.
I was fortunate for
whatever given reason,
somebody dragged me
into the freight elevator
what happens to be
right there at that moment.
When we got in
the freight elevator,
the mechanic told
the guy operating it,
hurry up and push the down
button because this elevator
is going to stop the
minute there's a fire in here.
Wow.
I'm watching the
floors coming down,
35,
34,
and made it to 1.
I said,
thank God.
Open the door.
I ran out to the concourse,
the World Trade
Center concourse.
and all I see was mobs of people
running and the cops telling us to...
Be cautious,
but go ahead and
run out of the building.
I kept on running out of D.C.
Street all the way
up to Chamber Street.
Good for you.
And then because when
I got to Chamber Street,
good thing I work out.
I'm very healthy.
Right.
You were able to run.
I know.
I heard a boom.
And when I turned around,
I said,
oh,
my God,
there's my tower.
That was two World Trade.
Oh,
my God.
I got hit.
At which point...
Let me ask you something.
How many people were
at work on your floor?
Let me tell you another thing.
My floor,
my co-workers are the actual
victims of the first bombing.
They were in B1 level when the actual
bombing happened back in the 90s.
So when you say you got out,
there was a lot of
people still on the floor,
There was a lot of people because there
was one space in the freight elevator.
I don't know who
pulled me in there.
And usually the elevators
stop because there's a fire.
They automatically stop.
Well,
you were real lucky.
I have no idea how
lucky I really am.
Oh,
my God.
What was your job at
the World Trade Center?
I was actually the sign and the coordinator
for all the signs and all the...
The directories of the
World Trade Center.
I work for the Port Authority.
You work for the building,
the World Trade Center.
For the Port Authority.
Right.
Oh my God.
You are so lucky.
Quick update on the
plane crash here in our area.
It was United 757.
We don't know how
many people are on board.
We have to assume the worst
given the pictures we've seen there
and the accounts of the scene
of a crater in the ground and very,
very little in the
way of debris.
Rick Earl just telling us.
The largest piece they
found is about five feet long.
There is again shots
of New York as the,
unbelievably.
I think that's the first tower
that was hit first collapsing,
but the second one to collapse.
And the
Pittsburgh incident that
they were describing,
United Airlines Flight 93,
a 757.
So devastated,
I'm so devastated.
the towers are gone.
Everything's gone.
I don't know what
happens tomorrow.
Well,
there's got to be retribution.
I see.
Not even retribution.
for self-preservation,
we must attack.
I tell you,
this is ridiculous.
And I said it at 9 o'clock in the
morning when I first saw the news.
I said,
now it is their excuse.
Now you finally
have been pushed.
I mean, really?
Now let's not stop.
I would love to know what
they're saying in Europe now.
All the people who always say,
The rest of the world
is laughing at us.
How about,
I don't even care.
I don't even care
what Europe's saying.
I'm saying,
now we have to make a decision.
Yes we do.
We know the countries
that harbor terrorists.
Don't wait to even find
out who is responsible.
Why even let them
into this country?
We should stop letting
people in already.
It's enough immigration.
We've got too many people here.
The mayor says he
arrived at the World Trade
Center building just
moments after the first
blast and witnessed people jumping from their
window- from the windows to their deaths.
Oh.
Wow.
Imagine jumping out of
the World Trade Center.
No,
and there's no way
of surviving that.
Well,
we're going to go now.
There's not much
more to be said.
You guys can tune to TV
and radio and everything else,
and
I'm just devastated by this.
We'll be doing
what you're doing.
Yep,
we'll all be sitting around
waiting to hear what goes on.
You know,
this is a great day in the
Arab lands.
They're cheering for us.
Let it be the start of the
worst moment of their lives.
Yeah.
Let this be the day
that we woke up.
Please.
You know,
much like when the Japanese had struck
their blow against the United States,
it was just the
beginning of the end.
It was the beginning
of their nightmare.
Let's hope this is the
beginning of the end.
I think this is
the wake-up call,
unfortunately.
It's an unfortunate
wake-up call,
but it's here.
I guess we would never really...
Because the world has been
plagued with this long enough,
obviously.
Let's free the
world of terrorists.
It's time to do it now.
It's going to take about a
month to really nuclear attack
them and do it in a devastating
way where they don't live.
So that maybe only a roach
will live in these Arab lands.
Alright,
Rick,
I held up the Redmond
Hart Commission that
said we were going
to get attacked like this.
We were a sitting duck
for a terrorist attack.
It would hit hard
and it would hit soon.
Where did we fail?
I don't think that we
necessarily did fail.
This is a very free nation.
There's no nation in the
world where you can travel
about and do the things that
you do in the United States.
Today is the day
that we must wake up.
I don't think I'm being
irresponsible by saying that.
Absolutely not.
This was,
if this doesn't wake us up,
you know,
this is affecting
our way of life.
They want to take our
way of life away from us.
As we sit here now,
we don't even know who is alive
and who is dead in our personal lives.
We don't,
especially those of us
who live here in Manhattan.
And just imagine
if we capitulate,
how our lives will be
affected from now on.
I'll leave you with this,
the military is at full threat
level and we'll see what happens.
That doesn't mean
we're attacking anybody.
No, No.
it just means that
we're on full alert.
which means nothing.
Like we're waiting
for another blow.
Yeah.
We might catch it.
How happy were you
yesterday now looking back?
What does that mean?
Meaning just,
you know,
you don't...
You were carefree.
Yeah.
Well,
and we shouldn't have been.
I mean...
Because today was coming.
For 20 years I've been
on the radio saying this.
And I'm not saying...
I remember you saying this when
we first started working together.
And I was like,
Yeah.
Stop it.
I know,
And I've been saying it.
I said the chickens
will come home to roost.
It's going to happen,
And we should really
wipe out terrorism now.
But we were afraid of
what France will say.
The intelligence
community regularly gets all
types of information
regarding potential threats.
There is,
however,
a chasm between
freedom of speech,
where people talk
about doing things,
and the actual acts themselves.
And it's frequently impossible to discern
whether someone is merely talking or,
in fact,
is planning to do some
sort of terrorist event.
I suspect that if we had any sort of
information at all regarding this in advance,
that it was still
being evaluated.
We did,
and let me turn to Joe Canameza,
Rick,
if you'll hang on
for just a moment.
It was reported three weeks
ago by the editor of an Arab
newspaper that Osama bin
Laden planned this kind of an attack.
Very soon,
he said it would be an
unprecedented attack.
Over
to Lester Holt.
Lester?
Greg,
we are getting an idea of what air traffic
controllers may have seen this morning.
The first indication
something was happening.
We are going to show
you with Flight Explorer.
That's American Flight 11,
Boston to LA.
going up upstate New York
and suddenly makes a sharp turn,
180-degree heading,
heading right toward
New York City.
That's probably at least a
20-30-minute flight there.
The controllers know this plane
is not only slightly off course,
way off course.
This,
again,
from Flight Explorer,
as that plane was being tracked,
there it makes that sharp turn,
way off course,
on a beeline to New York City,
where it slammed into one of the
World Trade Center towers today.
Good smear it.
Look at this,
Yeah.
That plane was scheduled to leave
about 7.45 from Boston this morning.
It's not clear if that's the
one you're seeing there.
Remember,
two airplanes hit separate towers
and were not clear of the order yet.
But this is something
I pointed out earlier,
that there was indications
a good time before these
attacks that something
horrible was happening.
What would an air controller
do in a case like this?
not a lot.
You could be making radio
call after radio call to the
plane when you decide
he's not listening or ignoring.
All you can do is get on
the horn to other planes,
clear out of the way.
We don't know where
this guy is going.
Clearly,
he was dropping in altitude as
well as he's making this approach.
This was a plane that
would have then come
straight into the Newark
International Airspace,
LaGuardia,
JFK,
all in that area.
So clearly,
other planes had to have been aware
that there was a rogue airplane in the sky.
American Airlines only given us a brief
statement saying it lost two airplanes.
We don't know the nature of any conversations
that took place between the crew,
between the air
traffic controllers.
They also have their own private
data links between the cockpit
and the airline headquarters when
they have a mechanical problem.
An airplane can squawk,
what's called squawk,
a certain code
on its transponder.
That lights up at the
air traffic control center.
It's a code that says
I'm being hijacked.
There's no voice communications.
But if the pilot can somehow
serotopously punch in that code,
it would alert someone to at
least know this plane is in trouble.
We are in the airport.
It's now about 12.30.
It's the hole in
the sky where the
World Trade
Center used to stand.
Crossed over the wires,
a Navy public affairs spokesperson
telling a Washington network
affiliate television station that
there are dead inside the Pentagon.
One of these hijacked
planes came crashing down in
what appears to be a
glancing blow on the Pentagon.
In fact,
NBC's Jay Barbary spoke to a
friend who works in the Pentagon.
who believe that the pilot appeared to make
a deliberate nosedive into the pad area,
the helipad area,
in a way to avoid the
heart of the Pentagon,
and perhaps it could have
been a heroic act by the pilot.
From this friend of Jay
Barber's vantage point,
the damage done to the Pentagon
came really from the plane's debris,
so not a direct hit,
perhaps a last-minute
effort by a pilot under
incredible duress to save
as many lives as possible.
David,
I want to go to a graphic that
our viewers just saw on our air,
and let's try to coordinate
this while you talk.
You can explain
what we're seeing.
This is from the
website Flight Tracker,
which every commercial aircraft,
every jet aircraft
has a transponder,
which is then traced by
global positioning system.
This is the American
Airlines flight out of Boston.
And,
David,
what are we watching here?
Right.
This is something
I sent over to you,
Flight Explorer,
which developed this.
out in Virginia
sent this over to me.
They reconstructed this.
This is the flight track
of American Airlines.
flight number 11 as it came out of Boston
and was heading on its route to Los Angeles.
You'll see four lines there.
The top line is
the airline number,
American Airlines
flight number 11.
The next line,
the left number,
is the altitude at
which the aircraft is at.
The right number in that
second line is the airspeed.
The third line shows
the originating point,
Boston,
and its scheduled
destination point,
Los Angeles.
The last line shows
the aircraft type,
in this case a Boeing 767-200,
and the proposed arrival time
in Los Angeles in eastern time,
at that point,
149.
As we track the
airplane out of Boston,
it seems to be making a normal
departure out of the Boston area.
I know your screen shows
beyond this at this point.
When it gets back to Boston,
let's start again.
It's coming out of Boston,
turns west,
going through
western Massachusetts,
going into upstate
New York above Albany and it
makes a very hard left turn there.
Now the folks at Flight
Tracker have indicated
to me that that plane
made that turn at 828 a.m.
according to the data
they received from the FAA.
The flight coordinates
We're 42.8 north,
74.15 west.
Now what's also quite interesting
in this tracking is you'll see that
when the airplane did come out of
Boston and start heading out west,
it was climbing.
to twenty nine thousand feet
apparently on its way to a higher
altitude on that classic northern
route by the way david that
would have taken it across
the continent right and up over
chicago perhaps and down into
los angeles great circle route right
What we start to notice,
and I've had a chance to be
able to look at this at some time,
Brian,
it was at a steady cruising
speed of about 457 knots.
Just before or apparently
around the time of the hijacking,
the speed gets very erratic.
It goes to 427 knots,
drops about 100 knots
down to 340 knots.
Maybe that's when they were
getting control of the airplane.
Back up to 470 knots,
up to 495 knots,
up over 500 knots.
Thank you.
493,
441,
407,
396,
390 knots,
and then finally
on the last readout,
313 knots.
This is quite a
dramatic picture.
And you know,
Brian,
that we would have not seen
any kind of tracking like this coming
out of an NTSB investigation for
months and months and months.
That's right,
and that's the advantage here.
It's ghoulish,
but we get to see what happened.
And
I don't know if people can
appreciate how severe a turn that is.
is on an aircraft that big and to go from
456 to 340 in terms of speed while turning,
it must have been an emergency.
And,
of course,
now we know.
David,
we'll return to this
topic in one second.
Hold there with me.
Okay.
A man in a white car,
who is in a hurry
to go to the hospital,
was taken to the hospital by a man
who was in a hurry to go to the hospital.
The man was taken to the hospital by a man
This brings us back
to David Stempler.
David,
four people,
and perhaps more than that,
got on four commercial
flights this morning,
diverted them,
killed themselves,
and everyone on board.
What does that mean to you?
Have we lost David Stentler?
Brian?
Yes,
David.
Yes.
I don't know how we can
assess this at this point,
and I'll tell you why.
What we have,
and the kind of domestic
airline security that we have,
is really set up to
manage a hijacked...
situation using
metal type weapons,
whether it's guns or knives.
I talked with a security
colleague this morning.
What could have happened
is you could have put 10,
15,
20 people on this airplane.
They could have overpowered.
any amount of people without
any guns or any weapons.
But I would assume that what has happened
here is that these were not the pilots,
the American or
United Airlines pilots.
I believe that those pilots were
taken out somehow and placed in the
seats were these terrorist pilots who
actually focused on these buildings.
So I don't know how you deal with that
kind of threat assessment at this point.
Airport outside Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania.
An earlier report that an aircraft had
crashed into Camp David has now been put down.
This is a picture of the
wreckage near Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania.
We also cannot forget that
the most crushing human drama
is taking place at this
hour in the city of New York.
What side of the overpass?
It's been theorized that
because of just how these planes
acted today that it would
have taken more even then uh...
someone with a gun
to the head of the pilot
To make a commercial airline
pilot aim for and blow through,
for starters,
one of the two towers of
the Twin Towers in New York,
that they had to be
overpowered and replaced,
and that adds yet another dimension
to what we're covering here today,
that these hijackers
were perhaps,
some would say,
were likely trained
commercial airline pilots,
and flying aircraft the size
we're talking about today.
is not a skill possessed by every person
walking around the face of the earth.
Wait a minute.
Paul Begala is with us today,
and for all the wrong reasons.
Paul,
what did you see?
Where were you?
Brian,
I was on the Boundary
Channel Drive,
which runs northeast
of the Pentagon,
along the Potomac River,
alongside one of
the parking lots.
And I was looking over at the
building and thinking about...
about those counterterrorism
folks who were going to be meeting
there in the tank as I was
driving to a meeting on Capitol Hill.
And as I looked at the building,
I didn't see any aircraft,
but I saw an enormous fireball,
red and orange
fireball that shot at least
twice the height of
the building into the air.
That was then followed,
of course,
by huge plumes of
thick black smoke.
Two other men were
driving alongside me,
and they pulled over as I did.
One of them,
they were on their cell
phones immediately.
One of them said he thought
maybe it was a chopper.
And I do know
there's a helipad there.
I've landed on it.
And I hoped against hope
that it was just an accident,
not an attack.
Another man who was
beside me was on a phone.
He looked for all
the world to be a trim,
young fighter pilot.
He said,
no,
we're under attack.
We're going to war.
And he sped off
into the parking lot.
Mayor Giuliani is
with us at the moment.
Mr. Mayor,
can you hear me?
I can,
Peter.
Mr. Mayor,
I saw you several
times on the street today,
and it looked like you were deeply
sharing the horror that all of us feel.
But I'd really appreciate,
aside from on top of your
sentiments about all this,
give us some sense
of what's going on.
What is going on now is
a massive rescue effort.
We have thousands of police
officers and firefighters in all of
Manhattan trying to rescue as
many people as we possibly can.
There are still a lot of
people there that are injured,
hurt,
dazed,
and we're trying
to get them out.
And we're mobilizing
all of our fire,
police,
and emergency
resources to do that.
The governor has
alerted the National Guard,
and they're being deployed to come and
relieve us early to later this afternoon.
And the urban search and
rescue teams are coming
here from around the
country to also assist us.
But until then,
which means until probably 2,
3,
4 o'clock this afternoon,
our police department,
our fire department,
and our emergency people
are being stretched out.
to the limit and i'm sure we've
also lost a significant number of
them and we were in a building
in which we were trapped for about
10-15 minutes are you talking about the
uh did you go immediately to the office of
emergency management i i went down to
the scene and we set up headquarters at 75
We were told that the World
Trade Center was going to collapse.
And it did collapse before we
could actually get out of the building.
So we were trapped
in the building for 10,
15 minutes and finally
found an exit and got out,
walked north,
and took a lot
of people with us.
My question is the Office of Emergency
Management headquarters into
which you put enormous effort for
coordination in a disaster like this,
has it been damaged?
Is it still operating?
It's gone?
It's been damaged.
I don't know how badly.
and right now that
whole area of Manhattan
including the police department,
which is another area
we would operate from,
City Hall is another area
have been closed off.
So we've moved to a
secure location in midtown
Manhattan where we're
operating city government.
A terrible,
terrible tragedy has
befallen my nation,
but it has befallen all
the nations of this region,
all the nations of the world,
and befallen all those
who believe in democracy.
Once again,
we see terrorism,
we see terrorists,
people who don't
believe in democracy,
people who believe that with
the destruction of buildings,
with the murder of people,
they can somehow
achieve a political purpose.
They can destroy buildings,
they can kill people,
and we will...
be saddened by this tragedy,
but they will never be allowed
to kill the spirit of democracy.
They cannot destroy our society.
They cannot destroy
our belief in the...
Democratic way.
What you thought at
the time about all this?
I thought that
I would never live to
see anything like this.
I didn't think anything
like this was possible.
When I first arrived there,
I rushed down there from
midtown Manhattan and I
saw the first building that
had been crashed open.
And when you look at it,
it takes you a minute to really
comprehend that this is actually happening.
and to see people jumping from
the top of the World Trade Center.
I don't think I've ever had a
nightmare that's worse than this.
Mr. Mayor,
one last question.
You said you never believed
you'd live to see anything like this,
and yet in the past you've
been one of the leaders
in preparing for just this
kind of thing to happen.
Yeah,
but you prepare for the worst,
but you don't believe
that it'll happen,
and this is the worst.
And
I can only say that
I thank God for the police department
and the fire department that we have,
because this would be much,
much worse.
Obviously.
We're joined also in
the studio this morning,
or this afternoon rather,
by Bill Heitman,
who was in one of the
towers when this happened.
And Bill,
after hearing Jim Hoffer
and seeing him running
from the scene there
as the building collapsed,
I was wondering,
as you were trying to get out,
you were in the darkened
stairwell for an hour,
did it ever cross your mind
that the building might collapse?
Absolutely not.
As a matter of fact,
there was good
spirit in the stairwell.
I mean,
I can honestly say we
were having some laughs.
You know,
we were just getting down,
making the best of it.
Some people had to...
it was more urgent
for them to get down,
so we would all call out,
move to the right,
and they would proceed down.
But there was no panic,
and there was generally,
considering the circumstances,
good spirit in the stairwell.
Again,
as you said earlier,
it didn't seem to be as
bad as the other explosion,
the first explosion.
Absolutely not.
So no clue and no panic
as you were going down.
No panic.
The thought of the
building collapsing or
being in any more danger
never crossed my mind.
And then, Bill,
you said it wasn't.
Sorry.
Jim,
I'm sorry to interrupt because I want to
just point out in this live picture here,
what you're looking at is
damage to an adjoining building.
Obviously,
the impact of this.
not just to those twin towers,
but also to adjoining buildings.
And it looks
like there is still,
obviously,
smoke,
and I think I saw some
flames there as well,
Jim.
So clearly there
is still damage.
They're all bunched up so
closely together down there,
obviously,
and there was bound
to be collateral damage
in the neighboring
businesses and buildings.
Bill,
as you were going down
that darkened stairwell,
and you say you had no thought
that the building might collapse,
was that because you had
faith in the integrity of the
building or simply because you
did not know what was going on?
I had no idea the magnitude
of the crash above us.
We didn't know anything
had happened over in two.
We thought it was
just us and one.
And as the further we got down,
you figure you're 94s
away from the worst of it.
I figured when we came out
into the concourse level of the
building that everything would
appear to be relatively normal.
But when we got down
into the concourse level,
which is very much
like a shopping mall,
it was just flooded.
And emergency
personnel were very,
very urgently trying to
get us out of the building.
So were people milling around down there
trying to check on others in the building?
No,
as soon as you came
out of the stairwell,
there was great urgency.
just...
Personnel just,
just go that way,
go that way,
get out,
and everybody was just
walking through water.
Sir,
can I ask you to stand
by for just a moment?
So much smoke.
We want to go now to the firefighter who was
on the scene and hear what he has to say.
I saw people originally coming
out the window and I was,
at that time I was
quite upset about it,
that
I thought we
should get in there.
But then the
explosion on the South,
World Trade Center,
happened and I said this
is something we have to do,
we have to back out.
We backed out over
here and even then,
I saw the squad again
in the second explosion.
...as possible.
You're looking at a live picture
from Newscopter 7 right now,
and of course you can see that
there is fire in adjacent buildings.
There is problems,
serious problems,
still in that area down
in Lower Manhattan.
We're up to the elevator.
The 24th floor,
as soon as we get up there,
the elevator,
the elevator get out.
Power,
we lost power in the elevator.
Thank God we kept one of
the truck guys there and he
forced the door and then we
walked away down the stairs.
As we came down the stairs,
we were just dragging
people along with us.
And then when we came outside,
it just blew,
the tower blew and I found the
mask on the floor as I was crawling.
Do you know anything
about the cause of the
explosions that brought
the two buildings down yet?
Was it caused by the
planes or by something else?
We believe that it
was caused by the after
effects of the planes
hitting the buildings.
We don't know of an
additional explosion after that.
It's weird.
Could you tell us,
do you expect any further
attacks on New York?
Is there anything to indicate
that there could be more bombs,
more planes out there?
I know originally there was a report
that eight planes had been hijacked,
four have only
been accounted for.
What about the remaining four,
and is there any possibility that
there could be bombs on the ground?
We have no specific
information to that effect.
Do we know anything about the composition
of that dust that flag was blown in half?
Is there any asbestos or any
hazardous material in that dust?
I don't know.
I don't know the answer to that.
Mr. Mayor,
are you aware of a gas
explosion related to this?
There was a gas
leak or possible...
We don't believe
that's the case.
Mr. Mayor,
can you tell us anything about
where the planes come from,
where the aircraft came from?
Bill Diamond reminds me that we've
turned off the gas in the city buildings,
just to be certain.
Can you...
Somebody got a stuck mic.
And now we join
Paddy O'Connell again in New York with
the latest news of what's happening there.
Paddy.
I think David what's becoming
clear is that this is not over.
That is to say,
if you look at the
pictures of Manhattan,
downtown where it happened,
the mayor has evacuated
part of Lower Manhattan.
That will be no surprise,
but if you think back
a step as to why,
it's because buildings
remain unstable.
This is the scene around
the building that collapsed,
but the question being
asked is what about the
buildings that were
standing immediately after it?
Now I don't, I don't,
where I'm sitting in
midtown Manhattan,
have an answer to that question,
but I'm afraid this question is
the one that's preoccupying us
because underneath the rubble
is the answer to the question.
How many people
have lost their lives?
we know there are disgusted
people all across this country,
and here there are
people trying to get home.
But as I speak to you,
David,
we don't know the answer to the
question of the scale of the human tragedy.
The analysis,
important as it is,
will be had,
but the figures on people,
we just don't know.
And what sort of flow
of information is there?
You say nothing is really known,
but is everybody,
Is information still coming out from
the World Trade Centre down there?
We have an unconfirmed
report of a building collapse.
In times like this you want to hear
directly from the city authorities.
I passed one of the major
hospitals four hours ago.
They were shouting for
blood donations in the street.
We have an unconfirmed
report of a building collapse.
In times like this you want to hear
directly from the city authorities.
We'll leave it there
for the moment.
We've got some news
just coming in actually.
That the
Salomon Brothers
building in New York,
right in the heart of Manhattan,
has also collapsed.
This does fit in with a warning
from the British Foreign Office a
couple of hours ago to British
citizens that there is a real risk.
Let me get the exact words.
The British Foreign Office,
the Foreign Department
of the British Government,
said there was a strong risk of
further atrocities in the United States.
And it does seem as if
there now is another one
with the Salomon
Brothers building collapsing.
We've got no word
yet on casualties.
One assumes that the building
would have been virtually deserted.
Whether this latest collapse is
going to influence the President,
who we heard about a few
moments ago was expected
to be heading from
Nebraska back to Washington,
we don't know.
Okay,
let's go.
No, no.
Go low to the corner.
Very difficult to breathe here,
Car after car after car.
Behind me, Behind me.
That gave me hope.
That's where one
of the two towers are.
It's not that.
It's a real environment.
It's almost impossible to track.
We have to make
a more correlation.
I'd like to say somebody
declared shoreline.
It's certainly a good start,
We're off to the side.
Ready?
Are we ready?
We are in an abandoned skyscraper and quite
frankly I don't even know where I'm at.
I see a sign outside that just gives
me a reference to Barclay Street.
As you can see all around here,
The windows have been
blown completely out.
And as we take a
walk towards the front,
towards the front
of the building here,
you want to take a look outside.
If you have never been to war,
like I have never been to war,
then this is what it looks like.
We don't know
what that building is.
where this building is.
But they're obviously on fire.
Maybe there's a chance
that they could collapse.
I've been on this
earth for 37 years.
I've never been to a war.
But I can only imagine that
this is as close as I've ever come.
Now more on the latest
building collapse in New York.
You might have heard a few
moments ago I was talking
about the Salomon
Brothers building collapsing.
And indeed it has.
Apparently that's only a few
hundred yards away from where the
World Trade Center towers were.
And it seems that this was
not a result of a new attack.
It was because the building had been
weakened during this morning's attacks.
We'll probably find out more now
about that from our correspondent,
Jane Stanley.
Jane,
what more can you tell us about the
Salomon Brothers building and its collapse?
Well,
only really what
you already know.
Details are very,
very sketchy.
There's almost a
sense downtown in
New York,
behind me,
down by the World Trade Center,
of just an area completely closed off
as the rescue workers try to do their job.
But this isn't the first building
that has suffered as a result.
We know that part of the
Marriott Hotel next to the
World Trade Center also
collapsed as a result of this.
Huge amount of falling
debris from 110 floors of
the two twin towers of
the World Trade Center.
As you can see behind me,
the
Trade Center appears
to be still burning.
We see these huge
clouds of smoke and ash.
And we know that behind that,
there's an empty piece
of what was a very familiar
New York skyline,
a symbol of the financial
prosperity of this city,
but completely disappeared.
The transmitter is
is off,
right?
There's things up
there right there.
What's he doing up there?
What are you doing up there?
I'm just fucking out there.
I'm just going to
go and park there.
whoa,
and then moments later I saw
that first tower collapse on itself.
Did you see anybody jumping?
I didn't see that.
What's your name, sir?
Michael.
I'm with the Connecticut Post.
let me ask you a question.
What does a fire safety
director do in a situation like this?
Actually...
I'm responsible for evacuating a
building that was a serious emergency.
Did you evacuate the building?
Yeah,
we did.
How many people was that?
Well,
it was like early in
the day we made the
decision to evacuate
after the first tower fell.
How long did it take
you to get people out?
Actually,
people started on their own,
so they started to just
kind of leave naturally.
But regarding the exact time,
I don't really remember what time
we even decided to clear the building.
Let's go to Emma's room.
Come here.
Get in the chair.
Is it still out there?
I'm right here.
Joining me is Jack Kelly.
Now,
he is a foreign correspondent,
war correspondent,
and just came back from Israel.
He has some information
about these attacks.
Jack,
what can you tell us
happened first in New York?
Apparently,
what appears to happen was that at
the same time two planes hit the building,
that the FBI most likely
thinks that there was a car or
truck packed with explosives
underneath the buildings,
which also exploded
at the same time.
and brought both of them down.
Now,
that's the first time
we're hearing that.
So two planes and explosives
that were in the building,
is that correct?
That is the working
theory at this point.
That is still unconfirmed,
but that is what the FBI
is going on at this point.
Let's go to 1010 Winds
reporter Eileen LaPalmer.
Eileen?
All right,
Ralph,
I'm here on Hudson Street.
As you've been hearing,
that Seven World Trade Center
just collapsed about five minutes ago.
suddenly we saw officers,
tons and tons of them,
maybe 100 officers,
police officers,
running north,
running along Hudson Street,
telling people to move,
get out of the way.
Again,
the smoke was billowing north,
and people were running.
I'm here with an
emergency worker.
He's a first-year
NYU medical student.
He was down there.
He was trying to help people.
His name is Daryl.
Yeah,
so I was just standing there,
you know,
we were watching the building
actually because it was on fire,
the bottom floors of the
building were on fire and,
you know,
we heard this sound that
sounded like a clap of thunder.
We turned around we were shocked
to see that the building was uh well it
the windows all uh busted out
then you know it was horrifying and
then uh you know about a second
later the bottom floor caved out
out and the building
followed after that and we saw
the building crash down
all the way to the ground.
You know,
we were in shock and
then the worst part about it,
we saw the smoke and the
plumes of smoke coming after
us and we had to run
north actually on that street.
We just ran north to
escape from the smoke and
luckily we weren't hurt
but it was certainly very,
very scary.
that was about it.
Okay,
and Daryl and his friends,
they are NYU medical students,
they are going to go back and help
with the emergency situation again.
Eileen LaPalmer,
1010 Winds,
live on Hudson Street.
Now Jack,
as these battleships
are headed out,
does this mean war?
Lawrence Eagleburger,
the former Secretary of State,
just told us that this is a declaration
of war as far as he is concerned.
He said this is the
biggest attack against the
U.S. since Pearl Harbor
more than 60 years ago.
Osama bin Laden appears to be
the number one suspect at this point,
though nobody will go
on the record and say this.
Only Osama bin Laden has the sophistication
to carry off a multiple coordinated attack.
I've sat with his people
and they've said that
this is something that
they would like to do.
As recently as just a
month and a half ago or so,
isn't that correct,
when you sat with
Osama bin Laden's people?
In Dubai and one of
them at that point said that
they were considering
more attacks against the US.
Also what's interesting,
three weeks ago a US official warned
the Taliban through a third person
that should there be any more attacks
that the US would respond militarily.
At this point now
the Pentagon...
And CIA and the FBI
have identified a possible
100 targets within Afghanistan
to possibly strike back.
that could possibly strike back.
We are now preparing for war.
Is that what I'm understanding?
That nobody will actually
state that at this point,
but there are always
situations ready and battle
plans ready just in case
something were to happen.
You know,
this has been warned
for quite some time.
It's just a matter of
when it would take place,
and it took place today.
There we can see what looks
like the Salomon Brothers building,
which is the third building,
which is just about to
collapse in these pictures.
They came in just
a few moments ago.
It's 47 stories high.
The World Trade Center
towers were 110 stories high.
And this building appears to
have been weakened by debris
or perhaps parts of the
plane from the initial crash.
You can see the
building go there.
And you can also imagine
the difficulties faced by
the emergency services
on the streets of Manhattan.
All right,
Jeff Rawson,
Lower Manhattan,
has an update for us.
Jeff.
And Roz,
last time we spoke
there was a collapse,
a building collapse.
We understand now it
was World Trade Center,
building number seven.
We were being evacuated live on
television and we want to let you know,
first of all,
everyone in our crew is okay.
everyone in the
area here is okay.
You can look at our live truck.
That's where we had
to abandon it just down
the street as we broadcast
these live pictures.
And beyond that,
you can see the smoke billowing.
Certainly there was smoke before
because that building was on fire.
But since the collapse,
we could literally
see the smoke,
the dark cloud of smoke
and dust coming down the
corridor of buildings down
Church Street toward us.
At that very same moment,
police started
evacuating everybody.
And this is where
we all are right now,
Evacuated back here to
Jwain Street at Church,
And you can see all these people
were about a block up with us.
But when that
building collapsed,
you heard another tremble,
kind of like this morning
when those two planes went
into it and then the
subsequent building collapses.
This sounded a lot like that.
And then all of a sudden we looked
over and we saw the smoke coming at us.
Right now we can tell
you that the paramedics,
the fire officials,
all emergency workers
trying to do a head count,
trying to figure out if everyone inside
that building fighting that fire is okay.
We will certainly bring that
information to you as we get it.
Live in Lower Manhattan,
Jeff Ross in ABC7
Eyewitness News.
Thank you,
Jeff.
Al Jones just saw building number
seven go down at the World Trade Center.
It's collapsed Al.
You know we've seen so much today with
the collapse of number one and number two.
we've seen so much today with the
collapse of number one and number two.
Folks standing here on the corner of
Leonard Street and West Broadway.
We're just sitting here watching all the
smoke pouring up from number seven.
Number 7 is the kind of
reddish-brown building
that's towards the
north end of the complex.
And although we really
couldn't see much damage on it,
there was smoke pouring
out of it here for hours.
And folks just kind of
standing around milling about it.
And then I wasn't watching.
I just could tell
from the reaction.
reaction of the crowd what had happened
because I'd heard it already before.
The gasp,
the screams,
people immediately turning
and starting to run even though
we're probably a dozen
blocks from the center itself.
People starting to run away
from the scene and I turned
in time to see what looked
like a skyscraper implosion.
Looked like it had been
done by a demolition crew.
The whole thing just
collapsing down on itself
and another big huge
plume of gray and white
smoke shooting up into the air and then more
of the smoke billowing up the street here.
So that's number one,
number two,
and now number six.
seven that have come down
from this explosion and uh folks just
simply can't believe it well i
didn't realize because the other
towers are so big but the number
seven is 47 story that was a
That was a huge
building in its own right.
huge building in its own right
right it was always it was the
one that kind of uh was dwarfed
by the other two it was kind of
a reddish brown and it uh more
or less ran east and west it was
a long thin building but uh uh
it had been damaged and it had
been on fire for hours uh and
the smoke just seemed to intensify,
But we really couldn't see a
lot of damage from this angle.
from the north side
of the structures.
That's why everybody was so surprised
when all of a sudden it just fell.
Now,
the other thing,
too,
we presume it has been
burning for some time.
As you indicated,
there was nobody inside,
and we hope no danger to
anybody when it went down.
Well,
that's the thing,
is that when number
two went down,
you know,
I don't think,
and I know I'll put
myself in that group,
I never thought these
things would fall down.
I mean,
we were watching them.
You could see them burning.
A lot of it was damaged.
There was fire
coming out of the top,
but I just never for the life
of me thought that these...
huge buildings that have been
here so long would actually just fall.
And that's what happened.
They just crumbled.
Well, you know,
as reporters,
you kind of run to the scene,
and that's what happened with
some of the firefighters and police,
too.
They ran to the scene,
and,
of course,
with devastating results.
And the thing is,
with all the triage that's been set up
around that area and all the people
that were being treated and all the
emergency personnel that are close to it,
you only hope that they
were far enough back so that
when this came down that
they were all out of harm's way.
Because as you suggested,
we never thought
they would go down.
No,
it's...
The gasp from the crowd
here was all you needed
to know that this just
shocked everybody again.
That is 1010 Windsor reporter Al
Jones with the news and giving us
that description of World Trade
Center building number 7 going down,
a 47-story building.
That too is gone.
We've just got some pictures in from New
York of the latest building to collapse.
That's the Salomon
Brothers building.
That's 47 stories tall.
There you can see it going.
So this happened,
oh,
some six hours or so after the
collapse of the World Trade Center.
Presumably,
it was so close to the World
Trade Center that it had been
weakened by the explosions
and the collapse of those buildings.
We were talking to our correspondent
in New York a few moments ago,
trying to find out what sort of
casualties might be involved.
In the collapse
of this building,
but it's just in the
realm of guesswork.
Most people,
it's assumed,
had been evacuated
from the building and
perhaps there'd only
be a skeleton staff there.
Presumably,
they would recognize the risk of it collapsing
in the wake of the World Trade Center.
The possibility that the
fire was going to get worse,
all of a sudden a loud,
incredibly loud explosion.
And we have the
video to show you.
Now what happened was
the police started screaming,
everyone started screaming.
It was a very foul odor.
We were covered in smoke
and everyone started running.
I started running as well.
My photographer,
Bache Warner,
did not run.
And he was there
filming all of the clouds,
filming the billowing smoke.
And it was just incredibly frightening to
see hundreds of policemen running away.
From the scene and just
anyone that was in the area.
Now,
we did speak to many
firefighters and policemen.
That building I was
referring to that was on fire,
I didn't know at
the time what it was.
I learned later and
also learned just how
lucky myself and my
photographer Terrence were.
That was 7 World Trade Center.
30 minutes after
I got out of there,
it collapsed.
30-some stories.
I have one other note
that I just want to put by.
This is probably the darkest day
in the history of New York City,
if not the history of
the United States.
But if you're looking
for some inspiration,
just 10 minutes ago,
I wasn't too far from where the tower
number one and tower number two went down,
and I saw a car completely
covered with soot.
And on that car,
somebody wrote,
this won't stop.
New York.
So if you're looking
for inspiration,
hang your hat on that.
What have you heard,
if anything,
about biological entities?
There had been that issue
raised earlier that perhaps anthrax
and the like might have
been part of this attack today.
What have you heard?
Well,
certainly there's a lot of
concern of that around here.
I haven't heard anything
concrete where there is definite,
I won't even say speculation,
definite feeling,
if you will,
that they believe that some sort of
biological terrorism has been used.
There's all kinds of speculation
as to what has happened here.
Was the plane loaded
with explosives?
Was the plane enough
in and of itself to crash
into a building to bring
those two towers down?
Because you'll see the video,
and you've seen
it a hundred times.
It looked like it was a
controlled implosion.
It didn't fall over.
It looked as if somebody put
TNT all throughout that building.
It pancaked from
floor to floor to floor.
So of course there's speculation
here that maybe these planes were
loaded with C4 explosives or
some type of explosives on timers.
That if the plane itself
didn't bring it down,
that charges would go off and that
eventually what happened would happen.
But as far as
biological attacks go...
Yes,
it is a concern.
How great of a concern?
I don't think at this point.
And word late tonight that two
suspects are in FBI custody after a
truckload of explosives was discovered
around the George Washington Bridge.
That bridge links
new york to new jersey over the
hudson river whether the discovery of
those explosives has anything to
do with other events today is unclear
But the FBI has two
suspects in hand,
said the truckload
of explosives,
enough explosives
were in the truck to do
great damage to the
George Washington Bridge.
But they arrested the two suspects
and they're questioning them as we speak.
I gather has just heard of
an incident in New Jersey.
The New York City Police
Department has a report that the
FBI is responding to New
Jersey because a truck
reportedly loaded with
explosives has been
stopped by authorities
on the road there and
the men with that truck
have been detained.
Members of the Joint
Terrorist Task Force,
according to the New
York police officials,
are responding to
question those people.
I asked him what happened.
what was amazing about his
story was that he was in the lobby
of World Trade Center one when
the plane the first plane hit and
When the debris
started coming down
He went back to go into the building to
protect himself and was in the revolving doors
Going back in off West Street when he
looked up and a fireball came flying out
I guess from the elevator shafts
here That's what he seemed to
believe and blew out all the
windows and threw him back onto
the street.
There was an explosion.
We were on the support floor,
which is a basement.
A guy came in running.
All his skin was
out of his body.
We took him out.
We ran out.
We heard a lot of rumbling.
I went back in.
There was a lot of smoke.
Well,
thank you.
And again,
our apologies to our viewers
about five minutes ago,
but we do have an established
connection now with CNN's Deborah Farrig.
The reports we're getting now,
two or three men arrested
on the New Jersey Parkway.
Deborah,
can you hear me?
me now yet that kind of uh...
that is the information that i'm getting
from two sources that there was a van either
on the new jersey turnpike or the garden
state parkway and that it was near the
george washington bridge there were two
or three men who were in the band that that
was pulled over it is not clear why the
band was pulled over but when it was uh...
law enforcers
that found that uh...
and kind of explosive inside
of the band that is right now
all i'm hearing a hundred
again two to three people uh...
two to three people in custody,
custody and we are trying to get
more information on that right now.
Deborah,
I don't mean to put
you on the spot here,
Do you know where on the
Jersey Turnpike this was?
how far from New York City?
We do not know that.
We are looking into that.
There is one report that it was
on the New Jersey Turnpike.
There is another report that
it was very close to the bridge,
if not on the bridge.
So again,
keep together at the depot got though
part two to three and people i think
two to three people
in custody running.
found with a bad filled
with explosive well as
the debris here is spread
over a three to four mile
radius which has now been
completely sealed off and
is being treated according
to the FBI as a crime scene
a crime scene governor tom ridge made
some remarks earlier at a press conference
He had flown over the site.
He said the emergency
response here was immediate.
He also said,
and I don't know whether or not
you all are able to see pictures of this,
but this is one of those cases where the
pictures really do tell the story that sort of
the most horrifying
aspect of this particular
crash scene is how
little debris is visible.
There is a large
crater in the ground,
and I'm hoping that you all are
seeing it as I'm talking about it.
That's really all you see is a large
crater in the ground and just tiny,
tiny bits of debris.
There's been at least one report
that the investigators out there,
and there are hundreds of them,
as I said tonight,
have found nothing
larger than a phone book.
They were having coffee in the World
Trade Center when the first plane struck.
And all of a sudden
it sounded like,
I don't know where
the subway is,
but it sounded like
a subway collision,
a bomb,
And it was just pounding,
boom.
And I literally
thought the subway.
The subway had exploded and
all the cars put the line on top of it.
It was so loud.
I was reviewing some work and it was
about 10 to 9 and the building shook.
And I felt it was an
earthquake and it didn't
bother me because I felt
it was a big earthquake.
the building could sustain
earthquake they were built for that
and then there was a huge
explosion in the ceiling cell he went
through the front door of the ground
floor and the lady who was about
three seconds in front of him
was hit by a terrific fireball and
she was injured, so
we went to assistance,
I think he got some touch over.
And as he was doing that,
another explosion happened.
I was entering the
building on the lobby level,
I was in the room.
...revolving door when
the plane hit the building.
David Dre worked in number
one World Trade Center.
One of the elevators,
I think,
came crashing to the lobby level
and all the debris came flying out of it.
And a fireball emerged from the
elevator lobby and was coming toward me.
We then were talking about the day's
work and what needed to be done when we
heard a massive explosion that was in
the World Trade Center at about 8.46 a.m.
in the morning.
The explosion came from,
I believe at first we believed that
it came from the mechanical room.
And then we heard a
series of other explosions
that sounded up on
the above levels of the
building to where we
then realized that there was
something wrong and
there was a major problem.
Rescue workers pushed
people away from the scene.
So everyone moved back,
leaving debris and silence.
We want to take our
viewers live to Shanksville,
Pennsylvania.
Our Brian Cabell is standing by.
This, of course,
is the site where
United Airlines Flight 93
crashed on its way from
Newark to San Francisco,
crashed on Tuesday.
And I understand in this investigation
there's some breaking news.
Brian,
what can you tell us?
Well,
Darren,
in the last hour or so,
the FBI and the state police here have
confirmed that they have cordoned off a second
area about six to eight miles away from
the crater here where this plane went down.
This is apparently
another debris site,
which raises a
number of questions.
Why would debris from the plane,
and they identified it specifically
as being from this plane,
why would debris be
located six miles away?
Could it have
blown that far away?
Seems highly unlikely.
Almost all the debris found
at this site is within 100 yards,
200 yards away.
So it raises some questions.
We don't want to over-speculate,
of course,
but there were some
cell phone callers,
one cell phone
caller in particular,
who said he saw a bomb
or something that looked
like a bomb with one
of the hijackers also.
The man who took over the
plane apparently announced
that at one point there was
a bomb on board the plane.
So,
again,
we don't want to speculate.
We don't want to
jump to conclusions.
But what we do know is
that there is a site about
a half mile behind me
where the plane went down,
where most of the debris is,
and then about six
miles away up by a lake.
There is another area
that's been cordoned off,
and state police and the
FBI have said definitely
there is debris from
the plane located there.
We have a crew on
the way right now.
We should have pictures
of that a little bit later on.
In the meantime,
the search here goes on.
80 searchers going foot by foot
combing the area looking for evidence.
They have not yet
found the black box.
Darren?
Which was my first question,
so I'll move on to my next one,
Brian.
We don't want to speculate
about this large debris field,
but it seems to me from
covering a number of
plane crashes on the
scene that if nothing else,
you can say this is
not typical for a plane
crash to be spread
across an area this large.
It certainly doesn't make
sense because most of the debris
has been found in a very
compact area within 100 yards,
200 yards,
maybe a little beyond that.
And then all of a
sudden they're telling us,
6 miles away,
they have another
concentration of debris.
They say it's very small pieces.
Most of these are
very small pieces.
Most of the pieces here are no bigger
than the size of a briefcase they say.
And the pieces six miles away
may be even smaller than that.
They have talked to a
number of individuals here.
They say they have talked to people who
saw this plane during the final moments.
They haven't confirmed
whether they saw,
they talked to anybody who saw
this plane actually land or crash,
rather.
And as to whether it
broke up on the way,
we don't know that FBI is
being very tight-lipped about that.
But again,
it leads to that possibility.
It certainly leads to a
number of questions.
You mentioned they have
yet to find the black box.
It would seem to me,
when you compare the four
plane crashes of Tuesday,
this would be the site where they
would be most likely to find a black box.
That's what they
told us initially,
and I think they're somewhat
disappointed they haven't found it.
It's been 48 hours,
but they are still
hopeful they will find it.
There is a pond nearby
this particular site.
They may have to send
divers into the pond.
They haven't done that yet,
but conceivably it
could be in the pond.
It could be anywhere.
It could be at this
other debris site.
They've also found some other
debris scattered around this area.
They say,
in fact,
some individuals
have been collecting it.
Again,
we're talking about very,
very tiny parts.
The biggest part they
found at this site is an engine.
an engine part,
and most of the other pieces are probably
no bigger than this particular notebook.
So again,
very small pieces.
They had hoped to find
the black box by now.
They're still voicing
optimism they will find it.
It's not an assignment I
would wish on anybody,
but I would say that you
would have to have an
assignment like that
to appreciate what that
looks like when a plane
comes crashing into the
ground and basically
just drops out of the sky.
Brian Cabell in Shanksville,
Pennsylvania,
thank you very much.
Also a note from yesterday when we
were listening into an FBI news conference,
a note from yesterday when we were
listening into an FBI news conference,
they were saying...
They expect this search just at this
site to take about three to five weeks.
So they are going to be very deliberate and
look for every possible piece of evidence.
Brian,
thank you very much.
In the B4 level,
I was assigned to the B3 level,
but I had to do something
in the B4 sheet metal shop.
So I went in the
sheet metal shop,
do what I had to do,
And on my way,
I heard a
a bomb such as probably a
transformer again blew up.
So
I stepped back,
finished what i had to finish
and i started towards the door
again and there come a
big blast with a big ball of fire
and that's when i got hit it
hit me right back down on the
ground and i realized that
my uncle was shattered pfeiffer
Piper was the first
chief into the building.
right away a guy from the port authority
told him the damage is somewhere above the
a guy from the Port Authority told him the
damage is somewhere above the 78th floor.
78th floor
But all you had to
do was look around.
It was obvious.
Something had happened
right there in the lobby.
You just saw that all the
windows were blown out.
We have a report now
that a large plane crashed
this morning north of the
Somerset County Airport,
which is in western
Pennsylvania,
not too terribly
far from Pittsburgh,
about 80 miles or so.
I don't think there are enough
words in the English language
or enough appropriate
words to describe.
I thought it was a generator
that blew up on the basement,
And I said to myself,
oh my god,
I think it's a generator.
And I was going to recognize it
when I finished saying that in my mind,
I hear a boom!
Right on top,
pretty far away.
So it was a difference between coming
from the basement and coming from the top.
And that's...
everybody started screaming.
And a person comes
running into the office saying,
explosion,
He got his hand extended and all
the skill was pulled from under his arm,
all the way to the top of his fingertips
and he was hanging on both arms.
Hanging and hanging.
And then I looked at his face and
he was making punch on his face.
I said,
What happened?
And he said,
the elevator is the elevator.